<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>MailOnline MSN</title><language>en-GB</language><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/feeds/msn/channel/travel.rss</link><item><title>EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:55:46 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5544629</guid><description><![CDATA[Jonathan Thompson reveals that cheering crowds and fire trucks squirting water cannons greeted Qantas's history-making Dreamliner in Perth. And he felt 'genuinely relaxed'.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">And just like that, Emily arrived in Australia. This morning, at 12.40pm local time (5.40am BST) the first ever direct flight from <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/london/index.html" id="mol-3c0f9110-30e4-11e8-a277-376324b2918c">London</a> to Australia landed in <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/perth/index.html" id="mol-3c0fdf30-30e4-11e8-a277-376324b2918c">Perth</a>, making aviation history.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/qantas/index.html" id="mol-3c0ea6b0-30e4-11e8-a277-376324b2918c">Qantas</a>'s Boeing 787-9 Dreamliner – nicknamed 'Emily' – touched down to no little fanfare in Australia's sunniest city.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Fire trucks ceremoniously squirted water cannons, a crowd cheered and TV crews recorded 236 blinking passengers stepping off the historic flight and into the embers of Australian summer, all looking surprisingly lively. And I felt genuinely relaxed (though the business class seat helped, admittedly).</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-73daa82d584babb5" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A91191F00000578-5544629-image-m-4_1522061023702.jpg" height="766" width="962" alt="Traveller Jonathan Thompson is pictured here at London Heathrow before boarding Qantas's historic first direct flight from the UK to Australia" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Traveller Jonathan Thompson is pictured here at London Heathrow before boarding Qantas's historic first direct flight from the UK to Australia</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our journey had taken just 16 hours and 30 minutes (15 minutes ahead of schedule) but it had been years in the making – the fruits of a decade of dedicated seasonal air pattern analysis for starters, and Qantas is justifiably proud to have finally achieved it.</p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Not only will the journey between the UK and Australia now be significantly shorter (four hours less than the next shortest flight, via Dubai), it will also be noticeably more comfortable aboard the Boeing Dreamliner. This sleek, parabolic panther of an aircraft boasts multiple advantages over its rivals, including softer cabin noise, larger windows, anti-turbulence technology, improved air quality and more space in every cabin. It's all designed to lessen jet lag - and it appears to work.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Dignitaries, business professionals, reuniting families, journalists and a smattering of celebrities – comedian Adam Hills and actress Gemma Atkinson were among those disembarking Qantas Flight 10 - all looked remarkably energetic considering they'd just travelled 9,009 miles from the other side of the planet.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And I felt refreshed and raring to go.</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-3ddaa40ae63bc5d" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A91193700000578-5544629-image-a-7_1522061096304.jpg" height="722" width="962" alt="Qantas's Boeing 787-9 Dreamliner – nicknamed 'Emily' - touched down at 12.40pm local time today in Perth. Jonathan is pictured here with First Officer Jim Eaglen" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Qantas's Boeing 787-9 Dreamliner – nicknamed 'Emily' - touched down at 12.40pm local time today in Perth. Jonathan is pictured here with First Officer Jim Eaglen</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Dreamliner definitely makes a difference. It almost felt like a trick - like I couldn't really be in Australia, because I hadn't earned it. But ultimately I'm not complaining. It has gone from a full day flight to an overnight flight - psychologically more akin to a trip to California now.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The most senior of the plane's four pilots – the affable Captain Andrew Simpson – was also full of beans, and understandably upbeat after completing such a momentous flight.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'This is absolutely fantastic, a real game changer for the world of aviation,' he said. 'For the first time, Australia and Europe have a direct air link, and that is a big deal. It's a major honour and extremely humbling for me to be at the pointy end of this particular plane.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our journey itself was almost ludicrously smooth - the seatbelt sign did not flicker on even once, with the only remotely rough patch of air experienced a few hundred miles north of the Maldives, before the Dreamliner tore away across the Indian Ocean.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There were some nice touches with regards to the on-board service too: every passenger's plastic water bottle was refilled, never replaced, while all of the meals had been specifically designed by chef Neil Perry, in consultation with experts from The Charles Perkins Centre at Sydney University, to stave off jetlag.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Back at London Heathrow's Terminal 3, our take off had been marked in style too, with actors dressed as kangaroos and surfers, and a giant of a man playing us aboard with an enormous didgeridoo. Even our boarding passes bore the legend 'Congratulations! You are boarding the first non-stop UK-AUS flight.'</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter"><div class="splitLeft"><div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-74877dc3829cc1b7" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A91192F00000578-5544629-image-a-14_1522061228634.jpg" height="467" width="470" alt="Jonathan said that the direct flight makes the journey to Perth from the UK akin to a trip to California" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div></div><div class="splitRight"><div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-33dde5c643564f3" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A9120F100000578-5544629-image-a-15_1522061235640.jpg" height="467" width="470" alt="A traditional roast served on board the direct flight to Perth" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div></div><div class="clear"></div><p class="imageCaption">Jonathan, pictured left in his business class pod, said that the direct flight makes the journey to Perth from the UK akin to a trip to California. Pictured right is one of his meals - a traditional British roast</p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-6efc996566e0ae7e" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A911B4400000578-5544629-image-a-16_1522061338353.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="The Dreamliner boasts several advantages over its rivals - softer cabin noise, larger windows, anti-turbulence technology, improved air quality and more space in every cabin" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The Dreamliner boasts several advantages over its rivals - softer cabin noise, larger windows, anti-turbulence technology, improved air quality and more space in every cabin</p></div><div class="mol-img-group floatXWHalfRHS">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-b330ac1ac819a098" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A91191800000578-5544629-image-a-22_1522061381511.jpg" height="550" width="470" alt="'Refreshed and raring to go': Jonathan gives the direct flight the thumbs up in Perth" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">'Refreshed and raring to go': Jonathan gives the direct flight the thumbs up in Perth</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Travelling in this fashion is light years ahead of the original London-Australia flight - the infamous 'Kangaroo Route' - which began in 1947. That four-day intercontinental hopscotch – involving seven stops and costing the equivalent of more than £24,000 today - has now become a seamless, non-stop 17-hour zip Down Under. (It's significantly cheaper in real terms too, with tickets for this London-Perth route starting at just £793 per person return in economy).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The new route, which will now fly daily, officially becomes the longest anywhere in the world from London (a massive 24 per cent longer than the previous record holder, from Heathrow to Jakarta) and the first ever direct air connection between the continents of Europe and Australasia.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There's still room for improvement of course. No Wifi on the history-making QF10 is an issue – particularly as British Airways has introduced it to many of its own long-haul flights in recent weeks. And Qantas remains agonisingly short of Qatar Airway's current world record for the longest commercial flight on Earth: 9,028 miles between Doha and Auckland.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One gets the impression that record won't stand for too long, however. Qantas already has its eyes on a non-stop London to Sydney flight by 2022, with New York-Sydney potentially coming even earlier. For now, all eyes are on the historic achievement of QF10 but ultimately, success on the London-Perth service is just the beginning.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="mol-style-italic">Jonathan Thompson was challenged by Huawei to take the upcoming Huawei P20 smartphone and test its features whilst onboard. Follow Huawei via <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://twitter.com/HuaweiMobileUK">@HuaweiMobileUK</a>. To find out more about the Huawei P20, visit <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://newrenaissance.com/">newrenaissance.com</a>.</span> </p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-c534b8b0-310e-11e8-a277-376324b2918c">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">FACTS ABOUT QF9 - THE PERTH TO LONDON ROUTE</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">1. QF9 is operated by four pilots across the 17-hour journey, with one or two pilots resting at any one time.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">2. The flight will follow different flight paths depending on the best winds, helping the aircraft fly faster and more efficiently. Qantas analysed a decade of seasonal wind patterns in preparation for the new service.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">3. At 14,498km, QF9 is the third longest commercial flight currently in operation. It is the world's longest Dreamliner flight.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">4. QF9 will carry around 92 tonnes or 110,000 litres of fuel with the Dreamliner burning approximately 20 per cent less than traditional aircraft its size.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">5. With a total seat count of 236 passengers, the Qantas Dreamliner has significantly fewer seats than many other airlines who have configured the same aircraft to carry more than 300 passengers.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">6. Currently, most aircraft have cabin air pressure equivalent to that of an altitude of 8,000 ft. For the Dreamliner, Boeing cut that down to 6,000 ft, meaning its closer to conditions on the ground.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">7. Menus for the flights between Perth and London have been designed to maintain hydration, aid sleep and reducing jetlag and including poke bowls as well as home style comfort food.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">8. There are more than 21,000 individual items loaded onto the aircraft for each flight between Perth and London including 330 peppermint tea bags and hundreds of chocolate biscuits.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">9. In 1947 a return flight from Sydney to London cost £525 when the average wage was £7. Today, the average Australian weekly wage is $1600 and a return fare from Perth to London can cost less than $1300.  </p></div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Jonathan Thompson reveals that cheering crowds and fire trucks squirting water cannons greeted Qantas's history-making Dreamliner in Perth. And he felt 'genuinely relaxed'. He reveals here that the journey was 'ludicrously smooth' and that the Dreamliner's anti-jet lag technology really seemed to work. Pictured: Jonathan snug in his business class pod (top left), meeting the captain at Heathrow (top right), being given an Australian-style send-off at Heathrow (bottom right), a roast dinner on board (bottom left) and the 787-9 Dreamliner than completed the epic trip (inset).</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-26T17:00:29.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>On board the first direct flight with Qantas from the UK to Australia</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-26T17:00:29.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>Qantas,Perth</media:keywords><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-5543541/Traveller-pictures-reveal-REALLY-like-Qantas-non-stop-flight-Perth-London.html" title="Traveller pictures reveal what it was REALLY like to fly on board the Qantas non-stop 17-hour flight from Perth to London"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505085/Why-fans-Malta-returning-year.html" title="Malta? I'll be back... Revealing why fans of this magical Mediterranean island keep returning every year"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505051/The-best-new-boats-cruising-itineraries-revealed.html" title="Catch a piranha, dance a polka or dine in Provence! How to have a REAL adventure with some of the best new boats and cruising itineraries around"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505269/Take-step-time-Rios-regal-Copacabana-Palace.html" title="Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace - the first luxury hotel in South America, which welcomed Albert Einstein and Frank Sinatra"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html" title="Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535621/The-worlds-lust-worthy-islands-BUY.html" title="The world's most lust-worthy islands you can BUY: From a £2.3m spit of sand in the Maldives to a £1.3m outcrop in Canada, the perfect properties for wannabe Robinson Crusoes revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535977/Rachael-Talibarts-stunning-wave-photographs.html" title="Real swell shots! Stunning photographs capture ferocious waves whipped up by a violent storm"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://twitter.com/HuaweiMobileUK" title="Huawei Mobile UK (@HuaweiMobileUK) on Twitter"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://newrenaissance.com" title="New Renaissance"></link></item><item><title>Nerve-wracking footage shows a passenger's-eye-view of a journey on the world's steepest train, which tackles a 48% gradient</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544325/Nerve-wracking-footage-shows-passengers-eye-view-journey-worlds-steepest-train.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 12:10:57 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5544325</guid><description><![CDATA[The Pilatus Railway has been running safely for nearly 120 years and transports passengers from the Alpnachstad station at Lake Lucerne in Switzerland to the top of Mount Pilatus.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">It transports passengers 6,800ft to the top of a mountain at a maximum gradient of 48 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And the world's steepest train ride has been caught on camera - and it is enough to make your stomach churn.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Pilatus Railway has been running safely for nearly 120 years and transports about 300,000 passengers a year from the Alpnachstad station at Lake Lucerne in Switzerland to a terminus near the top of Mount Pilatus.</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-4d35d1b5a1f729d3" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90926400000578-5544325-image-a-41_1522058560590.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="The view from the window of the Pilatus Railway in Switzerland. Trains travel to the top of Mount Pilatus at a gradient of 48 per cent " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The view from the window of the Pilatus Railway in Switzerland. Trains travel to the top of Mount Pilatus at a gradient of 48 per cent </p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-6f50e73445d3670" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90933500000578-5544325-image-a-43_1522058582856.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="Passenger Eric Sanchagrin captured the journey on camera. The railway from Lake Lucerne to Mount Pilatus has been in operation for the past 120 years " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Passenger Eric Sanchagrin captured the journey on camera. The railway from Lake Lucerne to Mount Pilatus has been in operation for the past 120 years </p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-661a4daad72affe8" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/16/4A90932500000578-5544325-Mr_Sanchagrin_said_The_train_is_very_quiet_but_just_a_little_cre-a-54_1522078373122.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="Mr Sanchagrin said: 'The train is very quiet but just a little creaky, but the ride provides a stunning view of Lake Lucerne' " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Mr Sanchagrin said: 'The train is very quiet but just a little creaky, but the ride provides a stunning view of Lake Lucerne' </p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">And the footage shows the journey that passengers take up the mountain and just how high the train goes.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But even those with a fear of heights will appreciate the beautiful views that the train journey delivers, which include lakes, mountains and even a cave.</p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The footage was captured by passenger Eric Sanchagrin.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 28-year-old explained: 'It was a stunning journey and the views were absolutely breathtaking - everywhere you looked there were gorgeous landscapes.</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-f34c231f0c4aab35" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90931100000578-5544325-image-a-50_1522058620564.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="Despite the stomach churning gradient at which the train travels, it does give passengers the opportunity to see breath-taking views, such Lake Lucerne, pictured " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Despite the stomach churning gradient at which the train travels, it does give passengers the opportunity to see breath-taking views, such Lake Lucerne, pictured </p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-c82a534e8682f1fd" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90940900000578-5544325-image-a-47_1522058605455.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="The service operates between May and November each year, with ten rail cars and a maximum transport capacity of 340 people an hour" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The service operates between May and November each year, with ten rail cars and a maximum transport capacity of 340 people an hour</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The railway line starts at the bottom of the mountain in the village of Alpnachstad and ends near the top of the mountain at Esel summit at an altitude of 2,073m.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The train is very quiet but just a little creaky, but the ride provides a stunning view of Lake Lucerne.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The first cave was well lit with electric lights every few meters - it was cool and damp as you passed through.</p><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-5d088a6f5f446545" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90925D00000578-5544325-image-a-57_1522058642676.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="Alpine cattle graze on the grass near to the 120-year-old railway tracks as the Pilatus train crawls past" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Alpine cattle graze on the grass near to the 120-year-old railway tracks as the Pilatus train crawls past</p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-3398791cfdb49af7" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/16/4A90931D00000578-5544325-Work_commenced_in_1886_on_the_railway_with_around_150_Swiss_and_-a-53_1522078373050.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="Work commenced in 1886 on the railway, with around 150 Swiss and 600 Italians tasked with building the nearly three-mile track " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Work commenced in 1886 on the railway, with around 150 Swiss and 600 Italians tasked with building the nearly three-mile track </p></div><div class="mol-img-group xwArtSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-464f6bfd66aadbb9" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/11/4A90912600000578-5544325-image-a-60_1522058674321.jpg" height="641" width="962" alt="It takes half an hour to ascend, and 40 minutes to get back down the mountain, moving at a speed of between five and seven mph" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">It takes half an hour to ascend, and 40 minutes to get back down the mountain, moving at a speed of between five and seven mph</p></div><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-c267b900-30ed-11e8-a277-376324b2918c">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Steeped in history: How the railway with the 48% gradient was built</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <p class="mol-para-with-font"> The story of the railway began more than a century ago.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Not long after the Swiss summit was scaled on horseback by Queen Victoria in 1868, Pilatus became in increasingly popular attraction. Some sort of transport mode to the top was therefore necessary.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Zurich-based engineer Eduard Locher was the first to suggest building a railway up the mountain in 1873, but his plans were essentially deemed mad.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, following the invention of the rail rack system - a track configuration in which the train's fitted cog wheels mesh with a toothed rack - things changed.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">His variation on the design involved opposing twin horizontal cogwheels carried on vertical shafts under the car.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This avoided the possibility of the train de-railing or toppling over. Custom automatic brakes also prevented the train from speeding.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Work commenced in 1886, with around 150 Swiss and 600 Italians tasked with building the nearly three-mile track.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On June 4, 1889, the Pilatus Railway started operating - originally using steam-operated coaches.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In March of 1937, it switched to electricity and re-opened using new electric motor coaches, each seating 40 passengers compared with their previous capacity of 32, and cutting the journey time by more than half. </p></div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">'There is a legend of a dragon who lives in a cave on the mountain but I did not get to view that!'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The service operates between May and November each year, with ten rail cars and a maximum transport capacity of 340 people an hour, according to tourism centre Pilatus Luzern.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It takes half an hour to ascend, and 40 minutes to get back down the mountain, moving at a speed of between five and seven mph.</p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>It transports passengers 6,800ft to the top of a mountain at a maximum gradient of 48 per cent. And the world's steepest train ride has been caught on camera - and it is enough to make your stomach churn. The Pilatus Railway has been running safely for nearly 120 years and transports about 300,000 passengers a year from the Alpnachstad station at Lake Lucerne in Switzerland to a terminus near the top of Mount Pilatus. The stunning views en route include Lake Lucerne (inset).</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-26T16:33:07.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Footage shows the journey on the world's steepest train in Switzerland</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-26T16:33:07.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html" title="EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html" title="We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505269/Take-step-time-Rios-regal-Copacabana-Palace.html" title="Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace - the first luxury hotel in South America, which welcomed Albert Einstein and Frank Sinatra"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html" title="Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539239/Meet-world-leaders-computers-coffee-bars-fish-flinging-Seattle.html" title="Meet the world leaders in computers, coffee bars and fish-flinging by heading to the thriving city of Seattle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html" title="The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539219/Alexander-Armstrong-blown-away-relentless-expansion-Dubai.html" title="Things can only get BIGGER... Alexander Armstrong is blown away by the relentless expansion of Dubai - where nothing is too large, tall or luxurious"></link></item><item><title>Heathrow trials a driverless vehicle with fascinating footage revealing what the robot cargo car 'sees'</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5545625/Heathrow-trials-driverless-vehicle-footage-revealing-robot-cargo-car-sees.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 15:04:34 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5545625</guid><description><![CDATA[The clip comes from a ‘cargopod’ vehicle that spent three and a half weeks running autonomously along a cargo route around the London Heathrow's airside perimeter.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Fascinating footage has been released of a robot's-eye-view of a driverless vehicle trial at Heathrow Airport, side-by-side with how a human driver would see the routes it took. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The clip comes from a 'cargopod' vehicle that spent three and a half weeks running autonomously along a cargo route around the airside perimeter.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The trial collected over 200km of data for Heathrow, cargo operator IAG Cargo and the software firm providing the self-driving tech, Oxford-based Oxbotica.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-ec5cf7011a9a0d22" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/15/4A93240000000578-0-image-a-42_1522075953217.jpg" height="353" width="634" alt="Fascinating footage has been released of a robot's-eye-view of a driverless vehicle trial at Heathrow Airport, side-by-side with how a human driver would see the routes it took " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Fascinating footage has been released of a robot's-eye-view of a driverless vehicle trial at Heathrow Airport, side-by-side with how a human driver would see the routes it took </p></div><div class="mol-img-group floatRHS">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-5a80209cb2969ee9" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/15/4A92F2E900000578-0-image-a-44_1522075966691.jpg" height="345" width="306" alt="The clip comes from a 'cargopod' vehicle, pictured, that spent three and a half weeks running autonomously along a cargo route around the airside perimeter" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The clip comes from a 'cargopod' vehicle, pictured, that spent three and a half weeks running autonomously along a cargo route around the airside perimeter</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The trial was designed to further understanding about how autonomous vehicles could work in an airside environment so opportunities for their use can be maximised.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Lynne Embleton, CEO at IAG Cargo, said: 'Technology is evolving at an incredible pace. We are working with fantastic businesses like Oxbotica to develop new capabilities that will change the way airports function around the world. The trial has yielded valuable insights and is another step in our ongoing commitment to embrace new technologies, improve processes and enhance our offering to our customers.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Dr Graeme Smith, CEO of Oxbotica, added: 'We've previously trialled autonomous vehicles on public roads but this is the first test of how they could operate airside at an airport. </p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">'While there were a huge number of variables to consider including transitioning from indoors to outdoors during each journey, our vision-based localisation system performed exceptionally. For us, the trial marks the first step in an ongoing relationship with Heathrow Airport and IAG Cargo.'</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group"><div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-6c1525f281767bff" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/26/17/4A9323FC00000578-5545625-The_trial_collected_over_200km_of_data_for_Heathrow_cargo_operat-a-3_1522080827458.jpg" height="488" width="633" alt="The trial collected over 200km of data for Heathrow, cargo operator IAG Cargo and the software firm providing the self-driving tech, Oxford-based Oxbotica" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div><div class="clear"></div><p class="imageCaption">The trial collected over 200km of data for Heathrow, cargo operator IAG Cargo and the software firm providing the self-driving tech, Oxford-based Oxbotica</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Gatwick, meanwhile, is trialling 'electric-powered autonomous vehicles' for workers and says that if it's successful it could lead to driverless baggage trucks and transport buses for passengers and an 'Uber-style' robot-car service for staff.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The trial is thought to be the first of its kind for any airport in the world.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The airport says that its 300 airside vehicles are stationary 90 per cent of the time – as staff attend to aircraft and passengers - but that a trial of driverless cars will see workers shuttled between popular locations on the airfield when it starts later this summer.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It said in a statement: 'The trial is thought to be the first of its kind for any airport in the world and - if successful and scaled up – could lead to airfield transport needs being met from a much smaller pool of autonomous vehicles, reducing the need for such large vehicle fleets, reducing emissions and saving on costs.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'If the technology is proven in an airfield environment and following further trials, this project may be the precursor to a wide range of other autonomous vehicles being used on airport, including aircraft push back tugs, passenger load bridges, baggage tugs and transportation buses.' </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Fascinating footage has been released of a robot’s-eye-view (right) of a driverless vehicle trial at Heathrow Airport. The clip comes from a ‘cargopod’ vehicle that spent three and a half weeks running autonomously along a cargo route around the airside perimeter. The trial collected over 200km of data for Heathrow, cargo operator IAG Cargo and the software firm providing the self-driving tech, Oxford-based Oxbotica.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-26T17:13:12.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Footage reveals what robot cargo car 'sees’ at Heathrow Airport</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-26T17:13:12.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>London</media:keywords><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html" title="EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544325/Nerve-wracking-footage-shows-passengers-eye-view-journey-worlds-steepest-train.html" title="Nerve-wracking footage shows a passenger's-eye-view of a journey on the world's steepest train, which tackles a 48% gradient"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html" title="Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505269/Take-step-time-Rios-regal-Copacabana-Palace.html" title="Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace - the first luxury hotel in South America, which welcomed Albert Einstein and Frank Sinatra"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html" title="We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539239/Meet-world-leaders-computers-coffee-bars-fish-flinging-Seattle.html" title="Meet the world leaders in computers, coffee bars and fish-flinging by heading to the thriving city of Seattle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html" title="The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539219/Alexander-Armstrong-blown-away-relentless-expansion-Dubai.html" title="Things can only get BIGGER... Alexander Armstrong is blown away by the relentless expansion of Dubai - where nothing is too large, tall or luxurious"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539209/From-matchmaking-Ireland-tomato-flinging-Spain-10-best-alternative-festivals-revealed.html" title="From matchmaking in Ireland to tomato-flinging in Spain, the 10 best alternative festivals revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539187/Great-British-boltholes-Nidd-Hall-Harrogate-party-place-changed-history.html" title="Great British boltholes: Nidd Hall in Harrogate is the party place-turned-full board hotel that changed history"></link></item><item><title>Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 07:21:17 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5505127</guid><description><![CDATA[The Mail on Sunday's David Rose says that in the two weeks he spent in the French-speaking Canadian province of Quebec with his family, he came across no other British tourists.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Britons on holiday in France grumble that the only language they hear is English, spoken by other Brits. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The solution to this lies 3,000 miles away - in the French-speaking <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/canada/index.html">Canadian </a>province of Quebec. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In two weeks there, my wife Carolyn, son Daniel, 13, and I came across no other British tourists.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-ba21142c591711f3" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36C5DB00000578-5505127-image-a-70_1521649501427.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Water wonders: The Gaspesie National Park in Quebec boasts beautiful lakes" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Water wonders: The Gaspesie National Park in Quebec boasts beautiful lakes</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">This was baffling, for Quebec is a place of beauty, diverse wildlife, and a rich culture which, while French-influenced, is definitively its own.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our first stop, Montreal, revealed itself to be a city of universities, a virtual reality art gallery, excellent restaurants and, in the warren of streets known as Old Montreal, fine stone buildings.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We headed east from Montreal – driving along the St Lawrence River towards mountains, lakes and forests. </p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">We paused to visit the nautical museum at Rimouski, a memorial to ‘Canada’s Titanic’ – the Empress of Ireland, in which 1,012 people were entombed after it collided with a coal ship in 1914. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Then we were into the mountains of the Gaspesie National Park, the granite spine of the Gaspé peninsula, a broad spit of land that juts out into the Gulf of St Lawrence.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We spent three days based at the Auberge Le Gite du Mont-Albert, a lodge in the shadow of the park’s rugged mountains that are criss-crossed by a network of well-marked trails, several of which we sampled. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-d27835f72d64ada4" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36C52400000578-5505127-image-a-71_1521649517990.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="The Mail on Sunday's David Rose said he found  pristine lakes, pink granite crags and herds of elk lurking in the Gaspesie National Park" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The Mail on Sunday's David Rose said he found  pristine lakes, pink granite crags and herds of elk lurking in the Gaspesie National Park</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">There are pristine lakes, pink granite crags and herds of elk, and from the ridge-tops, spectacular wilderness views.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Next stop was the Gaspé’s south coast – a more populous region of seaside villages, each with its church adorned with a wooden spire painted silver. At Percé, where a sandy bay is dominated by a huge offshore rock pierced by an arched sea cave, we were in foodie paradise: first at our hotel, the Riotel Percé, and on our second night, the outstanding Maison du Pecheur. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Between meals, we visited Bonaventure island to see Canada’s largest colony of seabirds and, close by on the beach, fat, furry seals.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Having rounded the end of the peninsula, we took a ferry from Matane to the St Lawrence Cote Nord. We hoped to see whales, and we were not disappointed. </p><div class="mol-img-group floatRHS" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-27c3825d7a2ecc2d" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36C41700000578-5505127-image-a-69_1521649400869.jpg" height="461" width="306" alt="Beak peek: Gannets on Bonaventure Island" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Beak peek: Gannets on Bonaventure Island</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">From Cap de Bon Desir, we gazed for hours at minkes only yards away. Next day, we took a boat from the village where we stayed, Tadoussac, into the middle of the water, seeing not only more minkes, but pods of white belugas.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The character of our trip shifted, with two nights in the province’s capital, Quebec City. It’s vibrant and architecturally alluring, with – in summer – an outdoors, cafe society buzz.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We couldn’t leave eastern Canada without a trip to Niagara Falls, so we headed for Ontario. Niagara, sad to say, is tacky and amusement arcades by the falls do nothing to enhance them, extraordinary as they are. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We took a helicopter ride and rode a jetboat through the rapids at the base: an exciting way to get soaked.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We flew home from Toronto, our clothes still damp from the jetboat. It had been a memorable trip.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-e75f88e0-2851-11e8-9f4b-652de2bee917">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">TRAVEL FACTS </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">Canada As You Like It (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://canadaasyoulikeit.com/">canadaasyoulikeit.com</a>, 020 8742 8299) has a 21-night holiday from £5,880 for two adults and two children, including return flights, car hire, two nights in Montreal, one night in Riviere du Loop, three in Ste Annes-des-Monts, three in Percé, one in Matane, two in Tadoussac, one in Parc National des Hautes-Gorges-de-la-Rivière-Malbaie, one in Baie St Paul, two in Quebec City, two in Ottawa, one in Calabogie, one in Toronto and one in Niagara Falls.</p>                            </div>                        </div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>The Mail on Sunday's David Rose says that in the two weeks he spent in the French-speaking Canadian province of Quebec with his family, he came across no other British tourists.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-26T12:38:39.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-26T12:38:39.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>Canada</media:keywords><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505085/Why-fans-Malta-returning-year.html" title="Malta? I'll be back... Revealing why fans of this magical Mediterranean island keep returning every year"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5526841/The-quietest-roads-America-revealed.html" title="From a deserted highway in Alaska to a tree-lined route in Maine you'll - almost - have to yourself: America's quietest roads revealed (just don't go all at once...) "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505051/The-best-new-boats-cruising-itineraries-revealed.html" title="Catch a piranha, dance a polka or dine in Provence! How to have a REAL adventure with some of the best new boats and cruising itineraries around"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5523657/The-164ft-superyacht-SILENT-mode.html" title="The 164ft superyacht with a SILENT mode: Hearing expert helped develop the hybrid-powered boat to ensure engine noise never goes above 'softly falling rain'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535621/The-worlds-lust-worthy-islands-BUY.html" title="The world's most lust-worthy islands you can BUY: From a £2.3m spit of sand in the Maldives to a £1.3m outcrop in Canada, the perfect properties for wannabe Robinson Crusoes revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535977/Rachael-Talibarts-stunning-wave-photographs.html" title="Real swell shots! Stunning photographs capture ferocious waves whipped up by a violent storm"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505071/Anna-Friel-daughter-discover-really-relax-St-Lucia.html" title="Simple treasures! The beach is beautiful, the sea is bliss and there's hotpot for breakfast. Anna Friel and her daughter discover how to really relax in St Lucia"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505119/Dreaming-Disney-Dont-let-turn-nightmare.html" title="Dreaming of Disney? Don't let it turn into a nightmare with intense heat, long walks and impossible schedules"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://canadaasyoulikeit.com" title="canadaasyoulikeit.com"></link></item><item><title>Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace - the first luxury hotel in South America, which welcomed Albert Einstein and Frank Sinatra</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505269/Take-step-time-Rios-regal-Copacabana-Palace.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 07:41:10 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5505269</guid><description><![CDATA[In a bid to get a taste of Rio's decadent past, The Mail on Sunday's Emily Perry visited the Copacabana Palace. When the venue opened in 1923, it was the first luxury hotel in South America.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">When the Copacabana Palace opened in 1923, it was the first luxury hotel in South America. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The gleaming white icon of progress stood out among the low-rise buildings along <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/brazil/index.html">Rio de Janeiro</a>’s Copacabana beach.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Taking the style of the grand hotels of the South of France, the Palace imported the best fittings and fixtures such as English carpets and chandeliers from Czechoslovakia. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-ba5afcfdef48488f" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A67E41100000578-5505269-When_the_Copacabana_Palace_opened_in_1923_it_was_the_first_luxur-m-82_1521650671102.jpg" height="373" width="634" alt="When the Copacabana Palace opened in 1923, it was the first luxury hotel in South America" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">When the Copacabana Palace opened in 1923, it was the first luxury hotel in South America</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">It became the byword for glamour with a long list of celebrity guests from Albert Einstein to Frank Sinatra.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Today, the hotel retains the grand presence of its designer’s vision. The distinctive exterior is magnificent among the late 20th Century buildings on the beach. </p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Arriving at the hotel, you are thrown back to a romantic era. Doormen in crisp white uniforms reveal a lobby filled with flowers and the marble staircase is padded with thick carpet.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The vast outdoor swimming pool is surrounded by glamorous people lying on loungers, enjoying a cocktail and taking in the warm sun. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-2d663cb5b6737bb0" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A67E62800000578-5505269-image-a-97_1521650803157.jpg" height="365" width="634" alt="The Mail On Sunday's Emily Perry said her room overlooking the beach didn't disappoint" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The Mail On Sunday's Emily Perry said her room overlooking the beach didn't disappoint</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The hotel was due to open with a casino, but gambling was banned in Brazil before it was finished. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The space is now given to the hotel’s restaurants. Our room overlooking the beach didn’t disappoint.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">From the early morning, Cariocas (the residents of Rio) are up pounding the beachside paths and playing sport on the golden sand.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The desire to be outside is contagious, and we dutifully walked along the seafront to Ipanema. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group" style="style">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-e06dfc227ad6f2ce" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A67E56300000578-5505269-image-a-100_1521650901540.jpg" height="427" width="634" alt="Rio is known for its vibrant social scene, with dance and music and the heart of local communities " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Rio is known for its vibrant social scene, with dance and music and the heart of local communities </p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">This was the setting for songwriters Tom Jobim and Vinicius de Moraes’s famous bossa nova song The Girl From Ipanema.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The sunsets in Ipanema are breathtaking – like watching a moving postcard – especially if you have a caipirinha cocktail in hand.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">If you’re visiting Rio, it is worth booking a guided tour to orientate yourself. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We used Xplora Rio, which offers small-group tours in a Land Rover to famous attractions such as the Christ the Redeemer, Sugarloaf mountain and the Lapa Steps.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The appearance of Rio has changed a lot in the past 95 years but the Copacabana Palace maintains the style and glamour of this special city. </p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-e75f88e0-2851-11e8-9f4b-652de2bee917">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">TRAVEL FACTS </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Belmond Copacabana Palace in Rio offers rooms from £214 per night including breakfast. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Visit <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://belmond.com/">belmond.com</a>.</p>                            </div>                        </div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>In a bid to get a taste of Rio's decadent past, The Mail on Sunday's Emily Perry visited the Copacabana Palace. When the venue opened in 1923, it was the first luxury hotel in South America.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-26T12:36:15.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-26T12:36:15.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>Brazil</media:keywords><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html" title="Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535621/The-worlds-lust-worthy-islands-BUY.html" title="The world's most lust-worthy islands you can BUY: From a £2.3m spit of sand in the Maldives to a £1.3m outcrop in Canada, the perfect properties for wannabe Robinson Crusoes revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535977/Rachael-Talibarts-stunning-wave-photographs.html" title="Real swell shots! Stunning photographs capture ferocious waves whipped up by a violent storm"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505075/Go-Bequia-golden-age-place-barefoot-holiday.html" title="Go Bequia to a golden age: The best place to go for a barefoot, sleepy holiday - and taste some top rum"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505085/Why-fans-Malta-returning-year.html" title="Malta? I'll be back... Revealing why fans of this magical Mediterranean island keep returning every year"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505051/The-best-new-boats-cruising-itineraries-revealed.html" title="Catch a piranha, dance a polka or dine in Provence! How to have a REAL adventure with some of the best new boats and cruising itineraries around"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505071/Anna-Friel-daughter-discover-really-relax-St-Lucia.html" title="Simple treasures! The beach is beautiful, the sea is bliss and there's hotpot for breakfast. Anna Friel and her daughter discover how to really relax in St Lucia"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505119/Dreaming-Disney-Dont-let-turn-nightmare.html" title="Dreaming of Disney? Don't let it turn into a nightmare with intense heat, long walks and impossible schedules"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5523657/The-164ft-superyacht-SILENT-mode.html" title="The 164ft superyacht with a SILENT mode: Hearing expert helped develop the hybrid-powered boat to ensure engine noise never goes above 'softly falling rain'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505291/One-travellers-journey-Himalayas-following-childhood-dream.html" title="At last, I've seen the sun rise in the Himalayas! One traveller's journey to India's magnificent mountain range in pursuit of a childhood dream"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://belmond.com" title="Belmond Hotels, Trains, River Cruises - Discover Belmond Luxury Travel"></link></item><item><title>The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 22:02:26 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5539197</guid><description><![CDATA[Continuing The Mail on Sunday's series featuring the holiday memories of famous people, this week broadcaster Frank Gardner recalls his vacations, from Ecuador to the Maldives and beyond.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Continuing our series featuring the holiday memories of famous people, this week broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures…</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>First holiday I can remember: </strong>We drove to Switzerland when I was seven. We were living in the pan-flat Netherlands at the time and I had never seen mountains or snow. The Alps provided both, and I will never forget the thrill of peering out of my room and watching a golden eagle glide past.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>First time abroad: </strong>Our family moved to The Hague when I was six. My dad loaded up the car and we drove to Harwich, from where we took a car ferry, the Avalon. In the morning I woke up in another country with a strange language and great pancakes. The first town we drove through was called Monster.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-d2dc96e7abc6f90b" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/24/11/4A815D0700000578-5539197-image-m-4_1521892369502.jpg" height="401" width="634" alt="Soaking up the sun: Frank (right) pictured out on a hike with a friend in Turkey" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Soaking up the sun: Frank (right) pictured out on a hike with a friend in Turkey</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>First school trip: </strong>Lydd Ranges in Kent. When I was ten I managed to get myself on to the school rifle-shooting team. We slept in tents on the coast near Dungeness, frying up sausages beneath the moon, chucking cans up in the air and trying to hit them with air rifles. For a boy at boarding school, this was unprecedented freedom.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>My honeymoon: </strong>Amanda and I went to the Maldives. We loved the late afternoons where we would sit on the warm sand with our toes in the water, drinks in our hands, and watch the fish chase each other through the shallows.</p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Worst ever trip: </strong>I went biathlon ski training in Austria with the British Army’s Physical Training Corps. It was a wet winter that year in Steiermark so instead of skiing across pristine snow fields, we ended up having to run up mountains in the rain while a Royal Marine yelled insults at us. Not fun.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>My dream destination: </strong>Patagonia. All those soaring Andean peaks wreathed in cloud, and patrolled by giant condors and prowling pumas. I can’t believe I haven’t been there yet.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-a2ac93e7f29549b1" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/24/11/4A815D1300000578-5539197-image-a-3_1521892365314.jpg" height="435" width="634" alt="Frank seen enjoying a rather large beer before tackling the Amazon in 1990" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Frank seen enjoying a rather large beer before tackling the Amazon in 1990</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>My favourite place: </strong>Despite all its recent commercialisation, it still has to be Thailand. For the food, for the scenery, the wildlife and the people. A university mate and I first went backpacking in the Golden Triangle in 1981. Since then our family has had brilliant holidays there.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Perfect holiday companion: </strong>I trekked deep into the Ecuadorian Amazon with my mate James Maughan and a guide, hacking down foliage to sleep in makeshift shelters at night and trying not to think about deadly coral snakes. On another trip we hiked for days in the Colombian cloudforest.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>The first thing I pack: </strong>My old Army bivvy bag is brilliant for keeping the crawlies out. Otherwise an Arabic scarf called a shemagh, which keeps you cool in the mountains or you can drape it over your head to keep out the sun.</p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Continuing The Mail on Sunday's series featuring the holiday memories of famous people, this week broadcaster Frank Gardner recalls his vacations, from Ecuador to the Maldives and beyond.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator></dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-27T08:03:21.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-27T08:03:21.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505085/Why-fans-Malta-returning-year.html" title="Malta? I'll be back... Revealing why fans of this magical Mediterranean island keep returning every year"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505051/The-best-new-boats-cruising-itineraries-revealed.html" title="Catch a piranha, dance a polka or dine in Provence! How to have a REAL adventure with some of the best new boats and cruising itineraries around"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535621/The-worlds-lust-worthy-islands-BUY.html" title="The world's most lust-worthy islands you can BUY: From a £2.3m spit of sand in the Maldives to a £1.3m outcrop in Canada, the perfect properties for wannabe Robinson Crusoes revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535977/Rachael-Talibarts-stunning-wave-photographs.html" title="Real swell shots! Stunning photographs capture ferocious waves whipped up by a violent storm"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505071/Anna-Friel-daughter-discover-really-relax-St-Lucia.html" title="Simple treasures! The beach is beautiful, the sea is bliss and there's hotpot for breakfast. Anna Friel and her daughter discover how to really relax in St Lucia"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/article-5469345/Seven-reasons-European-cruise-ultimate-holiday.html" title="World class cocktails, amazing food and a new adventure every day! Seven reasons a European cruise is the ultimate holiday"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505119/Dreaming-Disney-Dont-let-turn-nightmare.html" title="Dreaming of Disney? Don't let it turn into a nightmare with intense heat, long walks and impossible schedules"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5523657/The-164ft-superyacht-SILENT-mode.html" title="The 164ft superyacht with a SILENT mode: Hearing expert helped develop the hybrid-powered boat to ensure engine noise never goes above 'softly falling rain'"></link></item><item><title>Good job he checked his insurance! From suitcases to slaloms, Fred Mawer offers vital tips on getting the right cover</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505157/Fred-Mawer-offers-vital-tips-getting-right-travel-cover.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 07:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5505157</guid><description><![CDATA[Buying budget travel insurance policies is tempting, but it may well turn out to be a false economy, says The Mail on Sunday's Fred Mawer.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Just £19.75. That’s how little it can cost to get year-long travel insurance to cover any number of trips worldwide. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It’s the cheapest deal showing on the price-comparison website I’m looking at, and there are lots of other annual policies on offer for a mere few pounds more.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Buying one of these budget policies is tempting, but it may well turn out to be a false economy. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group"><div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-bcfd2fa871039b1a" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/27/08/4A97651900000578-5505157-image-m-9_1522135315473.jpg" height="387" width="634" alt="" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div><div class="clear"></div><p class="imageCaption">Unhappy landing: The Mail on Sunday's Fred Mawer says make sure you're covered for off-piste skiing</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Levels of cover for cancellation and baggage are likely to be pitifully low, and you may find your individual needs are not covered at all. So always assess the following areas carefully before selecting a policy.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Limits and excesses</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">For emergency medical cover, you need £2 million cover for Europe, £5 million worldwide, but no more than that is necessary. For cancellation cover, make sure the amount is greater than the total cost of your trip: limits can be as low as £750. And with cancellation cover being a key benefit of travel insurance, do remember to have the policy in place as soon as you’ve booked any travel arrangements.</p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">On the most basic policies, baggage cover limits can be as little as £500. That is not enough to cover most people’s belongings; £1,500 is a more sensible figure. Check, too, the single-item limits for valuables, which can be a paltry £100 – far less than the cost of a laptop or an iPhone. Many insurers offer an optional ‘gadget cover’, for an extra premium of course.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Also watch out for very hefty excesses on the cheapest policies: they can be as high as £250.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Pre-existing medical conditions</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">You need to declare any disease or illness you have or have had, requiring medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. If not, you risk invalidating even an indirectly related claim. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-de6029f5ac19c39" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/22/12/4A6F8F8C00000578-5505157-Buying_budget_travel_insurance_policies_is_tempting_but_it_may_w-a-48_1521721164257.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Buying budget travel insurance policies is tempting, but it may well turn out to be a false economy, says Fred Mawer" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Buying budget travel insurance policies is tempting, but it may well turn out to be a false economy, says Fred Mawer</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Also remember to provide information about any relative with pre-existing medical conditions, if their health could affect your trip. Price-comparison website <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://allcleartravel.co.uk/">allcleartravel.co.uk</a> is a useful starting point for finding appropriate cover (including its own policies) for those with pre-existing medical conditions.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Other well-regarded specialist insurers in this field that don’t appear on the AllClear website include Avanti (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://avantitravelinsurance.co.uk/">avantitravelinsurance.co.uk</a>) and Staysure (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://staysure.co.uk/">staysure.co.uk</a>).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The European Health Insurance Card (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://ehic.org.uk/">ehic.org.uk</a>), which offers access to state healthcare for free or at reduced cost in the EU and a few other countries, includes treatment for pre-existing medical conditions – provided you’re not travelling with the intention of getting treatment.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Hazardous activities</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">If you’re at all active on your travels, make sure you read the small print listing sports and activities that are included, and those covered only if you pay extra or those that are excluded. The lists vary considerably between insurers. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">If you’re a spontaneous type, select a policy with a broad range of inclusions. You’ll need to pay extra for winter sports cover. And check the rules for off-piste skiing, and leaving skis unattended outside a restaurant.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-a13a2c0d5e82cb26" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/22/12/4A6F945200000578-5505157-With_the_exception_of_emergency_medical_care_claims_resulting_fr-a-50_1521721319567.jpg" height="421" width="634" alt="With the exception of emergency medical care, claims resulting from terrorist attacks or so-called ¿acts of God¿ ¿ hurricanes, floods etc ¿ are usually excluded from standard travel insurance policies. But again, check the small print: it¿s a grey area" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">With the exception of emergency medical care, claims resulting from terrorist attacks or so-called ‘acts of God’ – hurricanes, floods etc – are usually excluded from standard travel insurance policies. But again, check the small print: it’s a grey area</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Disasters</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">With the exception of emergency medical care, claims resulting from terrorist attacks or so-called ‘acts of God’ – hurricanes, floods etc – are usually excluded from standard travel insurance policies. But again, check the small print: it’s a grey area. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">You can sometimes pay extra for something called catastrophe or disaster cover, or the protection may come under optional travel disruption cover.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Airline failure</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Some policies automatically insure you against the airline you’re flying with going bust, but many cheaper ones don’t. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In the wording, look for scheduled airline failure insurance (SAFI), or end supplier failure, which applies not only to airline collapse but also other companies folding (such as a hotel or car rental firm).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Having this cover is sensible if you’re travelling independently and don’t have the financial back-up that comes from booking a package. AllClear, Avanti and Staysure have policies that include end supplier failure.</p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Buying budget travel insurance policies is tempting, but it may well turn out to be a false economy, says The Mail on Sunday's Fred Mawer.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-27T08:59:30.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Fred Mawer offers vital tips on getting the right travel cover</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-27T08:59:30.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5504799/Zoos-post-hilarious-Amazon-style-reviews-animals.html" title="'Excellent sleeper, best to avoid during waking hours': Zoos post hilarious Amazon-style reviews of their animals, from vultures to lions"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5499227/Timelapse-footage-captures-Athens-glory.html" title="From the majestic Acropolis to modern high rises, stunning timelapse footage captures Athens in all its glory"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5500983/This-NOT-penis-museum-sign-sends-Twitter-meltdown.html" title="'This is NOT the penis museum': Photo of sign on office door directing lost tourists to the Icelandic Phallological Museum sends Twitter into meltdown"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5494863/Bloodhounds-Warrior-Machine-help-catch-poachers-Africa.html" title="Meet bloodhounds Warrior and Machine, whose ability to follow scent trails for 130 miles is helping to catch poachers in Africa"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5526841/The-quietest-roads-America-revealed.html" title="From a deserted highway in Alaska to a tree-lined route in Maine you'll - almost - have to yourself: America's quietest roads revealed (just don't go all at once...) "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5531457/Singapores-Changi-named-worlds-best-airport-ninth-time.html" title="The world's best airports revealed: Singapore's Changi is No1 for the sixth year in a row (with Heathrow T2 named as the top terminal)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505281/A-mother-son-lose-serenity-Japan.html" title="Simply divine! A mother and son embark on a trip to Japan and lose themselves in the serenity of the country's temple gardens"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5526749/Passengers-taken-planes-Gatwick-driverless-BUSES.html" title="Passengers may be taken to their planes at Gatwick Airport on driverless BUSES if 'autonomous vehicle' trial this summer is successful"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5527849/Interactive-map-reveals-200-vineyards-visit-ENGLAND.html" title="Fascinating interactive map reveals the 200 vineyards you can visit… in ENGLAND and WALES (and you can stay the night at 47 of them)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html" title="We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html" title="The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5500535/Silversea-cruise-ship-cut-HALF-49ft-section-inserted.html" title="We're going to need a bigger boat? Coming right up! Gigantic cruise ship is cut IN HALF to make room for a 49ft extension"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5518461/Meet-woman-runs-one-Africas-exclusive-conservancies.html" title="'It's like living on an island': Meet the woman who runs one of Africa's most exclusive conservancies, living remotely on 19,000 acres surrounded by rhino, lions and giraffes "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5523657/The-164ft-superyacht-SILENT-mode.html" title="The 164ft superyacht with a SILENT mode: Hearing expert helped develop the hybrid-powered boat to ensure engine noise never goes above 'softly falling rain'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5504037/The-worlds-lesser-known-local-laws-customs-revealed.html" title="No mooning in Greece, don't swear in the UAE and vaping in Thailand could land you in jail for TEN YEARS: Laws and customs in holiday hotspots you need to brush up on before jetting off "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5500723/The-hated-travel-Instagram-poses-revealed.html" title="Selfies, hot dog legs and pinching the sun: The most-hated holiday Instagram poses revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5527257/POV-footage-shows-Blackpools-Icon-coaster-action-time.html" title="Thrilling point-of-view footage shows Blackpool's £16m 'Icon' roller coaster in action for the first time with newly unveiled copper-gold carriages zooming around the track at 50mph "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html" title="EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5545625/Heathrow-trials-driverless-vehicle-footage-revealing-robot-cargo-car-sees.html" title="Heathrow trials a driverless vehicle with fascinating footage revealing what the robot cargo car 'sees'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://allcleartravel.co.uk" title="AllClear Travel - Specialist Travel Insurance for Over 50's | Get a Quote"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://avantitravelinsurance.co.uk" title="Medical Travel Insurance | Avanti Travel Insurance™"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://ehic.org.uk" title="ehic.org.uk"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://staysure.co.uk" title="Staysure.co.uk | Specialist Insurance for Over 50s | Get a Quote"></link></item><item><title>The peak in China you can conquer with one step: Rock that's just two feet high is classified as a MOUNTAIN</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5545571/The-60cm-high-rock-Chinas-Shandong-Province-thats-classified-mountain.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 09:54:01 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5545571</guid><description><![CDATA[Jing Mountain in Shandong Province is just four feet long and two feet wide. Needless to say, it's become a popular tourist attraction.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">In the UK it has to measure more than 2,000 feet while in the US the peak usually has to be over 1,000 feet.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But in <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/china/index.html" id="mol-c6b66580-31a4-11e8-afae-c734a2dc8172">China</a>, 60cm (1.9ft) is apparently enough for a rock to be classified as a mountain.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Welcome to Jing Mountain in Shandong Province. It's China's smallest mountain and can be conquered with just one step. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Scroll down for video </strong></p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-74645421bf470a2c" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/27/10/4A937D0200000578-5545571-Jing_Mountain_in_Shandong_Province_is_China_s_smallest_mountain_-a-19_1522144251675.jpg" height="355" width="634" alt="Jing Mountain in Shandong Province is China's smallest mountain and can be conquered with just one step " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Jing Mountain in Shandong Province is China's smallest mountain and can be conquered with just one step </p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The rock is four feet long and just over two feet wide - but it's thought to go down 157 feet. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Needless to say, it's become a popular tourist attraction.  </p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Zhen Binhai, the former curator of Shouguang Museum, told <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://www.facebook.com/CNpearvideo">Pear Video</a> how the rock came to be a mountain.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said: 'During the Republic of China era, some people challenged the claim that it was a mountain and insisted it was just a rock. The authority arranged for people to dig around it. They dug a long time but couldn’t reach the bottom. Therefore it was classified as a mountain. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'There was another attempt to dig it in 1958, and they couldn’t get to the bottom either, so it was confirmed to be a mountain. It’s the smallest mountain in the country.'</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-ce01ed272a8b61cf" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/27/10/4A937E0E00000578-5545571-Zhen_Binhai_the_former_curator_of_Shouguang_Museum_said_During_t-a-18_1522144226566.jpg" height="359" width="634" alt="Zhen Binhai, the former curator of Shouguang Museum, said: 'During the Republic of China era the authority arranged for people to dig around it. They dug a long time but couldn’t reach the bottom. Therefore it was classified as a mountain'" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Zhen Binhai, the former curator of Shouguang Museum, said: 'During the Republic of China era the authority arranged for people to dig around it. They dug a long time but couldn’t reach the bottom. Therefore it was classified as a mountain'</p></div><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-524fe2be4ec1d9e1" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/27/10/4A937DFA00000578-5545571-The_rock_is_four_feet_long_and_just_over_two_feet_wide_but_it_s_-a-17_1522144216725.jpg" height="356" width="634" alt="The rock is four feet long and just over two feet wide - but it's thought to go down 157 feet " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The rock is four feet long and just over two feet wide - but it's thought to go down 157 feet </p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">A local man added: 'Legend has it that, hundreds of years ago, a woman urinated on the mountain causing it to stop growing.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://www.china.org.cn/china/2018-03/22/content_50735859.htm">China.org</a>, digging around the mountain is now forbidden.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, Jing Mountain might not be the smallest in the world, with Mount Wycheproof in Australia also famous for its lack of loftiness.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It has an elevation of just 43 metres (141ft) above sea level. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-256bc32d8ff3e492" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/27/09/4A93443500000578-5545571-image-a-4_1522138262399.jpg" height="449" width="634" alt="Mount Wycheproof in Australia, pictured, has also been named a mountain, despite being just 141 feet above sea level " class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Mount Wycheproof in Australia, pictured, has also been named a mountain, despite being just 141 feet above sea level </p></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>In the UK it has to measure more than 2,000 feet while in the US the peak usually has to be over 1,000 feet. But in China, 60cm (1.9ft) is apparently enough for a rock to be classified as a mountain. Welcome to Jing Mountain in Shandong Province. It's China's smallest mountain and can be conquered with just one step.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-27T10:59:05.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Rock in China that's just two feet high is classified as a MOUNTAIN</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-27T10:59:05.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505157/Fred-Mawer-offers-vital-tips-getting-right-travel-cover.html" title="Good job he checked his insurance! From suitcases to slaloms, Fred Mawer offers vital tips on getting the right cover"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html" title="EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505281/A-mother-son-lose-serenity-Japan.html" title="Simply divine! A mother and son embark on a trip to Japan and lose themselves in the serenity of the country's temple gardens"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html" title="We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html" title="The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5545625/Heathrow-trials-driverless-vehicle-footage-revealing-robot-cargo-car-sees.html" title="Heathrow trials a driverless vehicle with fascinating footage revealing what the robot cargo car 'sees'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.odditycentral.com/travel/chinas-smallest-mountain-is-less-than-1-meter-high-looks-more-like-a-big-rock.html" title="China's Smallest Mountain Is Less Than 1 Meter High, Looks More Like a Big Rock"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.china.org.cn/china/2018-03/22/content_50735859.htm" title="Is it a rock or a mountain?- China.org.cn"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.facebook.com/CNpearvideo" title="Pear Video"></link></item><item><title>Simply divine! A mother and son embark on a trip to Japan and lose themselves in the serenity of the country's temple gardens</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505281/A-mother-son-lose-serenity-Japan.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 07:13:48 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5505281</guid><description><![CDATA[The Mail On Sunday's Alice Bianchi-Clark decided to take her six-year-old on a long-haul trip to explore the calming wonders of Japan, with Around The World In 80 Gardens the inspiration.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">With its rugged rocks encircled by ripples of raked white gravel, the walled dry garden of Ryoan-ji is a haven of quiet serenity. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This small, enclosed space has no grass or leafy plants, only moss, sand and stones. Its simplicity leaves much to the imagination – and this is its strength.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">No wonder Edward’s eyes are wide. My son is only six and at his age there’s not much difference between a garden and a sandpit: both are realms for play. ‘Playtime?’ he says hopefully, before I tug him back on to the wooden viewing platform.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-c66edee8d78a9923" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36BEB400000578-5505281-image-m-111_1521651299406.jpg" height="379" width="634" alt="Blooming marvellous: Cherry blossom at the Kiyomizu-dera temple, a World Heritage Site located in the Higashiyama district of Kyoto" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Blooming marvellous: Cherry blossom at the Kiyomizu-dera temple, a World Heritage Site located in the Higashiyama district of Kyoto</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">We’re in Kyoto in central Japan, a 150-minute journey from Tokyo by Shinkansen bullet train. Monty Don’s TV series Around The World In 80 Gardens is the inspiration for our trip.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There’s an aura of enchantment once you reach the scattered but well- preserved historic temples with their cobbled paths and gardens.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It’s akin to the delight of stepping into a toyshop – less Toys R Us, more Walt Disney’s Pinocchio with a Japanese twist. The magic is everywhere and, perhaps, this is why the temple gardens are spellbinding. </p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Kinkaku-ji/Rokuon-ji features a dazzling golden three-storey pavilion set around a pond with a picturesque scattering of rocks and bridges amid pine and maple trees. Ginkakuji-Jisho-ji has a sand garden, piled to symbolise Mount Fuji. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Fushimi Inari Shrine stars countless vermilion Torii gates (entrances to shrines) and a towering bamboo forest. The Kokedera temple sits on a rug seemingly woven with soft mosses. Zen gardens celebrate nature.  </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-d67d5c428d4f53a7" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36BECF00000578-5505281-image-a-109_1521651280967.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Two young geishas seen wearing traditional costume in the streets of Kyoto" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Two young geishas seen wearing traditional costume in the streets of Kyoto</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Japanese have a heightened sensitivity to beauty. The challenge is to stop and be present for every little moment, no matter how trivial. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Edward does this effortlessly; he finds delight in every moment, in every detail. Could this be the key to the Zen spirit of mindful contentment?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Cherry trees are festooned with sakura: cerise and pale pink blossoms marking the arrival of spring. The Japanese revere sakura. Hamami, cherry blossom viewing, is a national pastime. We amble along a cherry tree-lined canal.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Snowflakes!’ cries Edward, stretching out joyful, playful arms to the sky. Petals waltz around us, airy and graceful in the breeze. Edward has never seen snow before, nor dancing cherry blossom.</p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-95899613a0f829b6" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/21/16/4A36BEDB00000578-5505281-image-a-110_1521651293233.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Kinkaku-ji/Rokuon-ji features a dazzling golden three-storey pavilion set around a pond with a picturesque scattering of rocks and bridges amid pine and maple trees" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Kinkaku-ji/Rokuon-ji features a dazzling golden three-storey pavilion set around a pond with a picturesque scattering of rocks and bridges amid pine and maple trees</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">We’re staying at Hiiragiya, a traditional ryokan, with painted paper sliding doors, tatami mats, cypress wooden baths and large windows with views over the camellia garden. It’s enchanting. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Clad in a kimono-like dressing gown, Edward tugs at my dress. He pouts and says: ‘Mummy, I think they forgot our beds.’ </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Thankfully, after a kaiseki tasting menu of delicacies served in lacquered doll-sized cabinets, futons are rolled out.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Edward curls into a slumbering ball, celebrating the simplicity of this moment. Children, truly, are wonders.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-e75f88e0-2851-11e8-9f4b-652de2bee917">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">TRAVEL FACTS </h3><div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">British Airways (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://ba.com/">ba.com</a>) offers return flights from Heathrow to Tokyo from £835. For information on Hiiragiya visit <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://hiiragiya.co.jp/en">hiiragiya.co.jp/en</a>. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Wendy Wu Tours (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://wendywutours.co.uk/">wendywutours.co.uk</a>) offers a 13-day Trails Of Japan tour, including flights and a stay in Kyoto, from £4,990pp. </p>                            </div>                        </div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>The Mail On Sunday's Alice Bianchi-Clark decided to take her six-year-old on a long-haul trip to explore the calming wonders of Japan, with Around The World In 80 Gardens the inspiration.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ted Thornhill</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-27T08:58:24.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>The serenity of Japan's temple gardens</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-27T08:58:24.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5545625/Heathrow-trials-driverless-vehicle-footage-revealing-robot-cargo-car-sees.html" title="Heathrow trials a driverless vehicle with fascinating footage revealing what the robot cargo car 'sees'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505269/Take-step-time-Rios-regal-Copacabana-Palace.html" title="Take a step back in time at Rio's regal Copacabana Palace - the first luxury hotel in South America, which welcomed Albert Einstein and Frank Sinatra"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544629/On-board-direct-flight-Qantas-UK-Australia.html" title="EXCLUSIVE On board the RETURN flight to Perth: Traveller on the first direct service from the UK to Australia reveals he felt so lively on landing that 'it almost felt like a trick'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html" title="We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539197/Broadcaster-Frank-Gardner-56-recalls-lifetime-adventures.html" title="The joys of shooting cans in Dungeness and dodging coral snakes in the Amazon! Broadcaster Frank Gardner, 56, recalls his lifetime of adventures"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5544325/Nerve-wracking-footage-shows-passengers-eye-view-journey-worlds-steepest-train.html" title="Nerve-wracking footage shows a passenger's-eye-view of a journey on the world's steepest train, which tackles a 48% gradient"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505127/A-tour-Canadian-peninsula-thats-thrilling-tranquil.html" title="Quebec's so beautiful it'll make you Gaspé... A tour of a Canadian peninsula that's thrilling and tranquil - and free of British tourists"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://ba.com" title="Book Flights, Holidays, City Breaks &amp; Check In Online | British Airways"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://hiiragiya.co.jp/en" title="HIIRAGIYA"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://wendywutours.co.uk" title="Escorted Tour Holidays to Asia &amp; South America | Wendy Wu Tours"></link></item><item><title>We had a whale of a time bumping into sea lions! In the Sea of Cortez the challenge isn't finding amazing animals - it's avoiding them</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5539229/How-finding-amazing-animals-Sea-Cortez-isnt-challenge-avoiding-them.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 22:02:01 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5539229</guid><description><![CDATA[It isn’t every day you come face to face with a sea lion but, The Mail on Sunday's Wendy Driver found herself eyeing one up just inches from her snorkelling mask on a recent trip to Mexico.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">It isn’t every day you come face to face with a sea lion but I found myself eyeing one up just inches from my snorkelling mask. I thought it was another swimmer brushing past until I realised the juvenile had nuzzled up to my arm.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was as playful as a puppy. It nibbled my fins with its sharp teeth and darted straight at my face before diving down to join its friends, twisting, twirling and somersaulting in a breathtaking display worthy of an Olympic gymnast.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our guide Wilson had given us strict instructions beforehand. ‘The pups are very inquisitive so if you lie flat on the surface of the water, they will check you out,’ he told me. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-51fe43d33a4b2308" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/24/12/4A815D7B00000578-5539229-Pelican_crossing_Passengers_watch_the_birds_dive_into_the_Sea_of-m-52_1521893752582.jpg" height="370" width="634" alt="Pelican crossing: Passengers watch the birds dive into the Sea of Cortez from a zodiac boat" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">Pelican crossing: Passengers watch the birds dive into the Sea of Cortez from a zodiac boat</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘But don’t touch them.’ Not that there was much chance of that – they were so fast and agile, they would have left me floundering far behind.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This was one of the highlights on an expedition cruise aboard Safari Endeavour in the Sea of Cortez in Mexico. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In early February the water was teeming with marine life, making it the ideal time to sail around this untamed wilderness of mountainous coastlines and uninhabited islands.</p><div>


</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">There were just 50 passengers on board and my shipmates were for the most part well-travelled Americans. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The atmosphere was casual, with no formal dinners or cocktail parties. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Instead, the evening entertainment comprised lectures on geology and the underwater world. The talk on the sex life of a sea-slug had the audience in fits of giggles.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Afterwards I’d go star-gazing on deck or watch sparkling flying-fish skim the waves.</p><div class="mol-img-group artSplitter">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-fa393d062ecca993" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/24/12/4A815D8100000578-5539229-image-m-59_1521894464625.jpg" height="408" width="634" alt="The Mail on Sunday's Wendy Driver found herself eyeing up a sea lion just inches from her snorkelling mask" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">The Mail on Sunday's Wendy Driver found herself eyeing up a sea lion just inches from her snorkelling mask</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Each night, Kent, the expedition leader, briefed us on the following day’s itinerary but plans were often changed at the last minute – for good reason.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our introductory talk was cut short by an announcement from the bridge that our first whale had been spotted. We rushed out to the deck with binoculars and cameras at the ready. Before long, we were surrounded by a dozen sperm whales before they dived to the ocean floor to feed on giant squid.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Kent admitted he had seen them only twice in the Sea of Cortez. It had set the bar high, but there were many more jaw-dropping moments to come.</p><div class="mol-article-quote floatRHS travel" id="mol-683de170-2f5d-11e8-aee4-f520a36db8ef">                            <div class="mol-article-quote-wrapper ccox">One afternoon, the sea was whipped up into a churning cauldron as hundreds of dolphins, joined by mobula rays, gulls and frigatebirds, indulged in a feeding frenzy</div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">One afternoon, the sea was whipped up into a churning cauldron as hundreds of dolphins, joined by mobula rays, gulls and frigatebirds, indulged in a feeding frenzy. Leaning over the bow, I listened to their high-pitched squeaks and watched them riding the waves beneath me.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On another occasion, a blue whale circled the ship while her inquisitive calf, weighing a mere two tons and already the length of a bus, came right alongside.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I soon settled into life on board the ship. I was up at first light to do yoga on deck as the dawn turned the sun-baked cliffs from a dusky pink to flaming red.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I could choose from a range of excursions. At Agua Verde I joined a mule trek into the scorched desert landscape where cacti grew as tall as trees. We plodded across dry river beds and through a cool green oasis under shady palms.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Later I kayaked along a deserted beach, ducking to avoid pelicans dive-bombing into the water to catch fish.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">My favourite hike was on Isla San Francisco, where I scrambled up the scree to a high ridge overlooking a cobalt sea fringed by a crescent of icing-sugar sand. Ospreys flew above us with silver slivers of fish dangling from their claws. </p><div class="artSplitter mol-img-group">    <div class="mol-img">  <div class="image-wrap">
    <img id="i-71d3d6065809e4ea" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/03/24/12/4A815D7000000578-5539229-image-m-58_1521893894651.jpg" height="398" width="634" alt="A friendly wave:  A huge grey whale takes a dive at Lopez Mateos" class="blkBorder img-share" />
  </div>

</div>    <p class="imageCaption">A friendly wave:  A huge grey whale takes a dive at Lopez Mateos</p></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Making our way back across the salt flats, we scooped up crystals to lick off our fists with shots of tequila.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One day we drove across the Baja peninsula to Lopez Mateos, a huge lagoon where grey whales come to give birth, having travelled more than 5,000 miles from Alaska. Twice driven to the verge of extinction by whalers in the 19th and early 20th Century, they now bizarrely seem to revel in human contact.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Regulations state that we had to keep a distance of at least 100ft, but within minutes of our small wooden skiff leaving the dock, a whale and her month-old calf ventured near. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The calf came up for air every couple of minutes, while its gargantuan mother surfaced so close that I could see the barnacles on her back and almost smell her salty breath.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I felt incredibly privileged to interact with these creatures we have hunted remorselessly. They have even been known to rub themselves against the side of the boat and let people stroke their rubbery skin.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">My last afternoon I went paddle-boarding in the beautiful aquamarine waters off Ensenada Grande. Afterwards, while I lounged in the hot tub on deck, a humpback whale came up to breach nearby, putting on a spectacular final show just for me.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox travel" data-version="2" id="mol-736d2ce0-2f3f-11e8-86ff-01e3cfad7740">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">TRAVEL FACTS </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">Windows On The Wild (<a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="http://windowsonthewild.com/">windowsonthewild.com</a>, 020 8742 1556) offers a nine-night holiday to Mexico from £3,880 per person, including return Aero Mexico flights from Heathrow to La Paz, transfers, two nights room-only in La Paz, a seven-night Baja’s Bounty cruise with all meals and drinks, activities and equipment. </p>                            </div>                        </div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>It isn’t every day you come face to face with a sea lion but The Mail on Sunday's Wendy Driver found herself eyeing one up just inches from her snorkelling mask on a recent trip to Mexico. She said when she visited in early February, the water was teeming with marine life.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator></dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-03-27T08:04:28.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>How finding amazing animals in the Sea of Cortez isn't a  challenge</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-03-27T08:04:28.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505085/Why-fans-Malta-returning-year.html" title="Malta? I'll be back... Revealing why fans of this magical Mediterranean island keep returning every year"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505051/The-best-new-boats-cruising-itineraries-revealed.html" title="Catch a piranha, dance a polka or dine in Provence! How to have a REAL adventure with some of the best new boats and cruising itineraries around"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5536851/AA-reveals-Cornwall-family-friendly-holiday-capital-UK.html" title="AA reveals Cornwall as the family-friendly holiday capital of the UK and names the best nine B&amp;Bs to take your little ones to"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535759/Best-value-European-breaks-Brits-revealed.html" title="Best-value European breaks for Brits revealed: Krakow in Poland is the cheapest city for a getaway and Amsterdam is the most expensive (with London not far behind)"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535621/The-worlds-lust-worthy-islands-BUY.html" title="The world's most lust-worthy islands you can BUY: From a £2.3m spit of sand in the Maldives to a £1.3m outcrop in Canada, the perfect properties for wannabe Robinson Crusoes revealed"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5535977/Rachael-Talibarts-stunning-wave-photographs.html" title="Real swell shots! Stunning photographs capture ferocious waves whipped up by a violent storm"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505071/Anna-Friel-daughter-discover-really-relax-St-Lucia.html" title="Simple treasures! The beach is beautiful, the sea is bliss and there's hotpot for breakfast. Anna Friel and her daughter discover how to really relax in St Lucia"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/article-5469345/Seven-reasons-European-cruise-ultimate-holiday.html" title="World class cocktails, amazing food and a new adventure every day! Seven reasons a European cruise is the ultimate holiday"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travelsupplement/article-5505119/Dreaming-Disney-Dont-let-turn-nightmare.html" title="Dreaming of Disney? Don't let it turn into a nightmare with intense heat, long walks and impossible schedules"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/travel/travel_news/article-5523657/The-164ft-superyacht-SILENT-mode.html" title="The 164ft superyacht with a SILENT mode: Hearing expert helped develop the hybrid-powered boat to ensure engine noise never goes above 'softly falling rain'"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://windowsonthewild.com" title="Windows On The Wild - Home"></link></item></channel></rss>