<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>MailOnline MSN</title><language>en-GB</language><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/feeds/msn/channel/money/subchannel/cars.rss</link><item><title>Two slow blokes in a very fast car: What happened when our man Ray Massey took the new Ferrari 488 Pista for a spin with Grand Tour star James May</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5811977/Ray-Massey-takes-new-Ferrari-488-Pista-spin-James-May.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:49:54 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5811977</guid><description><![CDATA[Ferrari paired up Ray Massey – not the fastest performance car driver – with ‘Captain Slow’, aka James  May, formerly of BBC’s Top Gear and now the Grand Tour, to test the new 488 Pista.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">‘How far is it to the test track from here?’ asked my driving companion for the day, as we pulled over on a remote Italian mountainside in Ferrari’s latest supercar, the 488 Pista.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘About an hour,’ I ventured, looking at the time and distance details on the sat-nav.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘How long have we got if we’re to make our slot?’ ventured my wingman.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘About an hour. If we get a move on. Now. Right now. And miss lunch,’ I intoned looking at my watch.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Some wag with a sense of humour at Ferrari had clearly thought it would be a wheeze to pair up yours truly – not exactly the fastest performance car driver in the parish – with ‘Captain Slow’, aka James  May, formerly of BBC’s Top Gear and now the Grand Tour for Amazon Prime.</p><img id="i-a96a574918366ff8" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF83DDA00000578-5811977-image-a-5_1528286861997.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Ferrari teamed up Ray Massey, right, with Grand Tour and ex-Top Gear star James May, left, to test drive the new 488 Pista" class="blkBorder img-share" /><video preload="none" id="815917903517168935" title="Ferrari's 'most powerful V8 ever' in action" poster="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF9105200000578-0-image-a-14_1528287035496.jpg">
    <source src="http://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/06/06/815917903517168935/1024x576_MP4_815917903517168935.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source>
  </video><p class="mol-para-with-font">James had taken a break from shooting to have a spin in the new 488 Pista, before heading off to Detroit – the US motor industry’s original Motown.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He and his colleagues Jeremy Clarkson and Richard Hammond are currently filming the third series of the Grand Tour. Will it be the last? He was diplomatically tight-lipped on that.</p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/bills/article-1648512/Warranties-cheaper-cover-cars-motorbikes-vans.html">
          
          <span>Keep your car on the road the easy way with online MOT and tax reminders</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our own miniature grand tour on winding Italian roads proved to be a rather fun, entertaining and quite leisurely cruise, before we both rather nervously returned for a blood-and-guts drive around Ferrari’s famous Fiorano race-track test circuit.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This is the track opposite the firm’s factory in Maranello, in northern Italy, where all civilian and F1 cars are put through their paces.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And this would be after hours of dilly-dallying in a car starting at a cool £250,000 that will sprint to 62mph in under three seconds.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">So we got a move on. Sort of. But sadly we did miss lunch – a near criminal offence in Italy.</p><img id="i-2c0011ff92735d73" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF83DA200000578-5811977-image-a-7_1528286917224.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="How far away is it and how long have we got? With neither renowned for their speed, Ray Massey, left, and James May, right, found themselves running out of time to get to the track" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">What rubbed salt into the wound was that it was at Ferrari’s legendary works canteen – the Cavallino restaurant near the factory gates in Maranello and the Fiorano test-track circuit from which we’d set off.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Named after Ferrari’s prancing horse logo and festooned with memorabilia, this near shrine to food and Ferrari is where the firm’s founder Enzo Ferrari ate and where employees, drivers, executives and fans still go today.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But I was in good company. Engaging Mr May – the ‘nice one’ of the Top Gear trio - is already the owner- after much self-confessed wavering – of a £250,000 limited edition Ferrari 458 Speciale.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He secured the very last one. Or rather Ferrari built an extra one for him.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He bought it just as what he calls the infamous ‘punchgate’ affair led to the canning of their much-loved  version of the BBC Top Gear programme, after Clarkson got into an altercation with a producer over a steak dinner.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">So May sold a few motor bikes at auction to help keep his finances in balance, before Amazon Prime waved some large cheques in the trio’s direction to recreate their on-screen chemistry with the lavishly filmed Grand Tour.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Now he is pondering whether to trade in his 458 Speciale, which is growing in value as a collectors’ car, for the new and improved 488 Pista.</p><img id="i-cfda1a244288a9d7" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF83D6400000578-5811977-image-a-8_1528286932331.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="His nickname from fellow presenters Jeremy Clarkson and Richard Hammond is Captain Slow, but James May is not really a slouch behind the wheel, says Ray Massey" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Pista is not a limited edition, though bosses told me the first two years’ production run of around 2,000 cars is already sold out to largely long-standing Ferrari customers.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It would be ungentlemanly and churlish to apportion any blame for our tardy progress.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This involved a fair bit of faffing about, including: looking for a licensed tobacco shops for my chain-smoking companion, stopping for a well-earned coffee in a rather cool motor bike themed café, shooting the breeze about life and everything from Lego to Zeppelins, and getting ‘lost’ down some beautiful if diverting Italian country lanes when the sat-nav threw a bit off a wobbly and took us ‘off pista’.</p><img id="i-c6044bff5f48f7f5" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF83CFA00000578-5811977-image-a-9_1528286940002.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="The 488 Pista is pretty phenomenal to drive, says Ray, especially for a self-confessed ‘ordinary driver' for whom it makes light work of piloting a supercar" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Stopping en route for that espresso at a roadside bikers’ café, we parked next to a tiny but similarly red liveried Piaggio mini-van and caused a mini-sensation. Italians male and female of every age and shape busied around the Ferrari, debating the 488 Pista’s finer points, taking photographs and engaging in heated debate as we looked on. Such passion. About a car.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ferrari is at pains to point out that this phenomenally high performance car with racing pedigree is designed to be as easy and fulfilling to drive on the road by ‘drivers of all types', whether race-track pros or high net-worth petrolheads.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And you will need deep pockets, of course. The price for a 488 Pista starts at £252,765 before you add any of the potentially very expensive extras. That includes £2,112 for the four-point harness, £8,640 for the go faster racing stripe, and £14,208 for the carbon-fibre wheels alone.</p><img id="i-d66f90f8950e0f73" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF83C9500000578-5811977-image-a-10_1528286952349.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="The new supercar’s Pista name means track and Ferrari claims it can be both a racer out there and civilised for the road" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The new supercar’s Pista name may not translate so well into English from the Italian, but simply means track. When you arrive at the circuit you see above you in giant letters alongside a prancing horse on a Ferrari red banner the words Pista di Fiorano.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">So what’s it actually like to drive? Pretty phenomenal, as you might expect. Especially for a self-confessed ‘ordinary driver' for whom it makes light work of piloting a supercar.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ferrari say the new 488 Pista builds and improves upon the earlier 488 GTB iteration and the previous 458 Speciale model, and is lighter, faster and more ‘extreme’.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is powered by a mighty 4.0 litre (3,902cc) V8 engine developing 720 horsepower linked to a slick 7-speed dual clutch automatic gearbox with manual override, via paddles on the steering wheel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It accelerates at blistering speed from rest to 0-62mph in just 2.85 seconds – and up to 124mph in just 7.6 seconds – reaching a potential top speed of 211mph. The vitally powerful brakes will bring you to a complete stop from 62mph in 29.6 metres.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Some comfort elements have been stripped out – such as the glovebox – in favour of open cubby holes.</p><img id="i-5c66ef233ac5336c" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/14/4CF837C200000578-5811977-Aerodynamic_tweaks_mean_the_Ferrari_488_Pista_also_has_up_to_20_-a-1_1528291480452.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Aerodynamic tweaks mean the  Ferrari 488 Pista also has up to 20% more ‘downforce’ to help keep it rooted to the tarmac" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ferrari says the 488 Pista has the highest amount of transfer of racing tech to one of its roadgoing cars.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It’s 90kg lighter, about the weight of a man, than its predecessor 488 GTB, and has 50 more horsepower (and 115hp more than my driving companion’s 458 Speciale).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It also has 50 per cent more new parts in the improved engine and virtually no turbo-lag when you floor the throttle.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Aerodynamic tweaks mean the Pista also has up to 20 per cent more downforce to help keep it rooted to the tarmac. This is helped by a clever S-Duct used for the first time on a road-going car. It’s basically a gap behind the front bumper that forces air between the bumper and the bonnet and then over the front windscreen, boosting downforce over the front axle.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There are sharper gear-shifts and lashings of lightweight carbon-fibre in the functional racing-style interior.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It still had room for my hefty laptop bag in the under-the-bonnet ‘boot’. And there’s that satisfying Ferrari roar, which has been further tuned and enhanced, when you open her up.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox floatRHS money" data-version="2" id="mol-de3afa10-6974-11e8-b588-eff387529d1d">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Ferrari 488 Pista </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">Price: £252,765</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">First deliveries: September 2018</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">First two years’ production sold out.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Top speed: 211mph</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Acceleration:</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">0-62mph: 2.85 seconds</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">0-124mph: 7.6 seconds</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Braking distance: 62mph to 0 mph: 29.6m</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Engine: 3,902cc V8 twin-tubo</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Power: 720 horsepower (CV)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Length: 4,605mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Width: 1,975mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Height: 1,206mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Kerb weight: 1,385kg</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Transmission: F1 7-speed dual clutch gearbox. Automatic with manual override.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Lap time around Fiorano circuit: 1 minute 21.5 seconds.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Fuel consumption: 25 mpg (11.5 litres per 100km)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">CO2 emissions: 263g/km</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Boot capacity: 170 litre </p>                            </div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Instead of conventional seat-belts, Ferrari had fitted our car with a racing harness which proved a proper faff to put on. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Strapped in like a trussed up turkey or the  client of some dodgy dominatrix, it then proved impossible to lean forward to adjust things like one’s seat. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The reversing chimes were louder than Big Ben, too.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Italian supercar maker makes this bold claim: ’The Ferrari 488 Pista offers drivers of all abilities an exceptional and exhilarating experience that normally only a competition car could deliver, setting a whole new benchmark in terms of driving pleasure for the Ferrari range.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It’s certainly managed that.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And you can forget all the insouciant on-screen clowning. Trust me, Mr May is a pretty capable driver of performance cars.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Arriving back at the Pista di Fiorano test track just in time for our allotted time slot, it was straight on with the helmet and out onto the circuit with Ferrari’s imposing chief tester Raffaele De Simone.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Compact, wiry and intensely focussed, he proved a master tutor: ‘Eez a Ferrari. You have to drive it like a Ferrari,’ he said sternly after my first lap.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Not, I took to be the implied message, like a complete wuss.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As my confidence and feel for the car grew, the succeeding laps proved better with a satisfying bit of twitch on the tight corners and much faster acceleration out of them. The new specially created Michelin Pilot Sport Cup K2 tyres – tested on a TameTire simulator and promising extra grip - and solid brakes were doing their stuff.</p><img id="i-9bbae15e7d290562" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/06/13/4CF8380200000578-5811977-image-a-12_1528286990657.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="A run with a Ferrari test driver in full track mode  was the automotive equivalent of a virtuoso violinist playing a Stradivarius, says Ray Massey" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">A masterclass by Raffaele behind the wheel with me strapped into the passenger seat was awesome and awe-inspiring.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In full track mode with all the safety key settings off, it was the automotive equivalent of a virtuoso violinist playing a Stradivarius. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">My faffy racing harness came into its own and kept me wedded firmly to my seat during a roller-coaster ride. Few if any drivers will be able to take this car to the limit in the manner of the man who fine-tuned its performance handling.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It’s a far better car than I am a driver and I couldn’t scratch the surface of its capabilities – though Raffaela’s full-blooded no-prisoners circuits did give me a seat-of-the pants insight.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But it’s easy enough to drive for yourself if you don’t feel compelled to push it to the limit</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I wonder if James May will buy one? </p><div class="moduleFull"></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>‘How far is it to the test track from here?’ asked my driving companion for the day, as we pulled over on a remote Italian mountainside in Ferrari’s latest supercar, the 488 Pista. ‘About an hour. If we get a move on. Right now. And miss lunch,’ I intoned looking at my watch. Ray Massey (left) – not the fastest performance car driver – reveals what happened when Ferrari paired him up with ‘Captain Slow’, aka James  May (right), formerly of BBC’s Top Gear and now the Grand Tour.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Simon Lambert</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-06T14:48:43.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Ray Massey takes the new Ferrari 488 Pista for a spin with James May</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-06T14:48:43.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5807929/Almost-hybrid-car-sale-fails-meet-official-fuel-economy.html" title="Almost every hybrid car on sale fails to meet its 'official' fuel economy - and one of the worst offenders is Britain's best seller"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5803465/Car-garages-holding-motorists-ransom-new-MOT-repair-costs.html" title="Some garages are already exploiting MOT changes by holding motorists to ransom for high car repair costs, industry expert says"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5808279/Audi-reveals-new-Q8-SUV.html" title="Audi reveals its all-new Q8 SUV as the battle of the luxury 4X4s with sporting aspirations intensifies"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/article-5801451/RAY-MASSEY-puts-Jaguars-lightning-fast-Pace-SUV-paces.html" title="Tesla rival? Jaguar's electric I-Pace put to the test"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5792127/Five-best-five-star-rated-cars.html" title="Five of the best five star cars: The reviewers' favourites that can all be bought brand new for less than £20k"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/markets/article-5788015/McLaren-handed-keys-new-50m-carbon-fibre-factory-site-former-Yorkshire-coal-mine.html" title="The supercar tubs made in Sheffield: McLaren handed keys to new £50m carbon fibre factory on site of former Yorkshire coal mine"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/bills/article-1648512/Warranties-cheaper-cover-cars-motorbikes-vans.html" title="Keep your car on the road the easy way with online MOT and tax reminders"></link></item><item><title>Almost every hybrid car on sale fails to meet its 'official' fuel economy - and one of the worst offenders is Britain's best seller</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5807929/Almost-hybrid-car-sale-fails-meet-official-fuel-economy.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 17:06:38 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5807929</guid><description><![CDATA[In the worst cases, hybrid cars - which use a combination of a combustion engine and electric power - are up to 80 miles per gallon shy of what manufacturers tell customers they can do.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Almost every hybrid car on sale in the UK falls short of its official fuel economy claims, according to new measurements.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In the worst cases, hybrid cars - which use a combination of a combustion engine and electric power - are up to 80 miles per gallon (mpg) shy of what manufacturers tell customers they can do.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One of the models that misses its claimed economy is the Mitsubishi Outlander PHEV - the most-bought hybrid car in the UK last year.</p><img id="i-a169d63aa047d260" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/14/4CEFFAED00000578-5807929-image-a-16_1528204548590.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Hybrid heist: A new study has revealed that the typical hybrid car in the UK returns just 70% of its advertised fuel economy on average" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The startling figures were released by automotive consumer site HonestJohn.co.uk, which has so far conducted 148,000 real-world fuel tests of vehicles to work out how close they are to their claims.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">While most models - including petrol and diesel - fall short of their published stats,  self-charging hybrids and plug-in hybrids are the most misleading when it comes to fuel consumption.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The motoring site said just one in 39 hybrid models deliver their advertised mpg.</p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" rel="nofollow">
          
          <span>How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Mercedes-Benz C-Class C350e is the UK’s worst performer, achieving just 36.9 per cent of its official fuel economy, while the BMW 3 Series 330e and Volkswagen Golf GTE are the second and third worst with a respective 37.2 per cent and 38.1 per cent. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Mitsubishi Outlander PHEV - the nation's most-bought plug-in hybrid -  was also among the worst offenders, achieving just 42.5 per cent of its claimed 166mpg.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On average, the typical hybrid car in the UK returns just 70 per cent of its advertised fuel economy on average, HonestJohn.co.uk found. </p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox money" data-version="2" id="mol-d9718d60-68bf-11e8-bba7-6ba1b9133dd3">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Hybrids furthest away from their claimed fuel economy figures</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>1.</strong> Mercedes-Benz C-Class C350e - achieves 36.9% of claimed mpg (134.5mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>2.</strong> BMW 3 Series 330e - achieves 37.2% of claimed mpg (134.5mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>3.</strong> Volkswagen Golf GTE - achieves 38.1% of claimed mpg (166.2mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>4.</strong> Mitsubishi Outlander PHEV - achieves 42.5% of claimed mpg (166mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>5.</strong> BMW 2 Series Active Tourer 225xe - achieves 56.4% of claimed mpg (141.2mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-small mol-style-italic">Source: HonestJohn.co.uk </p>                            </div>                        </div><img id="i-d541dee1dda6a8f9" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/14/4CEFFAD000000578-5807929-image-a-17_1528204865728.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="The Mitsubishi Outlander was the most bought PHEV in the UK last year" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-37df653a004864ba" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/14/4CEFFAAE00000578-5807929-image-a-18_1528204895630.jpg" height="357" width="634" alt="The Outlander PHEV has proved popular across the continent, already surpassing 100,000 sales" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-489faee3e9cca618" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/14/4CEFFA9F00000578-5807929-image-m-20_1528204928297.jpg" height="414" width="634" alt="The Mercedes-Benz C-Class C350e plug-in hybrid is that model that misses its advertised mpg by the most, achieving just 36.9% of the claimed figure" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">This gap between the advertised mpg and what can be achieved by customers can have a serious impact on annual fuel costs. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This being made worse by the fact that fuel prices have risen every single day since the end of March, adding more than 8p to a litre of fuel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">For instance, with petrol current averaging 129.2p per litre, according to PetrolPrices.com, a Mitsubishi Outlander PHEV should cost £354 in fuel costs - based on the claimed mpg - for a driver covering 10,000 miles.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, HonestJohn.co.uk's measurement says it will really cost drivers £833 - a difference of £479.  </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">At the opposite end of the performance spectrum, the Lexus GS 450h is the hybrid car that gets closest to its claimed mpg figures.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It achieves 84.2 per cent of its fuel economy claims.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox money" data-version="2" id="mol-44bb5f60-68c0-11e8-bba7-6ba1b9133dd3">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Hybrids closest to  their claimed fuel economy figures</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>1.</strong> Lexus GS 450h - achieves 84.2% of claimed mpg (45.6mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>2.</strong> Toyota RAV4 Hybrid 2WD - achieves 79.3% of claimed mpg (57.6mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>3.</strong> Toyota Yaris 1.5 VVT-I Hybrid - achieves 77.9% of claimed mpg (up to 91.2mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>4.</strong> Kia Niro 1.6 GDI Hybrid - achieves 77.4% of claimed mpg (up to 74.3mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>5.</strong> Toyota C-HR 1.8 Hybrid - achieves 77.2% of claimed mpg (74.3mpg)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-small mol-style-italic"> Source: HonestJohn.co.uk</p>                            </div>                        </div><img id="i-e72fbc8e79c73ed2" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/14/4CEFFABE00000578-5807929-image-a-23_1528204989987.jpg" height="425" width="634" alt="The Lexus GS450h is the hybrid that gets closest to its official fuel economy figures when tested on the road" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Honest John’s managing editor, Daniel Powell, said: 'This is the most comprehensive study into hybrid fuel economy ever to be carried out. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'However, while these models are advertised with lofty mpg figures that will appeal to cost conscious drivers, our research shows that on-the-road economy is somewhat different.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Given that car buyers are being urged to replace their petrol and diesel cars with new low emission hybrids, we think more needs to be done to ensure drivers get a fair deal when it comes to real mpg.' </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">While the disparity for hybrid cars is significant, it should shrink when official fuel economy figures are measured under the new World Harmonised Light Vehicles Test Procedure (WLTP) that was introduced last year.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The majority of new car registrations will need to adhere to this test cycle from September 2018. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And while the average hybrid car is some way from its official fuel efficiency figure, they still remain some of the most economical cars on sale to date. </p><div class="moduleFull"></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>In the worst cases, hybrid cars - which use a combination of a combustion engine and electric power - are up to 80 miles per gallon shy of what manufacturers tell customers they can do. One of the models that misses its claimed economy is the Mitsubishi Outlander PHEV (inset) - the most-bought hybrid car in the UK last year.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Simon Lambert</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-06T10:08:14.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Almost every hybrid on sale fails to meet its official fuel economy</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-06T10:08:14.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5803465/Car-garages-holding-motorists-ransom-new-MOT-repair-costs.html" title="Some garages are already exploiting MOT changes by holding motorists to ransom for high car repair costs, industry expert says"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5807313/New-cars-sales-surge-year-declines.html" title="New cars sales surge again in May after a year of declines but diesel sales still down by nearly a quarter"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5801619/The-learner-driver-takes-motorway-new-law-change.html" title="The first learner driver takes to the motorway as law change allows provisional licence holders to use Britain's fastest-moving roads from June"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/article-5801451/RAY-MASSEY-puts-Jaguars-lightning-fast-Pace-SUV-paces.html" title="Jaguar's electric SUV aims to tear up the rulebook: RAY MASSEY puts the lightning fast I-Pace through its paces"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5771477/Ten-things-need-know-car-finance.html" title="Ten things you need to know about car finance: How to make sure you don't get stung if you buy a new vehicle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5772201/Some-pothole-repair-bills-cost-nearly-twice-average-national-monthly-wage.html" title="How a pothole could cost you nearly two month's wages: Damage to cars results in some repairs costing £3,800"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762697/Some-85-500-electric-car-chargers-needed-2-years-demand.html" title="The UK's electric car charging grid is 'playing catch-up', as study reveals 85,500 chargers are needed in the next two years to meet demand"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5754073/Four-gadgets-need-protect-car-theft-scams.html" title="The four gadgets you need to protect your car: Motorists flock to buy them to guard against a new wave of thefts and scams"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" title="How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover"></link></item><item><title>Audi reveals its all-new Q8 SUV as the battle of the luxury 4X4s with sporting aspirations intensifies</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5808279/Audi-reveals-new-Q8-SUV.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 15:02:45 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5808279</guid><description><![CDATA[It is Audi’s answer to the growing number of top of the market luxury off-roaders including Britain’s Range Rover Sport, BMW’s X6, Mercedes-Benz’s GLE Coupe and the Maserati Levante.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">You may not think that the world needs another large £80,000 SUV with sporty aspirations, but Audi certainly does.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The German carmaker today took the wraps off its new flagship Q8 sports utility vehicle at its global launch in China. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And instead of being bigger than the already super-sized Q7, as the model numbering might suggest, this is Audi’s answer to the growing number of top-end 'sporty' off-roaders, including Britain’s Range Rover Sport, BMW’s X6, Mercedes-Benz’s GLE Coupe and the Maserati Levante.</p><img id="i-d5385e7bec027a5e" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04E4600000578-0-image-m-59_1528207695905.jpg" height="426" width="634" alt="Audi's new sleek SUV: The Audi Q8 will become the German brand's range-topping 4X4 when it goes on sale in the UK in July" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The almost five metre long and two metre wide Q8, which will cost between £65,000 and £80,000, has been styled for a more coupe-like aerodynamic look - designed to appear much lower than its smaller Q7 sibling.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But while it is 66mm shorter it is also 27mm wider with a wheelbase stretching to nearly 3 metres, allowing for more space inside. Frameless doors add to the hoped-for streamlined look.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It aims to bring the luxury of its flagship A8 limousine - seen at glitzy and glamorous red-carpet events from the Oscars to the Baftas and Olivier awards - into the SUV sector. </p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" rel="nofollow">
          
          <span>How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The large 4X4 will reach UK shores in July packed with hi-tech kit and a luxury interior.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Although built in the German-car-maker’s Bratislava plant, Audi’s chairman Rupert Stadler launched the car in China - in the rapidly expanding city of Shenzhen just a short hop from the former British territory of Hong Kong - because it is one of the world’s fastest growing markets for selling and building luxury vehicles.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He also hosted a major Audi China Brand Summit.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Audi believes the new Q8 lives up to the spirit of Audi’s longstanding slogan of ‘Vorsprung durch Technik’ – a leap forward or advance through technology – which began with the launch of the original four-wheel drive Audi Quattro in the 1980s.</p><img id="i-f9b210036e63c54f" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04D7D00000578-0-image-m-60_1528207780218.jpg" height="432" width="634" alt="Created with a more coupe-like aerodynamic look, the new Q8 has been designed to appear much lower than its smaller Q7 sibling" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-5bbe2f4217f7dbe0" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04DE100000578-0-image-m-61_1528207808867.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Frameless doors add to the hoped-for streamlined effect that has been popular among SUV makers in recent years" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-69fa5013ac6189ed" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04F4D00000578-0-Range_Rover_Sport-a-68_1528208134409.jpg" height="270" width="306" alt="Range Rover Sport" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-fc44a0a855266eef" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04F2D00000578-0-BMW_X6-a-69_1528208140110.jpg" height="270" width="306" alt="BMW X6" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-488b4a4491fe66ec" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04F4500000578-0-image-a-70_1528208145462.jpg" height="289" width="306" alt="Mercedes-Benz GLE-Class" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-91446cf4e1fa7750" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04F3900000578-0-image-a-71_1528208150512.jpg" height="289" width="306" alt="Maserati Levante" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The launch car for the UK will be the six-cylinder 50 TDI in S-Line trim powered by a 3.0-litre diesel engine, linked to a mild hybrid, developing 286 horse-power, that can sprint from rest to 62mph in 6.3 seconds up to a top speed where permitted – such as German Autobahns – of 144mph. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This includes high definition LED lights, 21 inch alloy wheels, and adaptive sport suspension as standard.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It will be followed later by a fully-loaded Vorsprung edition with 22-inch alloy wheels, head-up display, and a full Valcona leather package as standard, plus a Bang &amp; Olufsen Premium Sound System.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Audi said it had wanted to remain faithful to the  styling of the original Q8 Sport concept model first shown at the 2017 Geneva motor Show.</p><img id="i-21206ba083e4ba5c" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04D6200000578-0-image-m-62_1528207832940.jpg" height="427" width="634" alt="Launch car for the UK will be this six-cylinder 50 TDI in S-Line trim" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-46d2f12be433c54e" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04E7A00000578-0-image-m-63_1528207844213.jpg" height="446" width="634" alt="It is powered by a 3.0-litre diesel engine, linked to a mild hybrid, developing 286 horse-power" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-c3ab6ce5bb67d3ca" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04EA100000578-0-image-m-64_1528207855668.jpg" height="428" width="634" alt="It can sprint from rest to 62mph in 6.3 seconds up to a top speed where permitted – such as German Autobahns – of 144mph." class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">It said it was positioning the Q8 as ’the fusion of an elegant four-door luxury coupe with a large SUV, with echoes of an Audi icon – the original Quattro.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It also claims to have won the space-race against its rivals. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 60-litre rear luggage compartment, which Audi says is big enough for two golf-bags laid diagonally, increases to 1,755 litres with rear seats folded. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A power-operated tail-gate adds to the practicality.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The new Q8 also heralds a tweak to the face of Audi’s SUV family with a bold and aggressive-looking octagonal grille. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Each of the bright high-definition matrix LED headlights consists of 24 individual LED lights.</p><img id="i-f5706951de65015f" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04DCC00000578-0-image-m-65_1528207947558.jpg" height="439" width="634" alt="The Q8 boasts a 60-litre rear luggage compartment, which Audi says is big enough for two golf-bags laid diagonally, increases to 1,755 litres with rear seats folded" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-da83df294fd3c3c5" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04DB600000578-0-image-m-66_1528207959619.jpg" height="446" width="634" alt="A smaller 3.0-litre diesel with 231 horse-power (Q8 45 TDI) and a 3.0-litre petrol-engined SUV developing 340 horse-power (Q8 55 TFSI) are to follow early next year" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The mild hybrid system fitted to the 3.0-litre TDI diesel integrates a rechargeable lithium battery underneath the luggage compartment floor, linked to a belt alternator starter and a 48-volt electrical system.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The regenerative braking system can recover power during deceleration. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The SUV can coast on electrical power with the engine switched off at speeds between 34mph and 99mph, before the hybrid system restarts the engine.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A smaller 3.0-litre diesel with 231 horse-power (Q8 45 TDI) and a 3.0-litre petrol-engined SUV developing 340 horse-power (Q8 55 TFSI) are to follow early next year.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Although fuel consumption has yet to be confirmed, expect around 40 miles to the gallon.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One key option (which will be standard on the higher-spec Vorsprung specification) is the all-wheel steering, which can also turn the rear wheels by up to five degrees for greater manoeuvrability.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Audi said: ’At slow speed they steer in the opposite direction to the front wheels, reducing he turning circle of the SUV by a good metre. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘At high speed, they steer in the same direction as the front axle, supporting stability during lane changes.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The adaptive air sport suspension has four setting s which can vary ride height by up to 90mm to improve handling over different surfaces and terrains. </p><img id="i-f68d9e8db6a7fdae" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04F0400000578-0-image-a-53_1528207647893.jpg" height="475" width="634" alt="The interior of the new Q8 seeks to be quite minimalist with two high-resolution touchscreens taking over most of the functions" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-aadf018cd81a7021" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04EF100000578-0-image-a-54_1528207669012.jpg" height="475" width="634" alt="Audi designers said the incorporation of the technology into the touchscreen systems means the dashboard needs almost no buttons or knobs" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-a2a6f916a81cb433" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04EC900000578-0-image-a-55_1528207672752.jpg" height="475" width="634" alt="Rear leg room dimensions are yet to be published, but it looks roomy enough for adult passengers" class="blkBorder img-share" /><div class="art-ins mol-factbox floatRHS money" data-version="2" id="mol-992680c0-68ca-11e8-bba7-6ba1b9133dd3">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Audi Q8: Will it fit in my garage?</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <img id="i-2fef786c25850a12" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/15/4CF04E5D00000578-0-image-m-67_1528207978952.jpg" height="152" width="274" alt="" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Model:</strong> Audi Q8 S-Line</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>On sale:</strong> from July</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Price:</strong> from £65,000 (range to to £80,000-plus)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Seats:</strong> 5</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Length:</strong> 4,986mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Width:</strong> 1,995mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Height:</strong> 1,705mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Gears:</strong> 8-speed tiptronic automatic</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Drive:</strong> Quattro all-wheel drive</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Engine:</strong> 3.0 litre 50 TDI Quattro (286 horse-power) with mild electric hybrid system.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>CO2:</strong> TBC </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>MPG:</strong> TBC</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Ground clearance:</strong> Up to 254mm</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Top speed:</strong> 144mph</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Acceleration 0-62mph:</strong> 6.3 seconds</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Wheels:</strong> 21-inch (22 inch on Vorsprung models)</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Luggage compartment:</strong> 60 litres.  Increases to 1,755 litres with rear sears folded.</p></div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The interior of the new Q8 seeks to be quite minimalist with two high-resolution touchscreens taking over most of the functions. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Audi says it needs ‘almost no buttons or knobs.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The upper 10.1-inch display controls the infotainment and navigation. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The lower 8.6 inch display allows the driver to manage heating, ventilation, air-conditioning and other ‘comfort’ functions.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Voice-control can understand sentences such as ‘I am hungry’ and offer suggestions for nearby restaurants. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There are also a host of safety systems and packages to help the driver.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A ‘Tour Assist’ package helps keep the car in lane, keep a safe distance from other cars, adjust to the prevailing speed limit, and reduce stress in traffic jams.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Audi said: ’It automatically adjusts to the current speed limit, reduces the speed before corners, during turning and on roundabouts.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It detects whether the driver is inactive – whether through illness or falling asleep – and gives a series of visual, acoustic and physical warnings</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">’If this does not prompt a reaction, the system takes control of the Audi Q8 and automatically stops it in its own lane,' the German car giant said.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It also triggers an emergency call. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sales books for the range-topping SUV open next month. </p><div class="moduleFull"></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>It is Audi’s answer to the growing number of top of the market luxury off-roaders including Britain’s Range Rover Sport, BMW’s X6, Mercedes-Benz’s GLE Coupe and the Maserati Levante. The large 4X4 will reach UK shores in July priced from around to £65,000 to more than £80,000 packed with hi-tech kit and a luxury interior.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Simon Lambert</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-05T16:09:20.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Audi reveals new Q8 SUV - an ultra-luxurious 4X4</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-05T16:09:20.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5803465/Car-garages-holding-motorists-ransom-new-MOT-repair-costs.html" title="Some garages are already exploiting MOT changes by holding motorists to ransom for high car repair costs, industry expert says"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5807313/New-cars-sales-surge-year-declines.html" title="New cars sales surge again in May after a year of declines but diesel sales still down by nearly a quarter"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5801619/The-learner-driver-takes-motorway-new-law-change.html" title="The first learner driver takes to the motorway as law change allows provisional licence holders to use Britain's fastest-moving roads from June"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/article-5801451/RAY-MASSEY-puts-Jaguars-lightning-fast-Pace-SUV-paces.html" title="Jaguar's electric SUV aims to tear up the rulebook: RAY MASSEY puts the lightning fast I-Pace through its paces"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" title="How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5771477/Ten-things-need-know-car-finance.html" title="Ten things you need to know about car finance: How to make sure you don't get stung if you buy a new vehicle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5772201/Some-pothole-repair-bills-cost-nearly-twice-average-national-monthly-wage.html" title="How a pothole could cost you nearly two month's wages: Damage to cars results in some repairs costing £3,800"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762697/Some-85-500-electric-car-chargers-needed-2-years-demand.html" title="The UK's electric car charging grid is 'playing catch-up', as study reveals 85,500 chargers are needed in the next two years to meet demand"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5754073/Four-gadgets-need-protect-car-theft-scams.html" title="The four gadgets you need to protect your car: Motorists flock to buy them to guard against a new wave of thefts and scams"></link></item><item><title>Some garages are already exploiting MOT changes by holding motorists to ransom for high car repair costs, industry expert says</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5803465/Car-garages-holding-motorists-ransom-new-MOT-repair-costs.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 10:29:57 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5803465</guid><description><![CDATA[It's been just a fortnight since changes were made to the MOT, and already car owners are being ripped off by some garages, according to a new report.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">It's been just a fortnight since changes were made to the MOT, and already car owners are being ripped off by some garages, according to a new report.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As of May 20, the MOT test has included three new fault categories: minor, major and dangerous. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The latter - and most serious - of these requires the owner to have the issue resolved before being able to use the car again.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Car site <span class="class">MotorEasy said it has already had reports of mechanics bullying motorists into paying over the odds for repairs - suggesting that they cannot take their vehicle away and thus must pay the price they quote for the job.</span></p><img id="i-abe2587825cb6884" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/04/15/4CE7D42A00000578-5803465-Motorists_being_held_to_ransom_Car_owners_have_already_reported_-a-18_1528123819029.jpg" height="478" width="634" alt="Motorists being 'held to ransom': Car owners have already reported that garages have pumped up the price of repairs for faults that need to be resolved to pass the recently updated MOT" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The vehicle ownership and maintenance service provider said garages are using the new categories to 'hold motorists to ransom' over unnecessary repairs.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Under the <a style="font-weight: bold;" class="class" href="/money/cars/article-5524077/Diesel-drivers-MOT-test-difficult-May.html">new Driver and Vehicles Standards Agency (DVSA) rules</a>, faults found during an MOT are classified under the three levels.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">While minor faults can be repaired at a later date and won't result in the vehicle failing the roadworthiness test, official guidance states that a major fault will result in the car automatically flunking an MOT and will need to be fixed before it is retested.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, cars that are deemed to have a dangerous defect should not be driven at all until the problem has been fixed - meaning owners can be made to feel that they have to fork out for the cost of repairs at the garage conducting the MOT.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This is not the case and they could instead ask other garages to quote for the work and potentially collect their car. </p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" rel="nofollow">
          
          <span>How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">MotorEasy said that within just two weeks of the changes being introduced, it has received reports from drivers that they're being trapped into getting repairs done.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In many cases owners are being charged over the odds by mechanics knowing that the new rules state that a  vehicle shouldn't be driven again until the dangerous fault has been resolved.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But despite the changes, the law states that garages have no power to stop motorists from driving their car away, regardless of the severity of the MOT failure.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'We would, naturally, never condone driving on public roads with a dangerous car and anyone who does so will still be risking a fine and penalty points if they are stopped by police,' explained MotorEasy founder, Duncan McClure Fisher.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'However, we have already seen examples of garages using an interpretation of the wording in the DVSA guidance to bullying motorists to get repairs done before leaving the premises, which they have no right to do.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Unscrupulous businesses could not only make customers feel they’re unable to take their car away if it fails, but could also hold the customer to ransom over parts and labour prices as a result. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'After all, if you think you can’t drive the car away, you lose all your negotiation power.' </p><img id="i-1584194b8da8ada0" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/04/15/4CE7D43900000578-5803465-image-a-17_1528123750379.jpg" height="475" width="634" alt="Under the new MOT rules introduced on 20 May 2018, any car deemed to have a 'dangerous' defect cannot be driven until the fault has been repaired. Some unscrupulous garages are reportedly using this restriction to pump up the cost of repairs knowing drivers can't drive their vehicles away to have work carried out elsewhere" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The DVSA’s MOT service manager, Neil Barlow, clarified: 'If a car has failed its MOT with a dangerous fault, DVSA’s advice is that it should not be driven until the defect is repaired. This is because it’s dangerous to both the driver and other road users.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Be he then confirmed that: 'Garages are unable to prevent owners from driving their cars away. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'But they will provide advice to the owner on what they should do to keep the car safe.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">With many motorists unaware that they are not restricted to having dangerous defects repaired at the same location where the MOT is  conducted, car owners are already claiming they've been fleeced garages that are also approved test centres.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Rob Cody, of Watford, told MotorEasy that he was put in a difficult situation when his Toyota Auris failed its MOT because of a faulty rear seat belt and was told that he couldn’t drive the car away, despite the fact he had no passengers travelling with him in the car.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said: 'It was really stressful; I have a long commute and needed to get home, but I also didn’t want to be ripped off.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Similarly, Ford Mondeo owner Donald McLean, of Clydebank, was told he needed new indicator covers and a suspension arm in order to pass the MOT, but was concerned at the six hours of expensive labour he was quoted by the garage that carried out the test.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I knew other garages would do the job quicker, saving me £200, but I didn’t want to get a fine so paid the extra,' he explained.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Both drivers said they were made to feel that they could not take the car from the garage and had to borrow money to cover the cost of the repair bills.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to MotorEasy stats, around 40 per cent of cars fail their MOT every year, with the average repair cost to make the vehicle roadworthy working out at £174. </p><div class="moduleFull"></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>It's been just a fortnight since changes were made to the MOT, and already car owners are being ripped off by some garages, according to a new report. Vehicle ownership and maintenance service provider MotorEasy said it has already had reports of mechanics bully motorists into paying for repairs on site that don't need doing.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Simon Lambert</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-06T01:53:10.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Car garages holding motorists to ransom over new MOT repair costs </mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-06T01:53:10.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5801619/The-learner-driver-takes-motorway-new-law-change.html" title="The first learner driver takes to the motorway as law change allows provisional licence holders to use Britain's fastest-moving roads from June"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/article-5801451/RAY-MASSEY-puts-Jaguars-lightning-fast-Pace-SUV-paces.html" title="Jaguar's electric SUV aims to tear up the rulebook: RAY MASSEY puts the lightning fast I-Pace through its paces"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5771477/Ten-things-need-know-car-finance.html" title="Ten things you need to know about car finance: How to make sure you don't get stung if you buy a new vehicle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5772201/Some-pothole-repair-bills-cost-nearly-twice-average-national-monthly-wage.html" title="How a pothole could cost you nearly two month's wages: Damage to cars results in some repairs costing £3,800"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762697/Some-85-500-electric-car-chargers-needed-2-years-demand.html" title="The UK's electric car charging grid is 'playing catch-up', as study reveals 85,500 chargers are needed in the next two years to meet demand"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5754073/Four-gadgets-need-protect-car-theft-scams.html" title="The four gadgets you need to protect your car: Motorists flock to buy them to guard against a new wave of thefts and scams"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762489/VW-owners-26-October-claim-dieselgate-compensation.html" title="Owners of VW cars in the UK caught up in dieselgate scandal have until October 26 to claim for compensation"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5761621/GoldenEye-Aston-Martin-DB5-film-car-hammer-1-6m.html" title="James Bond Aston Martin DB5 driven by Pierce Brosnan in GoldenEye to go under the hammer for £1.6MILLION"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" title="How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover"></link></item><item><title>New cars sales surge again in May after a year of declines but diesel sales still down by nearly a quarter</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5807313/New-cars-sales-surge-year-declines.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 10:28:54 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5807313</guid><description><![CDATA[Some 193,000 new cars were registered in May, an increase of 3.4 per cent compared with 186,000 during the same month last year.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Sales of new cars have pulled out of the slow lane as they grew for the second month in a row, new industry data shows.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Some 193,000 new cars were registered in May, an increase of 3.4 per cent compared with 186,000 during the same month last year, according to the latest monthly figures by the Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This is the second successive increase after 12 months of decline through to March, following a 10.4 per cent jump in April.</p><img id="i-2eb41791a6428380" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/11/16F369B200000514-5807313-image-a-11_1528193385074.jpg" height="393" width="634" alt="In demand: But much of May's increase is due to poor numbers from April and May last year" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, as already noted with April’s numbers, much of the increase is due to poor numbers from April and May last year, when the implementation of new Vehicle Excise Duty tax rates caused a rush of new registrations in March. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In May 2017, new registrations fell by 8.5 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And despite the second successive rise in May, new car sales are still down 6.8 per cent over the year so far, with the SMMT blaming ‘economic and political uncertainty’ for an impact on demand.</p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html">
          
          <span>How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sales of diesel cars continued to be affected by pollution concerns and new regulations, falling by 23.6 per cent to 62,260, the 14th consecutive month of declines.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, the drop in diesel sales was outweighed by higher demand for petrol cars, which rose 23.5 per cent and alternatively fuelled vehicles, which rose 36.1 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">These 'cleaner' hybrid, plug-in hybrid and electric vehicles now have a market share of 5.8 per cent, compared to 4.4 per cent a year ago.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">SMMT chief executive Mike Hawes said May’s figures were ‘encouraging’ and suggested that the market was now starting to rebalance.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘To ensure long-term stability, we need to avoid any further disruption to the market, and this will require sustainable policies that give consumers and businesses the confidence to invest in the new cars that best suit their needs,’ he added.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Fleet renewal is the fastest way to improve air quality and reduce CO2, and this applies to hybrid and plug-in technologies as well as the latest low emission petrol and diesels which, for many drivers, remain the right choice economically and environmentally.’</p><img id="i-2949265fa50e6259" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/05/11/4CED63BA00000578-5807313-image-m-13_1528193405482.jpg" height="463" width="634" alt="May's new registrations were  3.4 per cent higher than in May 2017" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Howard Archer, chief economic advisor to the EY ITEM Club, was cautious about May’s rise in new registrations.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said: ‘It should be kept in mind that May’s year-on-year gain benefited (as had April’s) from the fact that new car sales had fallen significantly in the corresponding months in 2017 following changes to vehicle excise duty (VED) at the start of April 2017.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Car sales had also been boosted in April by more selling days in April 2018 than in April 2017 due to the earlier Easter this year.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He also added that car sales may also have benefited in both May and April from some purchases being delayed from March when the severe weather made life very difficult for UK consumers. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Alex Buttle, director of car buying comparison website Motorway.co.uk, said it was too early to be talking about a recovery. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But he added: 'It's not all doom and gloom though. Both petrol and AFV new registrations were up substantially last month and it's dire diesel sales that continue to massively skew overall figures.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Take diesel out of the equation, and the picture doesn't look quite so grim. But May is the eleventh consecutive month in which diesel sales have been down more than 20%.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The car industry's efforts to promote the benefits of Euro 6 diesel cars are clearly not resonating with consumers, and it's difficult to see how confidence can be restored.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Richard Jones, MD at finance provider Black Horse said the figures 'reflect a natural market correction' with new car sales beginning to balance out compared to last year's declines but said there was still caution around diesel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said: 'Confusion over fuel choice continues to cause a fall in sales of new diesels. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'We’re seeing signs that the public policy debate on emissions and diesel is shifting to recognise the key issue of getting drivers into newer, cleaner cars irrespective of fuel type but we still have a long road ahead.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'For example, how many people know you could drive a 4.5-litre Euro 6 diesel car into London’s low emissions zone without being charged? </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Clarity for consumers around the diesel dilemma and fuel options overall will drive more informed purchasing decisions and help remove older more polluting vehicles from the UK’s roads. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The biggest difference we can make in the next five years is to accelerate the removal of these older cars and replace with newer Euro 6 technology.'</p><div class="moduleFull"></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Some 193,000 new cars were registered in May, an increase of 3.4 per cent compared with 186,000 during the same month last year, according to the latest monthly figures by the Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders. This is the second successive increase after 12 months of decline through to March, following a 10.4 per cent jump in April.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>This Is Money</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Rob Hull</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-05T11:40:20.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>New cars sales surge again in May after a year of declines</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-05T11:40:20.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5690529/New-diesel-car-sales-quarter.html" title="New car sales surge in April after a year of declines but industry warns increase does not signal a recovery"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5580979/Governments-bashing-diesel-takes-toll-37-decline-sales-March.html" title="New car sales fall 16% in March despite new number plate as industry is rocked by 37% plunge for diesel models"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5771477/Ten-things-need-know-car-finance.html" title="Ten things you need to know about car finance: How to make sure you don't get stung if you buy a new vehicle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/article-5801451/RAY-MASSEY-puts-Jaguars-lightning-fast-Pace-SUV-paces.html" title="Jaguar's electric SUV aims to tear up the rulebook: RAY MASSEY puts the lightning fast I-Pace through its paces"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" title="How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover"></link></item><item><title>The first learner driver takes to the motorway as law change allows provisional licence holders to use Britain's fastest-moving roads from June</title><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5801619/The-learner-driver-takes-motorway-new-law-change.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 23:01:02 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">5801619</guid><description><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Finbar King, 17, has become the first learner to legally drive on a British motorway by entered the M25 during a driving lesson with an instructor on Monday at 00:01.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Finbar King, 17, has become the first learner to legally drive on a British motorway.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The teenager from St Albans entered the M25 during a driving lesson with an instructor on Monday at 00:01, which is the exact time the law changed to allow provisional licence holders to motor along the nation's fastest-moving routes.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Road Safety Minister, Jesse Norman, said the decision to allow learners onto motorways will 'help more young drivers gain skills and experience they need to drive safely' on the roads. </p><img id="i-571f8a53df8c91d8" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/03/23/4CE35D8300000578-5801619-image-a-25_1528065633940.jpg" height="476" width="634" alt="First learner on the motorway: Finbar King, 17, became the first provisional licence holder to legally take a lesson on the motorway when he entered the M25 moments after midnight on Monday 4 June" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">As of today (Monday 4 June), learners will be given access to motorways across England, Scotland and Wales as part of a law update.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The new rule - first announced in August last year - will allow provisional licence holders to enter the multi-lane roads when accompanied by an approved instructor and driving a car fitted with dual controls and L plates. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Any motorway lessons will be voluntary and only take place when an instructor believes the individual has the right skills and experience to drive in a high-speed environment.</p><div>


<div class="related-partners ">
  <div class="bdrcc">
    <h2>
      HOW THIS IS MONEY CAN HELP
    </h2>
    <ul class="link-xogr1 linkro-ccox cleared">
      <li class="full-width">
  <a href="/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" rel="nofollow">
          
          <span>How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover</span>
        </a>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </div>
</div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Finbar King, son of AA President Edmund King, hit the motorway with AA instructor Mark Harrison.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He told Mail Online that he enjoyed the lesson but was still concerned by some elements of driving on such busy roads.</p><img id="i-77ab583e4c85cc94" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/03/23/4CE35D7B00000578-5801619-image-a-26_1528065691162.jpg" height="476" width="634" alt="Finbar King (left), an A-Level student from St Albans, took the opportunity to enter the M25 under the watchful eye of instructor Mark Harrison (right) within a minute of the law allowing learners to legally have lessons on motorways" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-86a37c3e1a2a92a7" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/03/23/4CE35D6800000578-5801619-image-m-21_1528065395806.jpg" height="408" width="306" alt="The teenager drove along smart motorway sections of the M25 in the Ford Fiesta AA Driving School car fitted with dual controls" class="blkBorder img-share" /><img id="i-8ee1f10953c21016" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/04/09/4CE35D7000000578-5801619-Finbar_King_pictured_with_his_father_AA_President_Edmund_King-a-5_1528101367571.jpg" height="408" width="306" alt="Finbar King pictured with his father, AA President, Edmund King" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I actually quite enjoyed it and felt safe having Mark instructing me,' he said.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'It is different due to more lanes of traffic and indeed there were lots of lorries.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The main worry is the lack of lay-bys when there is no hard-shoulder on the ‘smart motorways’ in case you break down. I would like to see more laybys.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I also know that some left-hand drive lorries can sometimes just pull out as they have a blind spot so I try to give them more room.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">When asked if he thought the law change was a good idea, the 17-year-old A-Level student added: 'Yes, I do, as it seems silly that you could pass your test and then five minutes later drive on a motorway alone without ever having been taught to do it safely.'</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox floatRHS money" data-version="2" id="mol-2d747560-677d-11e8-9d75-df2c7322e04d">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Top 10 reasons drivers are nervous on motorways </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>1.</strong> Behaviour of other drivers (e.g. tailgating, speeding etc) </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>2.</strong> Adverse weather conditions </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>3.</strong> Large trucks and lorries </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>4.</strong> Poor road condition (e.g. potholes, road markings) </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>5.</strong> Lack of a hard shoulder on smart motorways</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>6.</strong> Possibility of breaking down </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>7. </strong>Driving at night </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>8.</strong> Joining and leaving the motorway </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>9.</strong> Travelling at high speeds </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>10.</strong> Changing lane</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-small mol-style-italic">Source: AA Populus Survey of 20,435 drivers </p></div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Despite the new rule, there are still no plans to introduce a motorway-driving segment to the driving test, which was changed last December.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Jesse Norman said the shift to allow learners onto motorways was part of a bid to improve road safety and reduce the number of road deaths involving young people.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Allowing learner drivers to have motorway lessons with a qualified road safety expert will help more young drivers to gain the skills and experience they need to drive safely on motorways,' he said.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Statistics show that newly-qualified drivers are most vulnerable in the first six months after passing their driving test and road collisions are the second biggest killer of young people in the country. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Driver and Vehicle Standards Agency (DVSA) believes this can be attributed to the number of newly-qualified motorists choosing to drive on 'challenging' rural roads with blind bends, dips and distractions because they fear entering a motorway having not used them during driving lessons.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In 2015, 80 per cent of all young driver deaths happened on rural roads, stats show. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to new research by the AA, eight per cent of drivers surveyed said they avoided motorways for at least six months after passing their test.</p><div class="mol-article-quote nochannel floatRHS" id="mol-b2de22d0-677f-11e8-9d75-df2c7322e04d">                            <div class="mol-article-quote-wrapper ccox">Allowing learner drivers to have motorway lessons with a qualified road safety expert will help more young drivers to gain the skills and experience they need to drive safely on motorways </div>                        <div class="mol-article-quote-attribution"><div>Jesse Norman, Road Safety Minister</div></div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Just 25 per cent of the 20,435 motorists who answered the poll said they felt adequately prepared for motorway driving after their test.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But more than a quarter (27 per cent) said they felt scared when they did venture onto a motorway for the first time with women (46 per cent) more than twice as likely as men (18 per cent) to say this.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The changes to allow learners to practise on motorways have been supported by the AA Charitable Trust.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It has set aside £20,000 to fund 'Drive Motorway' courses aimed at newly-qualified motorists who missed out on the opportunity to drive on the nation's fast roads before sitting their test.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The courses will be given by AA Driving School instructors and last two hours.</p><img id="i-4087f691a3d2a30b" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/03/23/4CE360DE00000578-5801619-image-a-27_1528065876079.jpg" height="431" width="634" alt="Statistics show that many newly qualified drivers haven't felt comfortable entering motorways for the first time after passing their test having had no previous experience of using the fast-paced roads" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Edmund King, director of the trust, said: 'We welcome these changes to allow learner drivers onto motorways under the guidance of a fully-qualified driving instructor.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Collision statistics confirm that young drivers are drastically over-represented in crashes so this change, which will help broaden the opportunities they have while learning, is very positive.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'It’s clear from our research that motorway driving has been a significant hurdle for many drivers to overcome after their test and that being allowed on these roads whilst learning is welcomed by the majority of drivers.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'However, there will be many qualified drivers out there at the moment who have perhaps recently passed their test and have just missed out on this opportunity. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'This is why the AA Trust has set aside significant levels of funding for free motorway training and we would encourage any newly-qualified driver to take up the training. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'It is ironic that so many drivers avoid motorways after passing their test when, statistically, they are our safest roads.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He added that the changes present a 'great opportunity' to educate the next generation of drivers about avoiding poor habits, such as middle-lane hogging, tailgating and undertaking.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">All three are classed as 'careless driving', which can result in guilty motorists being issued with  a fixed penalty notice of at least three points  and a fine of £100 - though <a style="font-weight: bold;" class="class" href="/money/cars/article-5647269/Careless-driving-UK-roads-going-unpunished.html">recent stats have suggested that this is going widely unpunished</a>. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">To apply for a free AA Drive Motorway course, available from June 7,  drivers need to visit the <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="http://www.facebook.com/AADrivingSchool" rel="nofollow">AA Driving School Facebook page</a> and click 'send message'. </p><img id="i-259092375debfbeb" src="http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/06/04/09/4CE3604200000578-5801619-The_AA_Charitable_Trust_has_set_aside_20_000_to_fund_Drive_Motor-a-4_1528101367494.jpg" height="420" width="306" alt="The AA Charitable Trust has set aside £20,000 to fund Drive Motorway courses for new drivers who passed their test recently" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">You will need to include your name, contact details, postcode, year you passed test, preferred time/date of lesson and vehicle transmission type (manual/ automatic). </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Speaking ahead of the law change, DVSA Chief Driving Examiner, Mark Winn, said: 'DVSA's priority is to help you through a lifetime of safe driving.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Allowing learner drivers to have motorway lessons was supported by 80 per cent of people who gave their feedback on this change, with the public recognising the importance of developing these skills in a controlled environment.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I’m delighted that a new generation of drivers can now drive on the motorway to gain valuable experience, including overtaking safely and lane discipline.'</p><div class="moduleFull"></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>EXCLUSIVE: Finbar King, 17, has become the first learner to legally drive on a British motorway by entered the M25 during a driving lesson with an instructor on Monday at 00:01, which is the exact time the law changed to allow provisional licence holders to motor along the nation's fastest-moving routes.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Rob Hull</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-06-05T09:09:13.000+01:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>EXCLUSIVE: The first learner driver takes to the motorway</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-06-05T09:09:13.000+01:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url=""><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5771477/Ten-things-need-know-car-finance.html" title="Ten things you need to know about car finance: How to make sure you don't get stung if you buy a new vehicle"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/experts/article-5703473/Is-legal-use-smartphone-sat-nav-car-passenger-seat-cup-holder.html" title="Can you use your smartphone sat-nav on the car passenger seat or in the cup holder - and does it have to be hands-free?"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5772201/Some-pothole-repair-bills-cost-nearly-twice-average-national-monthly-wage.html" title="How a pothole could cost you nearly two month's wages: Damage to cars results in some repairs costing £3,800"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5754073/Four-gadgets-need-protect-car-theft-scams.html" title="The four gadgets you need to protect your car: Motorists flock to buy them to guard against a new wave of thefts and scams"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762697/Some-85-500-electric-car-chargers-needed-2-years-demand.html" title="The UK's electric car charging grid is 'playing catch-up', as study reveals 85,500 chargers are needed in the next two years to meet demand"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5762489/VW-owners-26-October-claim-dieselgate-compensation.html" title="Owners of VW cars in the UK caught up in dieselgate scandal have until October 26 to claim for compensation"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-5761621/GoldenEye-Aston-Martin-DB5-film-car-hammer-1-6m.html" title="James Bond Aston Martin DB5 driven by Pierce Brosnan in GoldenEye to go under the hammer for £1.6MILLION"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/money/cars/article-1640018/How-cheapest-car-insurance-Ten-tips-cheaper-car-cover.html" title="How to get the cheapest car insurance: Ten tips for cheaper car cover"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="http://www.facebook.com/AADrivingSchool" title="AA Driving School Facebook page"></link></item></channel></rss>