
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily Mail picture slideshow</title><language>en-GB</language><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/feeds/msn-article-body/slideshow.rss</link><description>Images slideshow</description><item><guid isPermaLink="false">10204683</guid><title>MAKEUPS AND BREAKUPS: Paris ties the knot, Cooper and Shayk reconcile?</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/galleries/article-10204683/MAKEUPS-BREAKUPS-Paris-ties-knot-Taylor-Swift-takes-thinly-veiled-jab-Gyllenhaal.html</link><pubDate>2021-11-16T15:00:46+0000 GMT</pubDate><description><![CDATA[When it comes to matters of the heart, celebrities really are just like us, as this week's installment of makeups and breakups proves.]]></description><dcterms:modified>2021-11-16T15:00:46.000Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:valid>start=2021-11-16T15:00:46+0000; end=2022-11-16T15:00:46+0000; scheme=W3C-DTF</dcterms:valid><media:keywords>MAKEUPS,BREAKUPS,Paris,ties,knot,Taylor,Swift,takes,thinly,veiled,jab,Gyllenhaal,Galleries</media:keywords><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50522123-10204683-When_it_comes_to_matters_of_the_heart_celebrities_really_are_jus-a-46_1637009067954.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>When it comes to matters of the heart, celebrities really are just like us, as this week's installment of makeups and breakups proves. This week, Paris Hilton finally tied the knot and hosted several star-studded  wedding events, while Adele reveled in her new relationship and opened up about her new beau. Elsewhere, Taylor Swift proved success is the best revenge, after her re-recorded album topped the charts and got fans talking about an ex who broke her heart. In other news, Kate Bosworth sparked new relationship rumors after posting a series of flirty pictures of fellow actor Justin Long.  Here's what you need to know.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50496079-10204683-PARIS_IN_LOVE_Paris_Hilton_is_married_now_and_it_seems_she_could-a-49_1637009067968.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Paris Hilton / Instagram</media:credit><media:title>Image title</media:title><media:text>Image1 alt-text</media:text><media:description>PARIS IN LOVE: &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10202747/Paris-Hilton-reflects-wedding-Carter-Reum-proud-stand-wife.html"&gt;Paris Hilton is married now,&lt;/a&gt; and it seems she couldn't be more excited about it. The reality television star, 40, married her new husband Carter Reum, 40, in a ceremony last Thursday at the Bel-Air estate of her late grandfather Barron Hilton. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50496075-10204683-After_a_weekend_chock_full_of_wedding_events_the_socialite_share-a-48_1637009067966.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Paris Hilton / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>After a weekend chock-full of wedding events, the socialite shared several photos of the wild few days along with a caption that stated, outright, how excited she truly is. 'Standing hand in hand at the altar, my heart skipped a beat,' the Cooking With Paris star wrote. 'It was one of the most incredibly magic and loving feelings I’ve ever felt in my life. I had found my missing piece.' </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50516475-10204683-She_continued_To_me_you_re_more_than_my_husband_You_re_my_best_f-a-51_1637009067978.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Chelsea Lauren/REX</media:credit><media:description>She continued: 'To me, you’re more than my husband. You’re my best friend, my teacher, my lover, my confidant, and the father of our future children. I am so proud to stand beside you as your wife.' Pictured: The star poses with her family from left to right, Barron Hilton, Tessa Hilton, Kathy Hilton, Paris Hilton, Carter Reum and Nicky Hilton Rothschild.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50516607-10204683-Reum_and_Hilton_celebrated_their_nuptials_in_style_with_several_-a-50_1637009067977.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Christopher Polk / Shutterstock</media:credit><media:description>Reum and Hilton celebrated their nuptials in style with several events including a star-studded celebration on Saturday night which saw the couple party with a number of famous faces. Singer-songwriter Macy Gray performed for all of those in attendance which included actress Emma Roberts, actor Jaden Smith, reality star Kyle Richards and many other celebs. Pictured: Paris with her longtime friend Nicole Richie. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50428425-10204683-Perhaps_the_biggest_event_of_the_couple_s_weekend_after_their_ac-a-64_1637009068184.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Rachpoot / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>Perhaps the biggest event of the couple's weekend, aside from their actual wedding  of course, came as the duo took over the Santa Monica Pier for a night of rides, games and a performance by the disc jockey Diplo. The pier was completely closed off to the public with barricades posted up at its entrance for the star's big night. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50491669-10204683-HOW_PAUL_GOT_THE_GIRL_In_other_loved_up_celebrity_news_Adele_spi-a-66_1637009068252.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>HOW PAUL GOT THE GIRL: In other loved-up celebrity news, &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10202171/Adele-gushes-new-boyfriend-Rich-Paul-reveals-met-birthday-party.html"&gt;Adele spilled the beans on her relationship with sports agent Rich Paul &lt;/a&gt;during her CBS special Adele One Night Only on Sunday. The two-hour special featured footage from a concert she gave at Griffith Observatory in Los Angeles – in front of a star-studded audience – and footage from Oprah Winfrey's wide-ranging interview with the 33-year-old singer.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50490359-10204683-Speaking_to_Oprah_the_hitmaker_revealed_how_her_hilarious_new_bo-a-67_1637009068270.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>CBS</media:credit><media:description>Speaking to Oprah, the hitmaker revealed how her 'hilarious' new boyfriend got her to go on a date and noted that their relationship is the first time she has 'loved herself'. According to Adele, she and Paul met at a birthday party, but the sports agent played it cool and didn't immediately ask the songstress out on a date. Several years later, he called the singer up to ask her for a 'business meeting'. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50490731-10204683-Adele_recounted_I_m_like_a_business_meeting_about_what_We_wouldn-a-68_1637009068272.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>CBS</media:credit><media:description>Adele recounted, 'I'm like, a business meeting about what? We wouldn't be having a meeting about business. And then it was just the first time we'd hung out only on our own, and not with other friends and stuff like that. So that was a very natural way. I think that's how people would normally meet each other, like, in real life.' She added it's 'quite incredible watching him do what he does. And just the easiness of it,' and he's making the relationship, 'easy' for her.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50485051-10204683-Now_that_she_s_in_a_happy_with_her_life_Oprah_asked_if_she_think-a-52_1637009067980.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>CBS via Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Now that she's in a happy place in her life, Oprah asked if she thinks she'll still be able to write new music. 'Well, I hope so. I hope so, you know,' she said, as Oprah asked about the final track of her album, Love Is a Game, when she asked if she was getting better at the game of love. 'I don't treat it like a game anymore. You know, that thing of like, you're gonna hurt me so I'm gonna hurt you first. I certainly, I'm not like that anymore,' she said. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50519577-10204683-THE_BEST_REVENGE_IS_SUCCESS_Taylor_Swift_sent_the_internet_into_-a-44_1637009067953.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>NBC</media:credit><media:description>THE BEST REVENGE IS SUCCESS? Taylor Swift sent the internet into a frenzy last Friday when she re-released her Red album with a 10-minute version of All Too Well. Fans have long suspected the song – and much of the 2012 album – was about &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10199661/Taylor-Swift-sparks-comparisons-Princess-Dianas-legendary-little-black-revenge-dress.html"&gt;Swift's relationship with Jake Gyllenhaal&lt;/a&gt;, and this new extended recording (and music video with a look-a-like Jake actor) includes more lyrics that seem to confirm this — and paint Gyllenhaal in a less-than-favorable light.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50509883-10204683-Fans_immediately_took_to_Twitter_to_taunt_Gyllenhaal_mocking_him-a-53_1637009067984.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>NBC</media:credit><media:description>Fans immediately took to Twitter to taunt Gyllenhaal, mocking him for the unflattering portrayal and honing in on the especially damaging lyrics – including that they reportedly broke up because Gyllenhaal thought Swift was too young.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50409905-10204683-Meanwhile_the_re_recorded_album_was_an_instant_hit_with_critics_-a-54_1637009068048.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>The re-recorded album was an instant hit with critics and has earned an impressive 96 percent on Metacritic, indicating 'universal acclaim,' with several outlets praising the expansive new material almost as much as the original songs.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50452971-10204683-Reveling_in_her_latest_success_Taylor_who_has_previously_said_sh-a-55_1637009068052.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>Reveling in her latest success, Taylor – who has previously said she loves leaving Easter eggs and clues for her fans – appeared to channel the late Princess Diana's iconic 'revenge dress' on Thursday evening. During her appearance on Late Night with Seth Meyers, the State Of Grace singer, 31, instantly drew comparisons to the beloved royal while rocking an off-the-shoulder minidress with a notch neckline and crystal embroidery.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50453263-10204683-The_revenge_dress_is_one_of_Diana_s_most_talked_about_looks_of_a-a-70_1637009068285.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Late Night with Seth Meyers/Instagram</media:credit><media:description>The 'revenge dress' is one of Diana's most talked about looks of all time, which she wore shortly after her ex Prince Charles admitted to cheating on her in an interview with Jonathan Dimbleby two years after they separated. While Swifties were convinced the pop star was sending a message to ex Jake Gyllenhaal, Swift mostly debunked the fan theory claiming that she just 'liked the dress'. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50443199-10204683-TAY_SAYS_YES_Elsewhere_another_one_of_Taylor_Swift_s_exes_had_a_-a-56_1637009068060.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>TAY SAYS YES: Elsewhere, another one of Taylor Swift's exes had a much better weekend. Taylor Lautner, who dated the singer in 2009 and 2010, &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10198601/Taylor-Lautner-engaged-Twilight-actor-drops-one-knee-proposes-longtime-love-Tay-Dome.html"&gt;dropped down to one knee &lt;/a&gt;and asked longtime love Tay Dome to be his wife during a romantic proposal.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50442313-10204683-The_29_year_old_actor_looked_dapper_in_a_suit_and_tie_while_his_-a-57_1637009068062.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Taylor Lautner / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>The 29-year-old actor looked dapper in a suit and tie while his bride-to-be went barefoot for the amorous display shared to Instagram on Saturday morning from the surprise engagement just days before. '11.11.2021. And just like that, all of my wishes came true,' Taylor captioned the post shared to his nearly seven million followers. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50519987-10204683-Tay_looked_completely_in_shock_as_she_held_her_hands_to_her_face-a-45_1637009067954.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Taylor Lautner / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>Tay looked completely in shock as she held her hands to her face while standing in a candlelit room surrounded by gorgeous red roses. A neon red Lautner sign illuminated the couple from behind as Taylor held open a ring box for his new wife, who is a registered nurse in the state of California.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50519977-10204683-Tay_shared_in_her_excitement_with_her_followers_as_she_professed-a-58_1637009068086.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Tay Dome / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>Tay shared in her excitement with her followers as she professed her love for her new fiance. 'My absolute best friend,' she captioned the gorgeous photo from their special night. 'I CANNOT WAIT TO SPEND FOREVER WITH YOU.' Lautner quickly fired back: 'Got news for you, the feeling is mutual.'</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50372385-10204683-SPEEDING_THINGS_UP_Comedian_John_Mulaney_hired_a_new_legal_team_-a-69_1637009068282.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit></media:credit><media:description>SPEEDING THINGS UP: Comedian&lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10192701/John-Mulaney-hires-new-lawyers-speed-divorce-estranged-wife-Anna-Marie-Tendler.html"&gt; John Mulaney has hired a new legal team in efforts to 'speed up' his divorce&lt;/a&gt; from estranged wife Anna Marie Tendler while he awaits the birth of his first child with new girlfriend Olivia Munn.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50372111-10204683-Sources_told_Page_Six_that_Mulaney_is_now_being_represented_by_T-a-59_1637009068087.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>NBC</media:credit><media:description>Sources told Page Six that Mulaney is now being represented by Teitler &amp;amp; Teitler, the firm who previously represented Matt Lauer's ex-wife Annette Roque in addition to a number of powerful Goldman Sachs execs and big-money battles. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50520177-10204683-_John_wants_to_speed_things_up_and_get_the_divorce_done_one_sour-a-61_1637009068171.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>JosiahW / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>'John wants to speed things up and get the divorce done,' one source said. 'He's becoming a father, so he switched to a new law firm with a reputation of being tough and efficient.'</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50372099-10204683-Mulaney_filed_for_divorce_from_Anna_his_wife_of_six_years_in_May-a-60_1637009068153.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Mulaney filed for divorce from Anna, his wife of six years, in May, following a 60-day treatment program last year for cocaine and alcohol abuse, and was in outpatient services in February. In the midst of their divorce, Mulaney began dating Munn after meeting in Los Angeles in the spring, and later confirmed she was pregnant while appearing on Late Night with Seth Meyers.  </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50522829-10204683-Anna_Marie_spoke_out_about_her_split_from_the_comedian_earlier_t-a-47_1637009067956.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Getty Images for The Other Art F</media:credit><media:description>Anna Marie spoke out about her split from the comedian earlier this year: 'I am heartbroken that John has decided to end our marriage. I wish him support and success as he continues his recovery.' Tendler also reportedly entered rehab for 'emotional and eating' disorders around the same time as her estranged ex. She is reportedly doing much better since she received treatment. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/16/13/50529795-10204683-MENDING_FENCES_Meanwhile_in_NYC_Bradley_Cooper_and_Irina_Shayk_s-a-1_1637069599861.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>BrosNYC / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>MENDING FENCES? Meanwhile in NYC, &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10206089/Bradley-Cooper-Irina-Shayk-look-cosy-strolling-arm-arm-fling-Kanye-West.html"&gt;Bradley Cooper and Irina Shayk sparked reconciliation rumors&lt;/a&gt; after looking very cozy on a stroll through Manhattan on Sunday. The exes, who share a four-year-old daughter named Lea, couldn't contain their smiles as they walked arm-in-arm on their way back to his place two years on from announcing their shock split after four years as a couple. Their outing comes after the supermodel was most recently romantically linked to Kanye West earlier this year after they enjoyed a romantic trip to Paris. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/16/09/50529823-10206089-Looking_cozy_The_exes_who_share_a_four_year_old_daughter_named_L-a-23_1637053341863.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>BrosNYC / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>As they battled the wind on the chilly afternoon, the star, 46, wore a navy coat over a plain t-shirt, dark-wash jeans and olive sneakers with red laces. While walking across a street, the Silver Linings Playbook actor appeared smitten as the supermodel, 35, sweetly held onto his arm. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/16/13/50531077-10204683-For_their_outing_Shayk_rocked_a_cosy_long_black_jacket_over_a_wh-a-2_1637069599879.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>BrosNYC / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>For their outing, Shayk rocked a cozy long black jacket over a white button-down and black trousers while her hair was in a sleek style. She accessorized with a  face mask, chunky white sneakers and a black leather handbag with a gold chain. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/16/13/24764028-10204683-The_former_pair_have_always_stayed_mum_on_their_relationship_and-a-3_1637069599880.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Getty Images for National Board</media:credit><media:description>The former pair have always stayed mum on their relationship, and Irina explained in a March interview: 'My past relationship, it’s something that belongs to me, and it’s private.' She added, 'It’s just a piece of my inner self that I don’t want to give away. I don’t read what is out there. Honestly, I’m too busy raising a child.' </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/16/13/50531075-10204683-She_called_the_performer_the_most_amazing_dad_in_the_interview_a-a-4_1637069599882.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>BrosNYC / BACKGRID</media:credit><media:description>She called the performer 'the most amazing dad' in the interview and explained that Lea – who was born in March of 2017 – doesn’t see Irina as a supermodel, just as mom. 'I have this huge picture that Peter Lindbergh gave me on my wall. She’ll always joke, "I want this mama, I don’t want this mama," pointing at the picture, and we laugh about it,' she said.</media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50512573-10204683-NEW_COUPLE_ALERT_Kate_Bosworth_has_sparked_dating_rumors_with_fe-a-71_1637009068288.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Kate Bosworth / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>NEW COUPLE ALERT? Kate Bosworth has &lt;a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-10204365/Kate-Bosworth-sparks-Justin-Long-dating-rumors-three-months-split-husband-Michael-Polish.html"&gt;sparked dating rumors with fellow actor Justin Long&lt;/a&gt; three months after announcing her split with husband Michael Polish. The 38-year-old Blue Crush actress and Long, 43, filmed a movie in Fayetteville, Arkansas back in May. At the time, a local paper had reported that the two had been spending plenty of time together in the city as Bosworth was still married to 51-year-old film producer Polish. </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50512041-10204683-Then_just_days_ago_celebrity_gossip_Instagram_account_Deuxmoi_sp-a-62_1637009068173.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>deuxmoi / Instagram</media:credit><media:description>Then just days ago, celebrity gossip Instagram account Deuxmoi sparked dating rumors between the talented actors once again as they asked followers 'What celeb secrets can you spill?' and received plenty of responses including one follower who wrote 'Justin Long and Kate Bosworth are dating.' </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50512567-10204683-Things_got_really_interesting_as_Deuxmoi_reposted_another_inside-a-63_1637009068182.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Kate Bosworth/Instagram</media:credit><media:description>Things got really interesting as Deuxmoi reposted another insider account who reiterated those claims as one person wrote: 'Oh I know this is fact! Justtttt after they finished their movie in the Ozarks they came into a deli in Fairfield CT together and were cuddly. This was before she announced her split with her husband. I think end of May?' </media:description></media:content><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2021/11/15/20/50512569-10204683-Bosworth_did_not_confirm_the_end_of_her_marriage_until_months_la-a-65_1637009068190.jpg" type="image/jpeg" hasSyndicationRights="true" medium="image"><media:credit>Kate Bosworth/Instagram</media:credit><media:description>Bosworth did not confirm the end of her marriage until months later in August but did post a rather flirty Instagram post featuring Justin back in May. She shared a gallery of images of them enjoying their time in Fayetteville together with a caption which read: 'There are some movie experiences when you learn a lotttttt about another person. Well, we just wrapped one of those – all night shoots, working 6 day weeks. The exhaustion &amp;amp; insanity was off the grid. Holy moly @justinlong you are a truly spectacular / fun / funny / kind / rare / thoughtful / totally... rad human being?' </media:description></media:content></item></channel></rss>
