<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily Mail debate</title><language>en-GB</language><link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/feeds/msn/articles/debate.rss</link><item><title>Black dog: Boris taste test for joker May</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6147379/Black-dog-Boris-taste-test-joker-May.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 01:13:40 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6147379</guid><description><![CDATA[Theresa May’s speech writers are sweating on the issue du jour: how to deliver her traditional gag about Boris Johnson in her party conference speech.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class"><a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/theresa_may/index.html" id="mol-95d7b710-b3cd-11e8-903f-b3c8a97b2198">Theresa May</a>’s speech writers are sweating on the issue du jour: how to deliver her traditional gag about <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/boris_johnson/index.html" id="mol-95d2ae00-b3cd-11e8-903f-b3c8a97b2198">Boris Johnson</a> in her party conference speech. Said one May ally: ‘There’s plenty to go on. It’s just finding something that’s, er, tasteful and Prime Ministerial.’  </span></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class"><strong>Hope springs eternal in the PM’s right-hand man. Gavin Barwell, her chief of staff, is trying to raise No 10 spirits by promising a Christmas ‘celebration’ if his boss pulls off a <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/brexit/index.html" id="mol-95d82c40-b3cd-11e8-903f-b3c8a97b2198">Brexit</a> deal by then. ‘Or presumably a collective leaving do if she hasn’t and Typhoon Bojo blows in instead,’ sighed one world-weary staffer. </strong></span></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class"><span class="class">Not for the first time, Frank Field has shown <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/jeremy_corbyn/index.html" id="mol-95d59430-b3cd-11e8-903f-b3c8a97b2198">Jeremy Corbyn</a> how to behave. When veteran MP Field, who quit Labour over the leader’s failings on anti-Semitism, visited Salisbury after the Novichok poisoning, he met local Tory MP John Glen and posed for snaps with locals. Corbyn seems to have slipped in and out of the town with all the stealth of a Russian spy. Someone should check the CCTV.</span></span></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class"><strong><span class="mol-style-large"> Ruth at the ready for Corbyn heavies</span></strong></span></p><img id="i-71f4ca062d594fff" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/09/02/4FE6D2BB00000578-6147379-image-a-118_1536455434710.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Jewish Labour MP Ruth Smeeth received ¿close protection¿ training before entering Parliament" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class"><strong>Jeremy Corbyn’s militant ‘heavies’ should think twice before targeting Ruth Smeeth. Dog hears the Jewish Labour MP who has been at the centre of the party’s raging anti-Semitism row, received ‘close protection’ training before entering Parliament in 2015 – allowing her to deftly disarm attackers a la James Bond.</strong></span></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Tory bosses may struggle to stop Brexit ‘bad boy’ Arron Banks joining the party. Unlike Labour, the Tories let people join any constituency association in the country – not just where they live. And they can also be members of more than one association. ‘I joined both in my constituency and where I live,’ said one ex-Minister. ‘I even got two votes in the last party leadership election. Only voted once, though.’ Such principle.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"> <strong>Judging from their joint grilling by MPs, Brexit Secretary Dominic Raab is now a human shield for Olly Robbins, chief Civil Service Brexit adviser to the PM. ‘Every time we tried to bowl a bouncer at Robbins, up popped Raab to fend it off,’ fumed one Brexiteer Tory. ‘Robbins is obviously so important to the PM that if someone has to take a bullet, it’s poor old Dom.’</strong></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><span class="class">Not all MPs are boasting tans from sunny summer holidays. Deputy Speaker Lindsay Hoyle’s souvenir is an alarming skinhead haircut – the result of a ‘lost in translation’ mishap. ‘My French wasn’t up to it,’ lamented Lancastrian Lindsay. ‘I thought I asked for short back ’n’ sides. The barber obviously heard shave it all off.’</span></p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong> Three years after being exposed by the MoS for his role in the Tatler Tory bullying scandal, Mark Clarke has crawled back on to social media. His first Facebook post? A picture of him posing next to Boris Johnson. With friends like that, Bojo…</strong></p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Theresa May’s speech writers are sweating on the issue du jour: how to deliver her traditional gag about Boris Johnson in her party conference speech. Said one May ally: ‘There’s plenty to go on. It’s just finding something that’s, er, tasteful and Prime Ministerial.’</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Mail on Sunday Reporter</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-09-09T10:17:28.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Black dog: Boris taste test for joker May</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-09T10:17:28.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/09/02/4FE6D2BB00000578-6147379-image-a-118_1536455434710.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Jewish Labour MP Ruth Smeeth&amp;nbsp;received ¿close protection¿ training before entering Parliament</media:title><media:text>35892588_Labour MP Ruth Smeeth. Photo by Barrington Coombs_mariela.ganeva.jpg</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content></item><item><title>TOM UTLEY: If my memory was so wonky in summer, heaven knows what I'll be like when the temperature drops</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6141437/TOM-UTLEY-memory-wonky-summer.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 01:06:23 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6141437</guid><description><![CDATA[One consolation of growing older and more forgetful (as I may have mentioned) is that I can re-read books with absolutely no memory of having read them before, writes TOM UTLEY.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">One consolation of growing older and more forgetful (as I may have mentioned in the past!) is that I can re-read books with absolutely no memory of having read them before.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Every page is as fresh as the first time, every twist of the plot as unexpected — and I find I can work my way through to the end, baffled and eager to discover whodunit.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But on our summer holiday this year, I plumbed new depths of forgetfulness that have left me seriously worried about the state of my marbles.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ever since my childhood I’d been wanting to visit Quimper, the historic capital of Cornouaille in the south-west corner of Brittany. This was because my late aunt, Deirdre, used to go there summer after summer, returning in raptures over its medieval delights.</p><img id="i-4bb27b86acf8ebb6" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/07/01/33531BE700000578-0-image-a-34_1536281423327.jpg" height="353" width="634" alt="Ever since my childhood I¿d been wanting to visit Quimper, the historic capital of Cornouaille in the south-west corner of Brittany (chateau in Quimper pictured)" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">I remember fondly how every year she would come back with gifts of the local pottery for her nephews and nieces — those colourful cups and bowls for which the region is famous, decorated with Breton characters and emblazoned with our names.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-bold">Familiar</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Anyway, this summer my wife and I decided we should finally get around to paying a visit. So we booked a gite in nearby Fouesnant and the two of us set off on the car ferry from Portsmouth to Saint-Malo, with the wonderfully traffic-free roads of Brittany opening up before us for the three-hour drive.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The following morning, after we’d settled in, I drove the short distance to Quimper, full of curiosity as to whether it would live up to the high expectations raised by my aunt.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was just after we’d found a space in the car park by the river that my wife said: ‘Are you sure we haven’t been here before?’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I told her not to be silly. True, there was something a little familiar about the place. But as I mansplained to her, many old French cities are laid out on the same pattern, with the cathedral and its surrounding half-timbered buildings close to the river and modern shops and offices spreading out from there.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As we walked towards the centre, however, I had to admit that Quimper did remind me quite strongly of somewhere we’d been before. I just couldn’t quite put my finger on where.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Maybe it was Dinan or Vannes — Brittany towns where we’d stayed in the early years after our wedding in 1980?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Or was it Ploudalmezeau, also in Finistère, near where we’d rented a gite not so long ago? No, they were all very different. So perhaps it was somewhere else, not even in France?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We found a nice-looking cafe by the cathedral — a bit of a tourist trap, to be sure, but that’s never really bothered me — and as we waited for our moules marinieres, I scanned a mental map of Europe to try to identify the city of which Quimper reminded me.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">No good. I could think of nowhere in Italy, Spain, Portugal, Hungary or Greece — locations of past holidays — that came even close to fitting the bill.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Then, as I racked my brains for the answer, a mini-funfair sprang to life in the large paved area between the cafe and the church.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Oh, Lord, that was familiar, too.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Suddenly, everything came back to me. As so irritatingly often, Mrs U was right.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We had been here before! In that moment, I knew that if we walked down the alley a few yards to the right from where we were sitting, we would find the restaurant where we’d had a superb dinner during our previous visit.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It dawned on me, too, that if we entered the cathedral in front of us, we’d see the east end by the altar set at an angle to the nave, in a way unlike any other church I’d seen.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Furthermore, I knew exactly where I’d find the shop, down by the river, in which we had bought T-shirts for our boys, and the jeweller where I’d had a new battery fitted in my watch.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-bold">Horror</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Worst of all, I remembered that the last time we were here, we had sat at this very same table, in this very same cafe, eating the very same dish for our lunch.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This was deja vu in the most literal meaning of the words.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On that last occasion, we decided that a single day and night were probably enough to see everything Quimper had to offer, and we headed off to the seaside in the north the following day.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">To discover when we were last there, I looked at my iPhone’s photo album. To my horror, there I found a picture I’d taken of the cathedral, with the caption: ‘Quimper, July 2016.’ Only two years ago! How could I have forgotten so soon?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">You will well understand, therefore, why I was more than a little interested in this week’s report by researchers at the University of Toronto, who believe they may have found the most promising way yet of detecting the early onset of Alzheimer’s, raising hopes of more effective treatment.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Based on a study of more than 3,000 elderly people in the U.S., France and Canada, the study finds that indications of this devastating condition tend to be more evident in the coldest winter months, while brains appear 4.8 years younger in the summer.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The best time to screen patients for dementia, therefore, is at the very end or beginning of the year.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">All I can say is that if my memory was so unreliable in late August — and the weather in Brittany was deliciously warm while we were there — heaven knows what it will be like when the temperature starts to drop.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But though Mrs U earned the right to say ‘I told you so’ in Quimper, I have to report (at the risk of instant divorce) that she, too, is capable of moments of forgetfulness. Take last Friday evening, when we were back at home in London.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Weeks earlier, as part of her duties as a secretary, she had booked a table for her boss at a small fish restaurant, where he was to host a dinner for his fellow senior executives in honour of a long-serving staff member who was leaving.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She happened to mention to me that the menu looked jolly appetising — and I decided that, as end-of-holiday treat, I would take her there to try the place out for ourselves.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font mol-style-bold">Hiding</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Though it was fully booked for lunch, she made a reservation for the one remaining table available that evening.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">When we walked into the restaurant, it was her turn to look horrified. For there at the back were her boss and his senior executives. She had clean forgotten that this was the very evening she had booked for the leaving party.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">What would her employer think of us? My poor wife was all for bowling up to him and explaining everything.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But I had a terrible fear that he might think we were creepy stalkers, trying to gatecrash his party.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Worse, with his great kindness of heart, he might have felt obliged to ask us to join him.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In the end, we decided that cowardice was the best policy, and we spent the duration of our meal hiding our faces if ever it looked as though one of the party might spot us. I have seldom endured a more embarrassing hour and a half.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Back at work since Monday, she tells me she seems to have survived the ordeal unnoticed, with her secret intact.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Not now it isn’t, with her blabbermouth husband spilling the beans in the national Press.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">So it is that Mrs U and I (assuming she doesn’t dump me the moment she opens this paper) seem destined to spend our declining years stumbling together from one senior moment to the next. Bring on that cure for senility!</p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>One consolation of growing older and more forgetful (as I may have mentioned in the past!) is that I can re-read books with absolutely no memory of having read them before. Every page is as fresh as the first time, every twist of the plot as unexpected — and I find I can work my way through to the end, baffled and eager to discover whodunit. But on our summer holiday this year, I plumbed new depths of forgetfulness that have left me seriously worried about the state of my marbles.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Tom Utley for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-09-07T08:15:13.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>TOM UTLEY: My memory was wonky in summer</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-07T08:15:13.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/07/01/33531BE700000578-0-image-a-34_1536281423327.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Ever since my childhood I¿d been wanting to visit Quimper, the historic capital of Cornouaille in the south-west corner of Brittany (chateau in Quimper pictured)</media:title><media:text>A general view of Chateau de Kistinic in Quimper, France.

This castle is set in 38 acres of park in the boundaries of the medieval city of Quimper in Brittany. Schools, shops and restaurants are very close and you?re just 20 minutes from a huge choice of beautiful beaches.

Visit www.frenchberry.com.


holiday-cottages-brittany-kistinic-parc-3.jpg</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content></item><item><title>So the trains are going to be late! How very British: ALEX BRUMMER says Crossrail is yet another sorry saga of spiralling costs and tedious hold-ups </title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6120661/ALEX-BRUMMER-says-Crossrail-sorry-saga-spiralling-costs-tedious-hold-ups.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:35:35 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6120661</guid><description><![CDATA[The capital commuters and businesses have endured a decade of disruption with great stoicism. The endless drilling and cancelled trains have been accepted as a price worth paying.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">The hype surrounding the £15billion Crossrail project has been extraordinary. Breathlessly described as Europe’s biggest infrastructure project and the most complex piece of engineering ever attempted, it has been presented as a resounding demonstration that we are still every bit as good at public works as our Victorian forebears.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In response, across the capital, residents, commuters and businesses have endured a decade of disruption with great stoicism. The endless drilling, cracked walls and cancelled trains have – remarkably – been accepted as a price worth paying.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">With its wide, safe platforms, architect-designed stations and – foremost in people’s minds after our sizzling summer – air-conditioned carriages, the December 9 opening of Crossrail, or the Elizabeth Line as it will be known, has long been in the diary as the day the capital gets a new train line it can really be proud of.</p><img id="i-428f9fd6ea8bf499" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/01/01/4F8E539600000578-0-image-a-33_1535762027272.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="With its wide, safe platforms, architect-designed stations and – foremost in people’s minds after our sizzling summer – air-conditioned carriages, the December 9 opening of Crossrail, or the Elizabeth Line as it will be known, has long been in the diary as the day the capital gets a new train line it can really be proud of" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">But as the grand opening approaches, now we learn that this magnificent British infrastructure project is not just going to be over budget, it’s also going to be late.</p><div class="item">
    

</div>
<p class="mol-para-with-font">Instead of a triumph harking back to the days of Isambard Kingdom Brunel, it has turned into the same sorry saga of spiralling costs and tedious hold-ups as Heathrow’s Terminal Five, the launch of the new Thameslink trains, and the abandoned electrification of the trans-Pennine rail route from Manchester to Leeds. In Japan and in parts of America they work around the clock, on public holidays and during every waking hour to ensure that promised developments are delivered on time and with minimal chaos.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Here, we just seem to shrug our shoulders and pretend everything is fine. In the case of Crossrail the bills were rising even while we were being assured that everything was on track. The Government has already had to come up with £600million extra and Transport for London another £150million to support the project. The upshot will almost certainly be higher fares for passengers and no central section to speak of until autumn next year.</p><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Officials say that 94 per cent of the job is done. However, when the outstanding work consists of some of the most frustrating tasks – including safety checks – the optimistic tone struck by this claim is unconvincing.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Passing the final tests, in our age of health and safety, can be the hardest part of the entire project. Just ask supporters of Tottenham Hotspur, who are still watching their team play at Wembley because issues with ‘critical safety systems’ prevented the new White Hart Lane stadium opening in time for the start of the football season.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This paper has long been sceptical about the £56billion HS2 project providing high- speed rail travel between London, Birmingham and eventually Manchester.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But it has always been my personal view that, like the Victorians, we ought to bite the bullet and leave something memorable and economically beneficial for generations to come. Tinkering with commuter lines and building better roundabouts, despite the importance of secondary projects, just don’t make the same statement as a major new development.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">With the Elizabeth Line estimated to boost the capital’s rail capacity by 10 per cent, the potential benefits of taking an ambitious approach are clear.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sadly, when we look at the real Crossrail, as opposed to the dazzling fictional vision we have been sold, it’s impossible not to wonder whether Britain plc will ever be capable of delivering something so complex and expensive.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>The hype surrounding the £15billion Crossrail project has been extraordinary. Breathlessly described as Europe’s biggest infrastructure project and the most complex piece of engineering ever attempted, it has been presented as a resounding demonstration that we are still every bit as good at public works as our Victorian forebears. In response, across the capital, residents, commuters and businesses have endured a decade of disruption with great stoicism. The endless drilling, cracked walls and cancelled trains have – remarkably – been accepted as a price worth paying.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Alex Brummer for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-09-01T10:16:28.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Crossrail is yet another saga of spiralling costs and tedious hold-ups</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-01T10:16:28.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/01/01/4F8E539600000578-0-image-a-33_1535762027272.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>With its wide, safe platforms, architect-designed stations and – foremost in people’s minds after our sizzling summer – air-conditioned carriages, the December 9 opening of Crossrail, or the Elizabeth Line as it will be known, has long been in the diary as the day the capital gets a new train line it can really be proud of</media:title><media:text>File photo dated 14/9/2017 of Crossrail engineers walk alongside completed tracks as the Crossrail project celebrates the completion of permanent Elizabeth line track in Whitechapel, east London. A £600 million increase in the budget of London's Crossrail project will be "poorly received by people in the North", a think tank has warned.</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1442227</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>PA Wire/PA Images</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6120613/PLATELLS-PEOPLE-hope-girls-role-models-like-these.html" title="PLATELL'S PEOPLE: What hope for girls with role models ranging from tiny-waisted Kim Kardashian to bountiful Tess Holliday? "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6116719/RAY-CONNOLLY-asks-swap-lifetime-memories-self-drive-car.html" title="As technology threatens to turn us all into passengers, RAY CONNOLLY asks: 'Who would swap a lifetime of memories for a self-drive car?' "></link></item><item><title>CRAIG BROWN: 'Less Riviera, more Carry On Up The Khyber' - your summer holiday dreams compared to the realities (part II)</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6111699/CRAIG-BROWN-summer-holiday-dreams-compared-realities-II.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 22:59:46 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6111699</guid><description><![CDATA[Craig Brown brings your holiday hopes down to earth with a reminder that no matter how much you hope to look like Charles Dance in The Jewel In The Crown, Carry On Up The Khyber looms ahead.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<img id="i-28215d563be5ddee" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/29/20/4F81AB6400000578-0-image-m-3_1535570254728.jpg" height="455" width="306" alt="A panama hat that makes you look like Charles Hawtrey in Carry On Up The Khyber" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> A panama hat that makes you look like Charles Dance in The Jewel In The Crown.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> A panama hat that makes you look like <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/prince_charles/index.html" id="mol-7f4c6460-abc5-11e8-987a-879a5a90ab23">Prince Charles</a> on the Italian Riviera.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> A panama hat that makes you look like Charles Hawtrey in Carry On Up The Khyber.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> To swim for hours on end in a beautiful azure sea, the only sound for miles around the gentle ripple of the waves.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> Swimming some distance away from the noisy family from Dusseldorf with the frisbee.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> Two young men on jet-skis with headphones yelling at each other as they circle within a yard of your head, while the family from Dusseldorf decide to accompany their game of frisbee with Germany’s last-Eurovision-entry-but-one playing on repeat at full blast.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> To be taken for a local.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> Being treated as a local.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> An extra 80 per cent surreptitiously added to your bill, and your English accent imitated mercilessly the moment you leave the restaurant.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> A discreet tattoo of a tropical bird, somewhere near your ankle.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> A tiny tattoo of a heart, somewhere near your shoulder.</p><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> A life-size tattoo of Ed Sheeran all over your chest.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> To exchange amusing banter with the interesting-looking couple in the far corner of the restaurant.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> Exchanging a few friendly words with the maitre d’ about how pleasant your day has been.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> Caught up in a heated argument about the pros and cons of Brexit with an overweight couple from Bishop’s Stortford.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> A three-course picnic from a wickerwork hamper beside a rippling stream within a landscape of meadows and leafy glades.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> A cheese and tomato sandwich on a park bench.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get: </strong>A lukewarm beef patty topped with melted American cheese and barbecue sauce in a parked car outside Burger King at Newport Pagnell services.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> To relax in a nice hot bath at the hotel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> Relaxing in a nice hot shower at the hotel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> Drenched when you turn on the bath taps and the shower spurts cold water all over you.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> David Attenborough sitting next to you on the plane.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> James Corden sitting next to you on the plane.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> Liam Gallagher sitting next to you on the plane, telling you to eff off when you ask him politely to turn his music down. And it later emerges that it’s not even Liam Gallagher, just someone who looks a bit like him.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> A hotel in the centre.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> A hotel not far from the centre</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> A hotel on the ring road, next to the detention centre.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You want:</strong> To drive an open-top Jaguar along deserted roads, the sweet scent of the pine trees billowing through your hair.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You’d settle for:</strong> Driving a two-door Fiat Uno along a busy motorway.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>You get:</strong> Caught in a queue at the car hire kiosk for an hour and a quarter before being informed that the car you booked is no longer available but luckily they can provide you with a model twice as expensive but first you must sign here here here here here here here and here, and do you want extra insurance because if you don’t take extra insurance then you could be charged up to £5,000 for the first scratch and £7,500 for every scratch thereafter and be sure to return the vehicle with a full tank of petrol, there’s a petrol station on the other side of the city which is due to close half an hour before your arrival and the way to put the car into reverse is hidden in small print towards the bottom of page 278 in the driver’s manual and if you wanted air-conditioning you should have ordered that three weeks in advance but for just £7.50 per day they can provide a battery fan, just sign here here here and here and if you want to insure the battery fan against loss or damage just sign here here here here and here. A steering wheel? You want a steering wheel? Ah you should have mentioned, that will be extra. And you want insurance for it?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Craig Brown brings your holiday hopes down to earth with a reminder that no matter how much you hope to look like Charles Dance in The Jewel In The Crown, Carry On Up The Khyber looms ahead.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Craig Brown for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-08-30T01:00:55.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Your summer holiday dreams compared to the realities (part II) </mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-08-30T01:00:55.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/29/20/4F81AB6400000578-0-image-m-3_1535570254728.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>A panama hat that makes you look like Charles Hawtrey in Carry On Up The Khyber</media:title><media:text>EDITORIAL USE ONLY / NO MERCHANDISING\nMandatory Credit: Photo by ITV/REX/Shutterstock (763768br)\n'Carry On Up The Khyber'   Film\nTerry Scott and Charles Hawtrey\nITV ARCHIVE</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1480583</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>ITV/REX/Shutterstock</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6108387/Society-stop-seeing-fat-people-greedy-failures-says-SARAH-VINE-amid-diet-pill-storm.html" title="'I'm proof diet pills can work,' says SARAH VINE. But society must stop seeing fat people as greedy failures who deserve to be punished "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6100975/ANDREW-PIERCE-Baroness-Betty-weighs-suffragette-statue-hubbub.html" title="ANDREW PIERCE: Baroness Betty weighs in on suffragette statue hubbub"></link></item><item><title>ANDREW PIERCE: Former BBC boss slates broadcaster over its Brexit bulletins that often topple into propaganda</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6077135/ANDREW-PIERCE-Former-BBC-boss-slates-broadcaster-Brexit-bulletins.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:20:36 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6077135</guid><description><![CDATA[ANDREW PIERCE: Roger Mosey was the most senior executive to admit what most of us have known for a long time: the corporation leans so far Left.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">As former head of <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/bbc/index.html" id="mol-dbdd2200-a40e-11e8-a3a0-f3bef318ba2c">BBC</a> Television News, Roger Mosey was the most senior executive to admit what most of us have known for a long time: the corporation leans so far Left, it often topples into propaganda.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Mosey, who left the national broadcaster in 2013 and is now Master of Selwyn College, Cambridge, laid bare the Beeb's bias in his book Getting Out Alive. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This week he is on the attack again, particularly over <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/brexit/index.html" id="mol-dbdd4910-a40e-11e8-a3a0-f3bef318ba2c">Brexit</a> coverage.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He's argued for years that the BBC has failed to give sufficient prominence to Leave voices and he now seems equally appalled by its obsession with <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/boris_johnson/index.html" id="mol-dbdb9b60-a40e-11e8-a3a0-f3bef318ba2c">Boris Johnson</a>'s 'letterbox' comments on burkas. </p><img id="i-3ac49d7e22b4b8ec" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/09/23/0158FCA800000578-0-image-a-1_1533854778841.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Boris Johnson is subject to a formal disciplinary investigation following his burkas comments" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">He writes in the New Statesman magazine: 'Compare and contrast days of headline coverage for Boris Johnson's view on the burkas with no equivalent scrutiny of his plans for the single market or free trade. The corporation knows it needs to sharpen its act.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Mosey recalled a 1980s bulletin explaining in depth — about half the bulletin — how perestroika and glasnost were helping bring reforms to the Soviet Union.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Shouldn't there be a similar commitment to examining issues such as what leaving on World Trade Organisation terms would mean for this country? </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'And when there is a reckoning about what happened to our politics, the broadcasters cannot and should not be exempt.' </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He may look shambolic, but Boris Johnson has what it takes to be the next Tory leader, according to Sir Bernard Ingham who was Margaret Thatcher's press secretary.</p><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">'If the world can get used to Donald Trump it can surely cope with Boris's mop and dishevelled self. Like so many tramps in high places, with the notable exception of the profoundly ignorant Jeremy Corbyn, he is highly intelligent, a classical scholar with both feet on the ground.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He has the priceless ability to talk to people in their own language, give or take a Woosterish 'crikey!' or two.'</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Labour MPs who raged about Boris Johnson's comments on the burka — which he doesn't want to ban — should check out a hard-Left guest speaker at the World Transformed Festival, which runs alongside the Labour Party conference in Liverpool next month.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Jean-Luc Melenchon, the French socialist veteran, says of full-face veils: 'The complete concealment of the face is problematic … it prevents any recognition of the persons concerned, which disturbs public order.' He adds a veil 'puts into question the person's dignity' and suggests the law might have to ban them.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Will howls of Lefty rage follow?</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong></strong><strong>EU wouldn't believe it... </strong><strong></strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">All internet domains ending in EU will have to be terminated in Britain when we leave the EU next March. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Could make life tricky for Leave.EU or www.leavemeansleave.eu. The only way to preserve the addresses will be to move the servers to the EU. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Nigel Farage will not be happy.</p><div class="item">
    

</div>
<div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>ANDREW PIERCE: As former head of BBC Television News, Roger Mosey was the most senior executive to admit what most of us have known for a long time: the corporation leans so far Left, it often topples into propaganda. Mosey, who left the national broadcaster in 2013 and is now Master of Selwyn College, Cambridge, laid bare the Beeb's bias in his book Getting Out Alive.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Andrew Pierce for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-08-21T16:52:38.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>ANDREW PIERCE: Former BBC boss slams broadcaster over Brexit bulletins</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-08-21T16:52:38.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>BBC,Boris Johnson,Brexit</media:keywords><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/09/23/0158FCA800000578-0-image-a-1_1533854778841.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Boris Johnson is subject to a formal disciplinary investigation following his burkas comments</media:title><media:text>Mayor for London, Boris Johnson.
. REXMAILPIX.</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1005782</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>COMMISSIONED WORK</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6053445/ANDREW-PIERCE-Lord-Sheikh-man-lecture-Boris-Johnson-respect-Muslim-women.html" title="ANDREW PIERCE: Is Lord Sheikh the man to lecture Boris Johnson on respect for Muslim women? "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6045543/ANDREW-PIERCE-Tories-suicidally-crisis-Boris-burka-drama.html" title="ANDREW PIERCE: How the Tories suicidally made a crisis from the Boris burka drama"></link></item><item><title>Comedy is no laughing matter (cont…): Don’t take the mickey out of us mice, the rodents complain to CRAIG BROWN </title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6057375/Comedy-no-laughing-matter-cont-Dont-mickey-mice.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:18:37 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6057375</guid><description><![CDATA[In a world where every joke provokes a furious reaction from some offended group, it's about time someone stopped to think of the mothers-in-law, or even the cheeses hurt by the cheesiest of gags.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<img id="i-d2c4c94a56a5a423" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/14/01/35C0E3F800000578-6057375-Craig_Brown_s_latest_column_shows_the_people_who_have_complained-a-55_1534205799502.jpg" height="400" width="306" alt="Craig Brown's latest column shows the people who have complained to him about offensive comedy" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sir: In response to your correspondence concerning hurtful so-called 'jokes', I am writing to express my concern that no one in Parliament or beyond has lifted a finger in the defence of aunts.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As an aunt myself, I have had to endure a lifetime of abuse dressed up as comedy. Mr Wodehouse remains the worst offender. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Just imagine what it is like for any aunt to read a passage such as: 'It is no use telling me there are bad aunts and good aunts. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">At the core, they are all alike. Sooner or later, out pops the cloven hoof.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Most aunts lead decent, hard-working lives. This sort of auntism fosters hate and prejudice. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Frankly, it defies belief that Wodehouse was never forced to apologise, or placed on a re-education scheme. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Instead, he was allowed to go on making incendiary insults against innocent women such as Aunt Agatha, 'who eats broken bottles and conducts human sacrifices by the light of the full moon', and Aunt Dahlia, who is 'short and solid, like a scrum half in the game of Rugby football'. Funny? I don't think so.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is high time such remarks were banned. Only yesterday, my nephew asked me: 'How do you make anti-freeze?' When I said that I didn't know, he replied: 'Shut her in the fridge.' What sort of a world are we living in?</p><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Norma-Lee Cross (Miss)</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sir: As the Chair of AAMILJ (Action Against Mother-in-Law Jokes) I sympathise with your previous correspondent. For too long, we as a society have tolerated deeply offensive 'jokes' against some of our most vulnerable members.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The late Les Dawson was particularly insensitive. It beats me how anyone could laugh at the following joke: 'I took my mother-in-law to Madame Tussauds' Chamber of Horrors, and one of the attendants said: 'Keep her moving, sir; we're stock-taking.' 'Yet they do.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Once, after seeing Dawson deliver a particularly vicious remark on television, I felt bound to call for his resignation from the world of family entertainment. 'I can always tell when my mother-in-law's coming to stay,' he said, 'The mice throw themselves on the traps.' Yet he never had the grace to apologise.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Yvonne Livid (Mrs)</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sir: As a mouse who has for many years been prone to depression, I found your previous correspondent's throwaway remarks about suicidal mice hard to stomach.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">For too long, people have laughed along with deeply objectionable and frankly mouse-ist riddles such as: 'What goes eek-eek-bang?' 'A mouse in a minefield.' And: 'What are crisp, like milk and go 'eek-eek-eek' when you eat them?' 'Mice Krispies.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Cruel jokes like these have done much to undermine the standing of mice within the community, and have led to many incidents involving cheddar in traps, and so forth. Something must be done!</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Michael Mouse (Mr)</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sir: As a lifelong member of the international cheese community — I was born a cream cheese, and later transitioned to a blue cheese — I object to being pigeonholed by your previous correspondent as useless for anything but catching mice.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I have suffered cheesist jokes my whole life. Riddles such as . . .</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Q: 'What kind of cheese do you use to disguise a small horse?' A: 'Mascarpone.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">. . . are not only offensive but inaccurate, as this mild, creamy cheese, though ideal for both sweet and savoury dishes, remains ill-suited to spreading over small horses.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Roc Fort (Mr)</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Sir: As a lifelong horse, I write to express my outrage at the supposedly 'light-hearted' remarks against members of the four-footed equine community in the letter above.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Let me make it clear. Ponies should always be treated with consideration, and never masked, either with cream cheese or with anything else. It is not funny to suggest otherwise.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I am sick and tired of horse jokes. Every time I walk into a bar, the barman always says: 'Why the long face?' as if this was the first time anyone had said it.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is the constant drip-drip-drip of horse-ist prejudice that is undermining our place in society. It is high time we as a society came to realise that there is no such thing as an inoffensive joke. Is it going too far to suggest that they should all be banned?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Dobbin</strong></p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>In a world where every joke provokes a furious reaction from some offended group, it's about time someone stopped to think of the mothers-in-law, or even the cheeses hurt by the cheesiest of gags.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Craig Brown for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-08-14T08:35:03.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>Comedy is no laughing matter: Rodents complain to Craig Brown</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-08-14T08:35:03.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/14/01/35C0E3F800000578-6057375-Craig_Brown_s_latest_column_shows_the_people_who_have_complained-a-55_1534205799502.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Craig Brown's latest column shows the people who have complained to him about offensive comedy</media:title><media:text>A stock image of a mouse with a big block of cheese.</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1147327</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>Getty Images</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6053377/DOMINIC-LAWSON-Senior-Tories-suffering-Boris-Derangement-Syndrome.html" title="DOMINIC LAWSON: Johnson's burka row critics cried 'Je suis Charlie' when French journalists were killed for satirising Islam - but (surprise!) not one will now say JE SUIS BORIS!"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-6056873/BRANDON-LEWIS-TORY-CHAIRMAN-Labour-Jeremy-Corbyn.html" title="TORY CHAIRMAN BRANDON LEWIS: This goes beyond party politics. In the name of basic decency, how can Labour put up with Jeremy Corbyn?"></link></item><item><title>BLACK DOG: After calling his Chinese wife Japanese...Jeremy Hunt's national calamity no 2? </title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6027655/BLACK-DOG-calling-Chinese-wife-Japanese-Jeremy-Hunts-national-calamity-no-2.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:59:47 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6027655</guid><description><![CDATA[Hot on the heels of wrongly telling his Chinese hosts that his wife was Japanese (rather than Chinese), Foreign Secretary Jeremy Hunt ruffled more feathers last week in France. ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">Hot on the heels of wrongly telling his Chinese hosts that his wife was Japanese (rather than Chinese), tongue-tied Foreign Secretary Jeremy Hunt ruffled more diplomatic feathers last week in <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/france/index.html" id="mol-d900cbb0-984a-11e8-869a-5faf56d64ddb">France</a>. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In a radio interview, he repeatedly referred to ‘l’Angleterre’ – not ‘le Royaume-Uni’. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Someone needs to tell Little Englander Jeremy he represents the UK as a whole.</p><img id="i-4f45062de0a46877" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/05/01/4EB0C8F600000578-0-image-a-14_1533430321512.jpg" height="475" width="634" alt="In a radio interview, Jeremy Hunt repeatedly referred to ‘l’Angleterre’ – not ‘le Royaume-Uni, suggesting he represents just England and not the UK" class="blkBorder img-share" /><div class="item">
    

</div>
<div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">At 80, Brexiteer ex-SDP leader Dr David Owen is as arrogant as ever. He sneers at pro-European Tory MP Anna Soubry: ‘What’s her name? Sowerby? That’s it. Sourpuss. My family used to call Roy Jenkins Le Roi Jean Quinze. That’s how you deal with impossible people like Madame Sourpuss.’ Brexit would be a piece of cake if only there was a more ‘charismatic’ PM than Theresa May at the helm, he drawls. Who can vain ‘Dr Death’ possibly mean?</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">MPs are keen to know how Leader of the House Andrea Leadsom will approach her task of confronting Labour MP Keith Vaz over claims he told Commons clerk Jenny McCullough she was unfit to look after members because she ‘wasn’t a mother’. Leadsom had to quit the 2016 Tory leadership race after suggesting Theresa May was unfit to be PM for the same reason. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>The special powers of new girl Steph</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Bosses of pro-Brexit think-tank the Institute of Economic Affairs last week denied offering rich US donors access to Ministers to help them win lucrative deals when the UK leaves the EU. Perish the thought. Clearly, that has nothing to do with the fact that pro-Brexit IEA head of communications Stephanie Lis, has been appointed new special adviser to Brexit Secretary Dominic Raab.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">After being prised out of the Foreign Secretary’s grace-and-favour London mansion a month after he quit the job, it turns out Boris Johnson is not the only Boris who won’t leave his pampered perch. Deputy Commons Speaker Lindsay Hoyle says it took him and his wife Cath hours to persuade their African Grey parrot ‘Boris’, above, out of his cage and into temporary lodgings while they were away on holiday.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Jez won't be rooted out</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Given how Jeremy Corbyn loves his allotment, he was remarkably unruffled by claims from Barnet councillors that he was unworthy of a local plot after his failure to tackle anti-Semitism. ‘Jeremy’s so well in with the local allotment holders’ association, he’s sure his beloved leeks are safe,’ says Dog’s mole. ‘It’s like Momentum’s grip over the Labour Party, only much, much tighter.’</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Serjeant at Arms Kamal El-Hajji faces the Westminster equivalent of a court martial in September. Colleagues of Kamal are gunning for him for publicly dismissing bullying allegations against Speaker John Bercow as a ‘witch hunt’. ‘Much as we’d all like to, it’s strictly “verboten” for senior staff to comment on MPs like that,’ says Dog’s snout. </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Hot on the heels of wrongly telling his Chinese hosts that his wife was Japanese (rather than Chinese), tongue-tied Foreign Secretary Jeremy Hunt ruffled more diplomatic feathers last week in France.  In a radio interview, he repeatedly referred to ‘l’Angleterre’ – not ‘le Royaume-Uni’.  Someone needs to tell Little Englander Jeremy he represents the UK as a whole, says BLACK DOG.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Black Dog for The Mail on Sunday</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-08-05T09:49:58.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>BLACK DOG: Jeremy Hunt's national calamity no 2? </mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-08-05T09:49:58.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/05/01/4EB0C8F600000578-0-image-a-14_1533430321512.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>In a radio interview, Jeremy Hunt repeatedly referred to ‘l’Angleterre’ – not ‘le Royaume-Uni, suggesting he represents just England and not the UK</media:title><media:text>© Licensed to London News Pictures . Oxfordshire , UK . FILE PICTURE DATED 12/07/2018 of British Foriegn Secretary JEREMY HUNT and his wife LUCIA GUO , at Blenheim Palace , during a visit by US President Donald Trump . Hunt has mistakenly referred to his Chinese wife as "Japanese" during an official visit to China . Photo credit: Joel Goodman/LNP</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1135783</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>Joel Goodman/LNP</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-6005907/Meet-two-women-work-six-months-year-share-best-travel-tips.html" title="Friends who only work for six months of the year share their top travel tips - and how they keep costs low wherever they are"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-6027383/The-way-Chavscot-New-Ascot-reality-TV-causes-uproar.html" title="The only way is Chavscot: Drunken brawls, fake tans galore and distinctly unladylike ladies bring Essex to Ascot in new reality show that has left the upmarket town's residents in uproar "></link></item><item><title>MAIL ON SUNDAY COMMENT: Money should never become our only goal</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6027593/MAIL-SUNDAY-COMMENT-Money-never-goal.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:17:58 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6027593</guid><description><![CDATA[It is hard to justify the vast differences between the Western way of life and the conditions endured by those who live in the poorer parts of the world.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<img id="i-5d938a5b89979b85" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/05/01/4ED5356300000578-6027593-Female_factory_workers_in_Phnom_Penh_Camboadia_are_paid_just_64p-a-5_1533428198055.jpg" height="459" width="306" alt="Female factory workers in Phnom Penh, Camboadia are paid just 64p per hour to produce Manchester United's jerseys for the 2018-19 season, a Mail on Sunday investigation revealed" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is hard to justify the vast differences between the Western way of life and the conditions endured by those who live in the poorer parts of the world. It is only because their poverty is so far away from us that we can keep it out of our minds.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But sometimes the contrast is too much to bear. How can it possibly be right for a super-rich football club such as <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/sport/teampages/manchester-united.html" id="mol-01f8fb60-9845-11e8-a2cf-6381ff7a83bc">Manchester United</a> to sell – for as much as £110 – a shirt made by women in Cambodian sweatshops for wages as little as 64p an hour?</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">These shirts are highly desired items. Young supporters clamour to wear them. The club can command astonishingly high prices for them. But where does the money go? Plainly, not to those who do the hardest work.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As it happens, the Cambodian factories where they are made comply with the laws of that country, but the harsh contrast between the two figures does not sit easily with the club's standing in its own city, in Britain and the world.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Manchester United is not simply a business. It is a powerful influence in its community. It has a duty way beyond the mere making of money.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Capitalism did not flourish here just because men were free to make profits. The great inventor of economics, Adam Smith, always made it clear that morals were fundamental to prosperity. Trust, honesty and justice are the foundations of the wealth of nations.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This is not the only case of business using its power and cunning to avoid its moral obligations.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The online retailer Amazon manages, quite legally, to avoid paying huge amounts of tax which its struggling high street competitors cannot escape. Apple, Netflix and Google are equally skilful in keeping their tax bills low.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is hard to prevent them. But that does not mean it is either wise or right for them to exploit their freedoms to the maximum, as they are doing now. On the contrary, if capitalism behaves in this crude and greedy fashion, exactly as the Marxists have always claimed it does, then the ultimate beneficiaries will be Leftist extremists. If they come to power, they will end prosperity for good.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ethical capitalism is not just possible, but desirable. Gross inequalities, of the sort we expose here today, can be avoided by intelligent management, and they should be avoided, for the sake of free societies everywhere.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Stop digging, Jeremy</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Jeremy Corbyn shows no sign of understanding how deep the hole is that he has dug for himself with his policies on Israel and his views on anti-Semitism.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">His narrow-minded 1970s agitprop opinions simply cannot stand the test of national politics. Yet he still hangs on, and this is one of the reasons why there are now serious moves to form a new and responsible opposition, involving senior Blairites and Liberal Democrat leader Vince Cable.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A major realignment in British politics is now perfectly possible, and may be the most powerful answer to Mr Corbyn's hopeless refusal to confront the nasty elements of his own faction.</p><div class="item">
    

</div>
]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>It is hard to justify the vast differences between the Western way of life and the conditions endured by those who live in the poorer parts of the world. It is only because their poverty is so far away from us that we can keep it out of our minds. But sometimes the contrast is too much to bear. How can it possibly be right for a super-rich football club such as Manchester United to sell – for as much as £110 – a shirt made by women in Cambodian sweatshops for wages as little as 64p an hour?</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Mail on Sunday Comment for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-08-05T02:18:01.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>MAIL ON SUNDAY COMMENT: Money should never become our only goal</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-08-05T02:18:01.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/05/01/4ED5356300000578-6027593-Female_factory_workers_in_Phnom_Penh_Camboadia_are_paid_just_64p-a-5_1533428198055.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Female factory workers in&amp;nbsp;Phnom Penh, Camboadia are paid just 64p per hour to produce Manchester United's jerseys for the 2018-19 season, a Mail on Sunday investigation revealed</media:title><media:text>02/08/18 SHOWS WORKERS AT THE FACTORY IN PHNOM PEHN ,CAMBODIA CALLED "TRAX APPAREL CO LTD".
WHERE THEY MAKE ADIDAS SPORTS AND FOOTBALL WARE.
(L) SOPHIEP RITH  (R) NARENN SAO</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1138008</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>PHILIP IDE</mi:licensorName></media:content></item><item><title>The cunning crocodile who may devour Zimbabwe’s new dawn: IAN BIRRELL on a nation gripped by fears of fresh violence on eve of historic poll </title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6003383/The-cunning-crocodile-devour-Zimbabwes-new-dawn.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 01:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6003383</guid><description><![CDATA[Tomorrow marks a landmark in the cruel history of Zimbabwe: the first election since independence in 1980 without Robert Mugabe’s name on the ballot paper.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">Tomorrow marks a landmark in the cruel history of Zimbabwe: the first election since independence in 1980 without Robert Mugabe’s name on the ballot paper. This alone is cause to celebrate in a continent corroded by old men and their corrupt cliques clinging to power.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">So it is a moment of hope for this beautiful nation. A moment when democrats can dare to dream of shaking off the shackles of an abhorrent regime that has slaughtered thousands, pillaged billions from diamond mines and unleashed the second-worst hyper-inflation in history.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But Zimbabweans are realists. They have been stockpiling food, filling up cars with fuel and trying to get their hands on scarce currency. For they know power does not change hands lightly in their land.</p><img id="i-a3d1bca403b540b0" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/29/02/4EA9501700000578-0-image-a-22_1532826234541.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Zimbabwe's President Emmerson Mnangagwa addresses a rally in Bulawayo on June 23, 2018" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The favourite to win is current president Emmerson Mnangagwa, a ruthless 75-year-old nicknamed The Crocodile for his ability to devour rivals, who seeks to consolidate power seized in a bloodless coup last year with his pals in the army.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Yet for all his desperate attempts at rebranding – with a Zimbabwean flag scarf always slung around his neck, wooden interviews with fawning foreign media and a fleeting appearance at Davos – there should be no illusions about Mnangagwa.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This is a man linked to the worst excesses of the Mugabe era. He may be posing as a democrat now but his history is one of crushing dissent – such as in 2008 when he persuaded Mugabe not to quit after losing an election, then unleashed savage violence to terrorise the rival Movement for Democratic Change into accepting a coalition.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Following the death of the MDC’s brave if flawed leader Morgan Tsvangirai, the party is led by a clever 40-year-old lawyer and pastor called Nelson Chamisa. He has run a feisty campaign appealing to younger voters desperate for change and an end to corruption. Polls show the gap between the parties closing, with the energetic Chamisa speaking at twice as many rallies as his elderly opponent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One video of soldiers urging people not to leave when Mnangagwa was delivering one of his dreary speeches went viral.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Chamisa even claims Mugabe and his reviled second wife Grace – stuck in their sprawling ‘Blue Roof’ mansion in Harare – are backing him, such is the ousted president’s loathing of his treacherous former spy chief.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The ruling Zanu-PF party claims to have created 4.5 million jobs since 2013, which causes bitter laughter in a nation of 16 million where people sleep in bank queues, formal jobs are almost unknown and ‘the economy is screaming’, as one columnist wrote last week.</p><div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Almost the entire national budget is consumed by the bloated civil service, stuffed with Zanu-PF supporters – yet they have just been given a hefty ‘special allowance’ bung.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Such is the fear of election deadlock, or defeat for The Crocodile leading to another explosion of violence, MDC supporters told me they are attending Mnangagwa rallies to collect his T-shirts as insurance against post-election attacks.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘My sister saw I had one of the T-shirts in my car so she took it for her security,’ said one Harare resident. ‘She knows these people will come back later for retribution if they lose.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The MDC is likely to sweep the cities again. In Zanu-PF’s rural heartlands, there have been reports of intimidation with soldiers and traditional leaders warning people not to vote ‘the wrong way’, while food aid from foreign donors has been used to buy loyalty.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Civil rights activists say 11 ‘bases’ have been established. Such places – run by loyalists, soldiers and the war veterans behind white farm seizures – have been used in past election campaigns for abductions, beatings and torture.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There have also been sightings of party thugs wandering around shaking matchboxes at people – an unsubtle reminder that their homes could burn if violence erupts. ‘I’m so tired – I just want this all over,’ said one pro-democracy campaigner.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Meanwhile, much of the media is a mouthpiece for Mnangagwa, the electoral commission is obviously partisan, and there are concerns over manipulation of the electoral roll. This is not surprising when it includes one voter aged 141 and another aged 134.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There is also concern over British ambassador Catriona Laing, a controversial character who I revealed two years ago was trying to fix a bailout for Mugabe’s regime. Western diplomats, backed by key MDC figures, claim she is supporting Zanu-PF.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One US source told me Laing had said to him: ‘We can do business with Mnangagwa.’ She was even accused of flaunting Mnangagwa’s campaign scarf in Downing Street this year, although she claimed it was a Christmas present in similar colours.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Certainly the political climate is freer than it was under Mugabe’s rigid one-party state. But who knows what will happen this week, especially with many former regime loyalists standing as independents and The Crocodile’s savage history.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Once again, fear walks hand in hand with hope in Harare.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘All the schools are closed,’ said one friend. ‘We are just hoping there is no violence since the kids are all at home and the younger ones have not experienced such things before.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Tomorrow marks a landmark in the cruel history of Zimbabwe: the first election since independence in 1980 without Robert Mugabe’s name on the ballot paper. This alone is cause to celebrate in a continent corroded by old men and their corrupt cliques clinging to power.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ian Birrell for The Mail on Sunday</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-07-29T03:05:39.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>The cunning crocodile who may devour Zimbabwe’s new dawn</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-07-29T03:05:39.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/29/02/4EA9501700000578-0-image-a-22_1532826234541.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Zimbabwe's President Emmerson Mnangagwa addresses a rally in Bulawayo on June 23, 2018</media:title><media:text>TOPSHOT - Zimbabwe's President Emmerson Mnangagwa addresses a rally in Bulawayo on June 23, 2018.\nAn AFP correspondent reported multiple injuries but could not immediately give a precise toll after a blast at a ruling ZANU-PF party rally today. Images broadcast on Zimbabwean TV showed scenes of chaos and medics fighting to save those wounded by the blast at the White City stadium in the country's second city Bulawayo. / AFP PHOTO / ZINYANGE AUNTONYZINYANGE AUNTONY/AFP/Getty Images</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1000161</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>AFP/Getty Images</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2519062/Nelson-Mandela-dead-95.html" title="NELSON MANDELA 1918 - 2013: Family gather at home of Nelson Mandela as mourners continue to pay their respects outside the former leader’s house and whole country enters period of mourning"></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-5982367/Prince-Harry-arrives-two-day-visit-Netherlands.html" title="Prince Harry follows in the footsteps of his mother Diana as he arrives in Amsterdam for international AIDS conference at start of two-day visit to Netherlands"></link></item><item><title>PETER OBORNE: Have we learnt nothing from the senseless Iraq War? </title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6001427/PETER-OBORNE-learnt-senseless-Iraq-War.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 01:26:36 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6001427</guid><description><![CDATA[Although 15 years have passed since Tony Blair took Britain to war in Iraq, the catastrophic fall-out from his calamitous decision still dominates global politics.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p class="mol-para-with-font">Although 15 years have passed since <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/tony_blair/index.html" id="mol-44ab9f30-9205-11e8-a3db-077d75860f64">Tony Blair</a> took Britain to war in <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="/news/iraq/index.html" id="mol-44ad25d0-9205-11e8-a3db-077d75860f64">Iraq</a>, the catastrophic fall-out from his calamitous decision still dominates global politics.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Without doubt, history will judge Blair and his fellow warmonger George W. Bush very harshly. Their rash move to topple Saddam Hussein caused incalculable bloodshed, the deaths of 179 British service personnel and has led to endless civil wars and political instability in the region. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And, of course, it also triggered the rise of Islamic State, the terrorist organisation that has launched murderous attacks on the West.</p><img id="i-109ecde628cb0c68" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/28/02/1B4A432E00000514-0-image-a-9_1532740962989.jpg" height="427" width="634" alt="Without doubt, history will judge Blair and his fellow warmonger George W. Bush very harshly. Their rash move to topple Saddam Hussein caused incalculable bloodshed, the deaths of 179 British service personnel and has led to endless civil wars and political instability in the region" class="blkBorder img-share" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Blair’s stubborn refusal to admit he was wrong and apologise has, rightly, made him a pariah figure for many. Bush, too, remains unrepentant. How ironic that this week the former U.S. president blithely accepted the award of a prestigious Liberty Medal for his ‘commitment’ to war veterans.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But there are many others who were responsible for the Iraq War fiasco who still believe they did nothing wrong.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">They include the so-called Neo-Conservatives — a tight-knit group of politicians and Right-wing thinkers.</p><div class="item">
    

</div>
<div>
</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">They have long been concerned that the West, because of the reduced threat from Russia since the collapse of the Soviet Union, has become too complacent about military threats from elsewhere.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Consequently, they are worried about what they see as a reluctance to invest sufficiently in the U.S. military.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">They are convinced, too, that the interests of the West are best served by breaking international rules, if necessary, and intervening in other people’s affairs even if it means going to war.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">These Neo-Cons were in the ascendancy in Washington in the run-up to the Iraq War. Most worryingly, I fear they now exercise huge influence in Donald Trump’s White House. What’s more, many of the men who were most vocal in putting the case for war against Saddam have Trump’s ear.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">One of those, John Bolton, who was Bush’s senior adviser on arms control and international security, has been given the key role of national security adviser.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Belligerently unrepentant, in recent years, he has said his view about the moral legitimacy of the Iraq War has not been altered by the discovery that Saddam did not possess weapons of mass destruction.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He has said: ‘I still think the decision to overthrow Saddam was correct. I think decisions made after that decision were wrong, although I think the worst decision made after that was the 2011 decision to withdraw U.S. and coalition forces.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The worry is that Bolton has powerful global allies.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">For example, Saudi Arabia’s Crown Prince Mohammed Bin Salman is straining at the leash to launch a war against Iran. He is supported in this by Israel’s Prime Minister, Benjamin Netanyahu.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Chillingly, the Neo-Cons’ biggest cheerleader is Trump, who last week posted an intemperate Tweet — in most unpresidential language — as a warning to Iran’s President Rouhani.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It said: ‘NEVER EVER THREATEN THE UNITED STATES AGAIN OR YOU WILL SUFFER CONSEQUENCES THE LIKE OF WHICH FEW THROUGHOUT HISTORY HAVE EVER SUFFERED BEFORE.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Trump is well-known for sending furious, rambling and misspelt Tweets in the middle of the night. But this — which I interpret as threatening a nuclear attack — should be taken very seriously.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The truth is that Trump speaks for a growing body of opinion on both sides of the Atlantic, which includes many British MPs.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Two members of the Cabinet, Michael Gove and Liam Fox, are ideologues whose views have been compared to those of hardline U.S. Neo-Cons. Former Tory leader Iain Duncan Smith, who strongly supported the Iraq war, recently stated in Parliament that Iran represented a ‘serious threat’ that needed to be ‘dealt with’.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Indeed, several Tory MPs sympathise with Trump’s foreign policy.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">During a recent Commons debate on Trump’s decision to tear up Barack Obama’s nuclear deal with the Tehran regime — which meant sanctions against Iran would be lifted in return for Iran halting its nuclear programmes — many Tories supported Trump instead of their own leader, Theresa May, who backed Obama.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Indeed, I fear that the drumbeat for war against Iran is getting worrying loud. I fear, too, that we are beginning to witness a repeat of the tactics which the Neo-Cons used to persuade the British and American governments to launch a war in Iraq in 2003 when they skilfully used allies in Westminster and the White House, sections of the Press and Right-wing think-tanks.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As part of the current propaganda campaign, a group of Tory MPs, led by ex-Cabinet minister Theresa Villiers, attended a conference in Paris last month that called for regime change in Iran.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The keynote speech was given by Trump’s attorney, Rudy Giuliani, a former mayor of New York. He said: ‘The mullahs must go, the ayatollah must go, and they must be replaced by a democratic government . . . Freedom is right around the corner . . . Next year I want to have this convention in Tehran!”</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Fifteen years ago, Neo-Cons such as Giuliani were convinced Saddam was a pushover and would easily replaced by a pro-Western leader. How utterly wrong they have been proved to be.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">They are utterly wrong, too, now, if they think the Iranian regime can be replaced by a democratic, pro-Western government.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The world is far more dangerous — and complicated — than it was 15 years ago. It’s time to call off these mad dogs of war.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong><strong><span class="mol-style-large">A very unsuitable buddy for Boris </span></strong></strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Boris Johnson has cleverly manoeuvred himself to be the undisputed leader of the Tory faction dedicated to pursuing a ‘positive’, ‘self-confident’ approach to restore what he calls the ‘vision of Brexit’ that people voted for in the EU referendum.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He deserves praise for this and his principled resignation from Cabinet.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But since stepping down as Foreign Secretary, there have been disturbing reports that he has had secret meetings with Donald Trump’s former adviser, Steve Bannon. The American has been in Europe recently to cement links with far-Right political parties.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Indeed, he has shamefully spoken out in support of the former leader of the English Defence League, Tommy Robinson, a football hooligan turned anti-Muslim racist who is in jail.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Disgracefully, Bannon called Robinson ‘the backbone of this country’.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">I am a friend of Boris Johnson and have long admired his policies of liberal internationalism.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He is betraying those fine values if he is supping with Steve Bannon.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:abstract>Although 15 years have passed since Tony Blair took Britain to war in Iraq, the catastrophic fall-out from his calamitous decision still dominates global politics. Without doubt, history will judge Blair and his fellow warmonger George W. Bush very harshly. Their rash move to topple Saddam Hussein caused incalculable bloodshed, the deaths of 179 British service personnel and has led to endless civil wars and political instability in the region. And, of course, it also triggered the rise of Islamic State, the terrorist organisation that has launched murderous attacks on the West.</dc:abstract><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Peter Oborne For The Daily Mail</dc:creator><dc:modified>2018-07-28T12:40:45.000+02:00</dc:modified><mi:shortTitle>PETER OBORNE: Have we learnt nothing from the senseless Iraq War? </mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-07-28T12:40:45.000+02:00</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/28/02/1B4A432E00000514-0-image-a-9_1532740962989.jpg"><media:thumbnail url="" type=""></media:thumbnail><media:title>Without doubt, history will judge Blair and his fellow warmonger George W. Bush very harshly. Their rash move to topple Saddam Hussein caused incalculable bloodshed, the deaths of 179 British service personnel and has led to endless civil wars and political instability in the region</media:title><media:text>Former British Prime Minister Tony Blair addresses a news conference in London on July 6, 2016, following the outcome of the Iraq Inquiry report.
Former British prime minister Tony Blair voiced "sorrow, regret and apology" after a damning report on the Iraq war Wednesday, but said he did not mislead parliament and did not regret toppling Saddam Hussein.  / AFP / POOL / Stefan Rousseau        (Photo credit should read STEFAN ROUSSEAU/AFP/Getty Images)</media:text><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1000161</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>AFP/Getty Images</mi:licensorName></media:content><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-6001285/QUENTIN-LETTS-asks-happened-Calm-Carry-On.html" title="Why are today's leaders hysterical doom merchants? QUENTIN LETTS asks whatever happened to Keep Calm and Carry On "></link><link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/debate/article-5955003/PETER-HITCHENS-Britain-declare-independence-Europe-US.html" title="Get out of the EU? Of course. Dump the USA? Definitely! PETER HITCHENS on why Britain should declare independence from BOTH Europe and the States"></link></item></channel></rss>