<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>MailOnline MSN</title><language>en-GB</language><link>http://www.dailymailint.co.uk/feeds/msn/channel/news.rss</link><description>Daily Mail news feeds for MailOnline MSN</description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.dailymailint.co.uk/feeds/msn/channel/news.rss"></atom:link><item><title>MOL-14275 Tekashi 6ix9ine released from prison just days after grand jury indicted rapper for his alleged involvement in acts of murder, robbery, extortion and distribution of controlled substances</title><link>https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6546627/MOL-14275-Tekashi-6ix9ine-released-prison-just-days-grand-jury-indicted-rapper-for.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 15:16:18 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6546627</guid><description><![CDATA[MOL-14275 Tekashi 6ix9ine released from prison just days after grand jury indicted rapper for]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="mol-para-with-font">Daniel Hernandez, known to many as Tekashi 6ix9ine, had reason to be thankful this holiday after being released from federal prison.</p><div class="mol-article-quote nochannel floatRHS" id="mol-35624a20-18d7-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd">                            "THIS IS PULL QUOTES "                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Records show that Hernandez was discharged from the Metropolitan Detention Center in Brooklyn on Wednesday, just days after a grand jury indicted him and five other members of the Nine Trey Gangsta Bloods on racketeering charges. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There is no transfer facility listed however for Hernandez, as is standard when a prisoner is released from the MDC.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news" data-version="2" id="mol-3fb12500-18d7-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">FACT BOX Test</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <p class="mol-para-with-font"> There is no transfer facility listed however for Hernandez, as is standard when a prisoner is released from the MDC.</p><img src="https://idev.dailymail.co.uk/1/2019/01/15/15/7904920-0-image-a-1_1547564876189.jpg" height="586" width="586" alt="TEST" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">There is no transfer facility listed however for Hernandez, as is standard when a prisoner is released from the MDC. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>                            </div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 22-year-old 'FeFe' rapper has not been cleared however in that racketeering case, and is still facing six counts and a sentence of 25 years to life in prison for his alleged involvement in multiple acts involving murder, robbery, extortion, and distribution of controlled substances.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">DailyMail.com reached out to Hernandez's lawyer Lance Lazzaro over the holiday, who did not respond to a request for comment. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Scroll down for video </strong></p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/22/22/6533778-6419659-image-a-73_1542924229738.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Proof: Prosecutors claim they have video proof of Tekashi 6ix9ine being involved in shootings and robberies " /><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/22/22/6533774-6419659-image-a-72_1542924225921.jpg" height="265" width="634" alt="" /><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/22/22/6533780-6419659-image-m-85_1542924774262.jpg" height="428" width="306" alt="Records show that Tekashi 6ix9ine was discharged from the Metropolitan Detention Center in Brooklyn on Wednesday, just days after a grand jury indicted him and five other members of the Nine Trey Gangsta Bloods on racketeering charges" /><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/22/22/6533776-6419659-image-m-87_1542924782452.jpg" height="428" width="306" alt="Records show that Tekashi 6ix9ine was discharged from the Metropolitan Detention Center in Brooklyn on Wednesday, just days after a grand jury indicted him and five other members of the Nine Trey Gangsta Bloods on racketeering charges" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">There are conflicting reports as to where Hernandez has been moved at this time.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">TMZ first broke the story on Thursday and reported that the rapper was being housed in a facility for individuals who agree to cooperate with authorities.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Soon after DJ Akademiks, who worked with Hernandez on his now-delayed album Dummy Boy, offered up his own theory.</p><p class="mol-ratings"><strong>Rating: <strong>0/5</strong></strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He posted a lengthy diatribe on his YouTube channel in which he conjectured that Hernandez may have been used as a pawn to get the other five defendants indicted on RICO charges.</p><div class="mol-html" id="mol-810f7560-18d7-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd">                            <div><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en-gb"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">❤️ this Tweet to start 2019 with a bang <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HappyNewYear?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HappyNewYear</a> <a href="https://t.co/egW24kOJu7">pic.twitter.com/egW24kOJu7</a></p>— Twitter (@Twitter) <a href="https://twitter.com/Twitter/status/1079497619074940929?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">30 December 2018</a></blockquote></div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The producer cited the decision by law enforcement officials to quickly indict the group and pointed out that it all happened after Hernandez disbanded his team, a move that would have made it harder to show the connection between members of the group.</p><div class="news" id="mol-9cc8c770-18d7-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd"> <table class="mol-table" data-swipe-article="false" width="100%"> <caption class="wocc">TABLE TITLE</caption> <tbody>  <tr>   <th>Column</th>    <th>Column</th>   </tr>  <tr>   <td> 1 cl1</td>    <td>2 cl 2</td>   </tr> </tbody> </table></div><p class="mol-para-with-font">That would ultimately make it difficult to prosecute on racketeering charges, so his belief is that prosecutors are hopsing hernandez will flip and therefore put him in a ghang-free facility. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The indictment alleges that the violent episodes involving 6ix9ine included the July shooting of a bystander in Brooklyn and the gunpoint robbery of one of the gang's rivals last spring.</p><div class="mol-gif" id="mol-a9dd5200-18d7-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd">                            <span class="class"></span>                            <img class="blkBorder" src="https://media.giphy.com/media/eeSVExQFa52mCj9bZW/giphy.gif" />                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Hernandez was initially held without bail after an initial appearance before a Manhattan federal magistrate judge Monday.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On Wednesday, defense attorney Lance Lazzaro said in a statement that his client was 'completely innocent of all charges.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'An entertainer who portrays a "gangster image" to promote his music does not make him a member of an enterprise,' said Lazzaro.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Mr. Hernandez became a victim of this enterprise and later took steps by firing employees and publicly denounced this enterprise through a morning show. Threats were then made against his life which resulted in this case being brought immediately.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">At Monday's hearing, Assistant U.S. Attorney Michael Longyear pointed out that the rapper did not renounce his membership in the gang while appearing on a radio show last week.</p><mol-xpmodule id="mol-00f2de70-18d8-11e9-9854-7d0b4b21a4cd"></mol-xpmodule><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said Hernandez would have been arrested this week anyway, but the timetable was speeded up when authorities learned that he planned to go to a Connecticut casino where it would be harder to protect him from the threats.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Longyear said the threats were overheard on phone calls intercepted Saturday by investigators, including one in which an individual was heard saying that gang members wanted to 'super violate him.'</p><div class="moduleHalf">[item name=poll id=1078764 style=1 /]</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">The prosecutor noted that violence seemed to surround the entertainer. He said 10 shots were fired into a Beverly Hills, California, home where he was filming a music video a week ago.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Hernandez had previously been kidnapped outside his Brooklyn residence as well in a bizarre incident this past July in which three men alleged robbed and beat him before making off with $750,000 worth of jewelry and $35,000 in cash.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">His ex-manager Kifano Jordan, aka Shotti,Faheem Walter, aka Crippy, Jamel Jones, aka Mel Murda, Jensel Butler, aka Ish, and Fuguan Lovick, aka Fu Banga, were also indicted.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Prosecutors described Nine Trey as a 'criminal enterprise involved in committing numerous acts of violence, including shootings, robberies, and assaults in and around Manhattan and Brooklyn'.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Members and associates of Nine Trey engaged in violence to retaliate against rival gangs, to promote the standing and reputation of Nine Trey, and to protect the gang's narcotics business,' the press release continues.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The group 'enriched themselves by committing robberies and selling drugs, such as heroin, fentanyl, furanly fentanyl, MDMA, dibutylone, and marijuana.'</p><div class="moduleHalf">[item name=module id=65338191 style=5 /]</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">Nine Trey was established in the early 90s at Rikers and operates in other areas of the country, including California.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In 2015, 6Hernandez pleaded guilty to one felony count of using a child in a sexual performance.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Authorities said the rapper had sexual contact with a 13-year-old girl when he was 18 and distributed videos of the incident online. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Hernandez recently pleaded guilty to disorderly conduct in Brooklyn Criminal Court in connection with a May traffic stop.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Last week the rapper revealed in an Instagram clip that he had dismissed his entire staff, including his manager and booker.</p><div class="moduleHalf">[item name=module id=65630539 style=151 /]</div><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I fired everybody on my team,' the Gummo artist said in the clip, imploring his fans that he was not going to be performing live in the near future, even in cases where he might be advertised.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I don't got no manager, I got no booking agent, no PR, no publicist, I don't got nobody on my team - it's just me.' </p><video preload="none" id="1805184" title="Tekashi 6ix9ine warns his fans not to buy fake tickets to show" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/16/05/6260172-0-image-a-10_1542347080918.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/11/16/7401504983278534008/1024x576_MP4_7401504983278534008.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video>]]></content:encoded><dc:description>MOL-14275 Tekashi 6ix9ine released from prison just days after grand jury indicted rapper for</dc:description><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Pankaj Molekhi</dc:creator><dcterms:modified>2019-01-15T15:26:46.000Z</dcterms:modified><mi:shortTitle>MOL-14275 Tekashi 6ix9ine released from prison just days after grand</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2019-01-15T15:26:46.000Z</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/11/22/21/6533428-0-image-a-71_1542923873019.jpg"><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/wires/afp/article-6546615/VW-Ford-announce-alliance-build-commercial-vans-pickups.html" title="VW, Ford announce alliance to build commercial vans, pickups"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/wires/ap/article-6546055/Shiffrin-leads-1st-run-giant-slalom-massive-margin.html" title="Shiffrin finally conquers elusive Kronplatz giant slalom"></atom:link></item><item><title>REVEALED: Toxic farm-strength insecticide was sprayed INSIDE the Egyptian hotel where two British tourists died - just hours before they fell ill in the next room </title><link>https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6157583/Farm-strength-insecticide-sprayed-Egyptian-hotel-room-British-couple-died.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:56:05 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6157583</guid><description><![CDATA[Contractors used lambda-Cyhalothrin 5 per cent to spray a hotel room at the luxury Thomas Cook resort in Hurghada, Egypt, a day before John Cooper, 69, and his wife Susan, 64, died on August 21.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="mol-para-with-font">The room next door to where a British couple died in an <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="/news/egypt/index.html">Egyptian</a> hotel last month had been fumigated with 'farm-strength' insecticide just hours earlier, it has been confirmed.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">John Cooper, 69, and his wife Susan, 64, died after being taken ill during a Thomas Cook holiday in the Red Sea resort of Hurghada.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">An investigation was launched after the couple died at the luxury five-star resort, although a further post mortem into their deaths will be carried out when their bodies are repatriated. </p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEDF700000578-0-image-m-2_1536597063852.jpg" height="467" width="634" alt="John, 69, and Susan Cooper, 64, died on August 21 after being taken ill during a Thomas Cook holiday in the Red Sea resort of Hurghada before their mysterious death" /><video preload="none" id="1751728" title="Inside the Aqua Magic Hotel where John and Susan Cooper died" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/08/26/19/4F6BE9E600000578-0-image-a-1_1535308586395.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/08/26/8811562635450432631/1024x576_MP4_8811562635450432631.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><p class="mol-para-with-font">Egyptian officials said on Monday they would release the bodies so they can be returned to the UK. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thetimes.co.uk/edition/news/farm-strength-bug-killer-used-in-hotel-where-couple-died-r30kstqbz">The Times</a>, the day before the couple died, August 20, Namaa Agricultural and Engineering Services sprayed an adjacent with lambda-cyhalothrin 5 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The door of the room, which was sealed with tape, was at the end of the corridor next to where the Coopers were due to stay. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is feared the fumes may have entered their room through the ceiling space.  </p>                                                                                <p class="mol-para-with-font">According to the <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://sitem.herts.ac.uk/aeru/ppdb/en/Reports/415.htm">University of Hertfordshire</a>, the spray is highly toxic to mammals and is a known irritant.  </p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news floatRHS" data-version="2" id="mol-a61c94a0-b62b-11e8-8c81-9546bc6a4c4b">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">WHAT IS LAMBDA CYHALOTHRIN? </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <p class="mol-para-with-font">The insecticide is used to control flies and is similar to that used to fumigate aeroplanes when they land. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was developed in 1977 and has been approved for use on agricultural land in the UK since 1988.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But according to Public Health England, prolonged exposure can be harmful to humans. They warn symptoms can include dizziness, loss of appetite and production of too much saliva.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It is highly toxic to mammals and is a known irritant. </p>                            </div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font">A World Health Organisation <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/92a2/9c04b716595bb46d63365048f326422a5f5e.pdf">bulletin </a>from 1990 investigated possible poisoning cases involving the insecticide. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to the report: 'Acute pyrethroid poisoning in humans is characterised by headache, nausea and, when severe, by muscle fasciculation (spontaneous contractions) and convulsive attacks.' </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Their daughter Kelly Ormerod has previously said said vital clues may have been lost when cleaners and maintenance workers accessed the room soon after her parents died.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ms Ormerod has always been adamant that she believes something in the room killed her parents, despite Egyptian officials insisting their deaths were 'normal for an old English man and his wife' and the result of respiratory and heart failure. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She has previously mentioned a 'funny smell' in the room at Steigenberger Aqua Magic Hotel the night before they died.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The results of the post-mortem were still spending on Friday, nearly three weeks after the tragic double death.</p><video preload="none" id="1757466" title="Thomas Cook Egypt holiday deaths: Daughter fears cover up" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/05/19/4FBE9FC200000578-0-image-a-2_1536173007360.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/09/05/179830481165007514/1024x576_MP4_179830481165007514.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEE1000000578-0-image-a-3_1536597090635.jpg" height="591" width="634" alt="Their daughter Kelly Ormerod (right) has dismissed authorities' claim that her parents were killed by E.coli. She said: 'They are either stuck for answers or don't want to tell the truth'" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">However confirmation has now been given by Egyptian authorities that their bodies have been released and can be brought back to the UK.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Egypt's General Prosecutor released a statement ordering the release of the bodies of Susan and John Cooper to a UK Embassy representative in Cairo.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The statement says the results of the autopsy will be released at a later stage and that the investigation will continue.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEDFF00000578-0-image-a-12_1536597435128.jpg" height="427" width="634" alt="Trip of a lifetime: Susan and John Cooper were staying at the Steigenberger Aqua Magic hotel (pictured in the resort)" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">It says they can now be repatriated and the British can conduct their own post-mortem.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ms Ormerod told ITV News that she had returned to her parents' room on Wednesday the day after their deaths to collect belongings and noticed the cleaners had been in.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEE0300000578-0-image-m-15_1536597449636.jpg" height="484" width="306" alt="Kelly and her three children (pictured leaving Egypt) landed at Manchester Airport in the early hours of Sunday flanked by staff from Thomas Cook" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">'All the floors had been mopped, all the bedding had been changed and for those 24 hours maintenance were in and out quite often.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'If it happened over here it would have been taped off but the room wasn't taped off until I believe the Thursday so everybody and anybody could go in that room on that Wednesday.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She said she had 'no idea' what maintenance had been doing and added that the room was not taped off until the Thursday.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ms Ormerod believes potentially crucial evidence may have been lost in the process.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'There was obviously evidence left over from my Mum and Dad in that room which I think was quite crucial as to why they possibly died.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'There was a distinct change of smell in the room. The air conditioning unit was a lot crisper and cooler and you could tell that somebody had been in that room doing something.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ms Ormerod had reported a strange smell in the room in the hours before they died.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEDFB00000578-0-image-a-11_1536597427459.jpg" height="354" width="634" alt="Ms Ormerod has always been adamant that she believes something in the room killed her parents, she told ITV news" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">She also said her daughter had intended to stay the night with her grandparents but returned to her room due to the odour.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The couple had been staying next to a room that had been fumigated just hours before, raising fears they may have been poisoned by toxic gases.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Mail on Sunday revealed that pest controllers sprayed chemicals into the room on August 20, the day before Susan and John Cooper died.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The fumigated room – number 5106 – is located at the end of the first floor. The only connected room was that occupied by the couple.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEE0700000578-0-image-a-16_1536597499159.jpg" height="359" width="634" alt="Susan and John were staying at the Steigenberger Aqua Magic hotel (pictured) when they fell ill" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Speaking with the BBC she explained: 'At 11 o' clock I went to knock on the door to see if they were just having a bit of a lie in and didn't want to be bothered, and as I opened the door I could see that my dad was extremely ill.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He was staggering back to the bed. Mum was laid on the bed. And I could tell there was something seriously wrong with them.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Ms Ormerod said she was feeling 'disheartened' that neither post-mortem results had been returned, but didn't think 'the answers will be the answer I necessary believe'.    </p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEE1700000578-0-image-a-17_1536597504928.jpg" height="659" width="634" alt="The fumigated room – number 5106 – is located at the end of the first floor. The only connected room was that occupied by Susan and John from Burnley" /><video preload="none" id="1750712" title="Thomas Cook&amp;#39;s evacuation of Egypt hotel &amp;#39;shows level of concern&amp;#39;" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2018/08/24/12/video-4056820-333_636x358.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/08/24/6664533234113725148/1024x576_MP4_6664533234113725148.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><p class="mol-para-with-font">Her father died in the couple's room at the hotel while Susan was later rushed to hospital where she later passed away.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Egyptian authorities ordered an investigation into the deaths despite saying the British couple died of natural causes.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Thomas Cook evacuated 300 guests staying at the all-inclusive Steigenberger Aqua Magic Hotel in the Red Sea resort town of Hurghada.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/10/17/4FFCEE0C00000578-0-image-a-19_1536597671951.jpg" height="474" width="634" alt="The tragedy happened in the Red Sea resort town of Hurghada in eastern Egypt" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Around 200 people have lodged sickness complaints against the resort.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Thomas Cook commissioned an independent hygiene specialist and air quality specialist to conduct a series of tests at the hotel.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">They said the tests on the food and hygiene standards identified a high level of E.coli and staphylococcus bacteria.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The travel firm said its experts did not think E. coli killed the Coopers.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It said the results of the tests identified 'a high level of E. coli and staphylococcus bacteria', which were reviewed by Dr Vanya Gant from University College London Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news" data-version="2" id="mol-9fe377d0-b625-11e8-af55-0fcd8bfc71ab">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">British tourist caught E.coli at the same hotel in January</h3><div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body"><p class="mol-para-with-font">Elizabeth Austin, 29, thought she was going to die after contracting E.coli in January. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The bank clerk, from Canterbury, Kent, discovered she was suffering from E.coli when she returned to Britain. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She said she spent a week bed-bound having to use the toilet up to 30 times a day.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She told <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/7232694/brit-woman-29-falls-violently-ill-with-deadly-e-coli-at-egypt-death-hotel-where-thomas-cook-couple-mysterious-died/">The Sun</a>: 'When I complained it was almost like they knew what was coming, they didn’t try to put up a fight.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I asked them if there had been any other cases and they said no. But that was obviously a lie. They tried making out I contracted E. Coli on my way to the hotel or at a restaurant out of the site - but we never left the place.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'They knew there was a problem at the hotel before the poor couple died there in August.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>                            </div>                        </div>]]></content:encoded><dc:description>Contractors used lambda-Cyhalothrin 5 per cent to spray a hotel room (inset) at the luxury Thomas Cook resort (pictured right) in Hurghada, Egypt, a day before John Cooper, 69, and his wife Susan (pictured left), 64, died on August 21. The World Health Organisation warned back in 1990 that exposure to the drug can cause 'headache, nausea, and when severe, by muscle fasciculation and convulsive attacks.' An investigation was launched after the couple died at the luxury five-star resort, although a further post mortem into their deaths will be carried out when their bodies are repatriated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Darren Boyle for MailOnline</dc:creator><dcterms:modified>2018-09-12T12:00:23.000Z</dcterms:modified><mi:shortTitle>Farm-strength bug spray sprayed in Egyptian hotel  before couple died</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-12T12:00:23.000Z</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>Egypt</media:keywords><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/10/5011F7D200000578-0-image-a-78_1536743561780.jpg"><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights><mi:licenseId>1011482</mi:licenseId><mi:licensorName>UNKNOWN</mi:licensorName></media:content><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6143823/Thomas-Cook-pays-3-000-holidaymaker-food-poisoning-Turkish-Hotel.html" title="Thomas Cook pays out £3,000 to holidaymaker who suffered such extreme pain for food poisoning at a Turkish Hotel she 'would have shot herself with a gun if she could'"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6135155/High-levels-e-coli-bacteria-Egypt-hotel-British-couple-died.html" title="Dozens of Thomas Cook holiday makers to receive compensation after high levels of e-coli and bacteria are found at Egypt hotel where British couple mysteriously died"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.thetimes.co.uk/edition/news/farm-strength-bug-killer-used-in-hotel-where-couple-died-r30kstqbz" title="‘Farm-strength’ bug killer used in hotel where couple died | News | The Times"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://sitem.herts.ac.uk/aeru/ppdb/en/Reports/415.htm" title="lambda-cyhalothrin"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/92a2/9c04b716595bb46d63365048f326422a5f5e.pdf" title="WHO bulletin"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/7232694/brit-woman-29-falls-violently-ill-with-deadly-e-coli-at-egypt-death-hotel-where-thomas-cook-couple-mysterious-died/" title="Brit woman, 29, falls ‘violently ill’ with deadly e-Coli at Egypt ‘death hotel’ where Thomas Cook couple mysterious died"></atom:link></item><item><title>Obesity Britain: Two thirds of us are overweight and only two - Turkey and Malta - out of 53 European countries are fatter, UN study finds </title><link>https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6156965/Obesity-Britain-Two-thirds-overweight-Turkey-Malta-fatter-study-finds.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 23:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6156965</guid><description><![CDATA[Only two of 53 European nations are fatter than Britain, a UN report reveals. Our obesity rate of 28 per cent is beaten only by Turkey, with 32 per cent, and Malta at 29 per cent.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="mol-para-with-font">Only two of 53 European nations are fatter than Britain, a report reveals today.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The UN study found that two in three of us are overweight and one in four is obese.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It blamed the crisis on lack of exercise, poor diet and heavy drinking. Campaigners said the figures were frightening and warned that deaths from diabetes and heart disease could spiral without urgent action.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Our obesity rate of 28 per cent is beaten only by Turkey, with 32 per cent, and Malta at 29 per cent. The European average is 23 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Obesity is defined as a body mass index (BMI) score of more than 30. A tally higher than 25 is seen as overweight.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500BC8B600000578-6156965-image-a-13_1536701697001.jpg" height="210" width="634" alt="Our obesity rate of 28 per cent is beaten only by Turkey, with 32 per cent, and Malta at 29 per cent. The European average is 23 per cent" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘The Government has to work and quickly if the UK is to avoid shortly becoming the fattest nation on Earth,’ said Tam Fry of the National Obesity Forum.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘It is frightening that there are millions of children whose current obesity will doom them to die before their parents.’ </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">He said it was now accepted that adults died early ‘not only because of being overweight but because of the co-morbidities they have triggered by their obesity’.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Britain was fourth worst – with a 64 per cent rate – when it came to measuring how many adults were overweight.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/009576041000044C-6156965-image-a-20_1536702209279.jpg" height="414" width="306" alt="Experts said Britain had such a weight problem in part because of the heavy influence of the US" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Obesity is known to raise the risk of Type 2 ‘lifestyle’ diabetes, heart disease, stroke, dementia, joint and back problems and cancer.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Data from Public Health England shows that 34 per cent of children are overweight and 10 per cent are obese when they leave primary school.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The research from the World Health Organisation, an arm of the UN, covered 53 countries, including former Soviet nations it considers part of the European region.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Its author Dr Claudia Stein said life expectancy had gone up but obesity was putting this progress at risk.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘What is even more alarming is what is going on with children,’ she said.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘If I remember my childhood there were one or two chubby children in the class. Now if you see the data it is really high.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She added: ‘Adult alcohol consumption is a huge contributor to obesity, and Britain has overtaken the European average.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Experts said Britain had such a weight problem in part because of the heavy influence of the US, which has an even worse obesity rate of 38 per cent.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">European countries such as France and Italy are less susceptible to American advertising because of the language barrier.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Martin McKee, professor of European public health at the London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine, said: ‘We have long known that, among high-income countries, obesity rates are higher in English-speaking ones, including the USA and UK.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Within Europe, other countries with high rates include Ireland and Malta.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘This has been a long-standing puzzle and some have asked whether it is because the intensive marketing in the United States in English has a global reach, but especially in countries where everyone speaks English.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Caroline Cerny of the Obesity Health Alliance said: ‘It’s very concerning to see the UK has one of the highest levels of adults with obesity in Europe.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/07/5001DEF200000578-6156965-The_Mail_revealed_yesterday_that_the_NHS_is_to_put_diabetics_on_-a-2_1536735015712.jpg" height="304" width="634" alt="The Mail revealed yesterday that the NHS is to put diabetics on low-calorie soup and shake diets to try to beat the disease" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘However this is hardly surprising when we live in an environment that steers us towards unhealthy choices with marketing, promotions and super-size portions.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘We need the Government to fully implement measures outlined in their childhood obesity strategy such as a 9pm watershed on junk food adverts to help ensure the next generation have the opportunity to grow up healthy.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Helen Dickens of Diabetes UK said the figures from WHO were very worrying. She added: ‘Obesity is one of the main risk factors of Type 2 diabetes, and the reason why 12.3million people in the UK are at risk of developing the condition.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘We need to tackle the obesity epidemic in order to stop the Type 2 diabetes crisis from growing, by helping people make healthier choices and supporting them to maintain a healthy lifestyle.’</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/01744409000004B0-6156965-image-m-17_1536702160376.jpg" height="832" width="634" alt="People need to make healthier choices and support them to maintain a healthy lifestyle" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Mail revealed yesterday that the NHS is to put diabetics on low-calorie soup and shake diets to try to beat the disease.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A Department of Health spokesman said: ‘Our regulations on junk food advertising to children are some of the toughest in the world – while our soft drinks industry levy has removed billions of tons of sugar from children’s diets.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘We recently set out proposals to ban energy drinks for children and plans are under way to reduce their exposure to sugary food and get them moving more in school.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The WHO study, which covers data up to 2016, showed Britons consume 24 per cent more alcohol than the European average.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A BMI score is a rough calculation based on the relationship between an individual’s weight and height.</p><div class="mol-page-break"><div class="pageBreak"> </div><div class="clear"> </div></div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>I cut out beer and curry to reverse my diabetes – and lost 7st, says Labour’s Tom Watson</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Tom Watson reversed his Type 2 diabetes by cutting out beer and curry, he revealed last night. The Labour deputy leader lost 98lbs in weight – seven stone – after he adopted a radical diet and took up boxing.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘I am very happy to reveal that my Type 2 diabetes has been reversed, it’s in remission,’ said the 51-year-old. ‘No longer having to take medicines for diabetes is a joy. To all Type 2 diabetics I say: “Yes, we can.”</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Yet the tragedy for many is that they don’t even know their condition is reversible, let alone how to achieve it.’</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Writing in the Daily Express, Mr Watson said he realised his problem last year as he ‘huffed and puffed’ to his Westminster office. ‘It felt that if I didn’t do this, I was going to die,’ he said. He cut out all sugar and ultra-processed food from his diet and started walking and running and then boxing.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘Politicians of all sides must join forces to enact change,’ he said. ‘My experience of escaping Type 2 diabetes has given me a new mission to help others get healthy.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">‘We can’t afford to keep going as we are. The challenge is huge but generations will suffer if we fail to get a grip on the obesity crisis that threatens to engulf us.’</p><video preload="none" id="1719388" title="&amp;#39;What is diabetes?&amp;#39; Diabetes UK explains in video" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/03/00/4DDCC9CA00000578-0-image-m-58_1530575826218.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/07/02/5905343855727365680/1024x576_MP4_5905343855727365680.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/07/500B271C00000578-6156965-Pictured_before_and_after_he_downsized_Tom_Watson_said_he_was_so-a-1_1536735015580.jpg" height="487" width="634" alt="Pictured before and after he downsized: Tom Watson said he was so overweight he thought he would die" /><p class="mol-para-with-font"> </p>]]></content:encoded><dc:description>Only two of 53 European nations are fatter than Britain, a UN report reveals. Our obesity rate of 28 per cent is beaten only by Turkey, with 32 per cent, and Malta at 29 per cent. The European average is 23 per cent. Among those successfully losing weight is Labour deputy leader Tom Watson, above, who reversed his Type 2 diabetes by cutting out beer and curry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Ben Spencer Medical Correspondent For The Daily Mail</dc:creator><dcterms:modified>2018-09-12T07:23:42.000Z</dcterms:modified><mi:shortTitle>Obesity Britain: Two thirds of us are overweight</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-12T07:23:42.000Z</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>Weight Loss,Turkey,United Nations</media:keywords><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/00/500D5DC900000578-0-image-a-10_1536707386532.jpg"><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6150907/Granddaughter-slams-care-home-serves-grandmother-79-frozen-chips-one-slice-ham.html" title="Granddaughter slams care home after it serves grandmother, 79, frozen chips with one slice of ham despite boasting of 'restaurant-style' and 'appetising' menus in its brochure "></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6155093/Nutella-Festival-Helensvale-Queensland-Saturday.html" title="That's nuts! Festival dedicated to NUTELLA expected to see thousands of revellers to pass through its gates"></atom:link></item><item><title>The REAL First Lady: Overly familiar presidents, blundering US officials and squabbling Hollywood stars – but, as the final extract from ROBERT HARDMAN’S book reveals, the Queen’s deft diplomacy has kept THAT relationship special </title><link>https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6157131/The-REAL-Lady-Overly-familiar-presidents-blundering-officials.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 21:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6157131</guid><description><![CDATA[A major new book by the Mail’s royal writer outlines the diplomatic role undertaken by the Queen during her unprecedented years of public service.]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>A major new book by the Mail's royal writer outlines the diplomatic role undertaken by the <a style="font-weight: bold;" target="_blank" class="class" href="/news/the_queen/index.html">Queen </a>during her unprecedented years of public service. </strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Yesterday, he told what really happens when the royals embark on a foreign tour. </strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Today, in the final part of our serialisation, he traces HM's own special relationship with the U.S.  </strong></p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B16CC00000578-0-image-a-36_1536701192508.jpg" height="408" width="634" alt="Gerald Ford dancing with Queen Elizabeth II at the ball at the White House, Washington, during the 1976 Bicentennial Celebrations of the Declaration of Independence" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">For her very first trip to Florida — part of her 1991 state visit to America — the Royal Yacht had sailed in to Miami to rendezvous with the Queen.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As Britannia's crew waited to greet her, they flushed through all the royal baths and heads (ship's lavatories), which was standard practice ahead of a royal arrival. Whereupon Britannia's captain suddenly had a furious official from the Miami port authority thumping on his door.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The crew had just breached strict environmental regulations and the captain was handed a $10,000 (£7,700) fine plus an order to leave port within two hours.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">No matter that the Queen was due to host a state banquet on board that very evening, with two former U.S. presidents among the guests. Rules were rules. The Yacht would have to pack up and go.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was only after the direct intervention of the White House that Britannia was allowed to remain alongside. The banquet duly took place without further incident.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> The fabled 'special relationship' had worked its magic once again.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It's a phrase, however, which is heard more often on this side of the Atlantic and there are commentators in both Britain and the U.S. who regard any notion of a 'special relationship' as sentimental, subservient wishful thinking on the part of the British Establishment.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There have certainly been some strong individual pairings between No 10 and the White House, notably Churchill and Roosevelt, Thatcher and Reagan and, latterly, Blair and George W. Bush.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B16C600000578-0-image-a-37_1536701252559.jpg" height="489" width="634" alt="Queen Elizabeth II rides on horseback with American President Ronald Reagan in Windsor, June 1982" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, historians will note that there has been a more subtle, yet more consistent, 'special relationship' operating between the White House and Buckingham Palace throughout the reign of Elizabeth II — even during periods of deep political division.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Unlike the Queen's dealings with most countries, which have followed a well-established pattern, this is a friendship that has broken the bilateral mould. There can be few people in the U.S., let alone the rest of the world, who have lived through the administrations of 16 presidents — more than one-third of the total — and met 12 of them.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Of the handful of private foreign holidays that the Queen has enjoyed in her life (all horse-related), five have been spent in the U.S.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">And in 2018, the Royal Family welcomed their first American Princess. Yet the Queen's own 'special relationship' goes back to the nursery.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was in 1939 that her parents travelled to Canada and the U.S. to bolster support for Britain ahead of impending hostilities in Europe. The royals rather enjoyed all the informality.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen wrote an excited letter to her daughters about a memorable picnic lunch: 'All our food on one plate — a little salmon, some turkey, some ham, lettuce, beans &amp; HOT DOGS too!'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">While some Americans were appalled at the idea of serving hot dogs to a king, the Royal Family would never forget it.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Growing up in wartime Windsor, Princess Elizabeth was acutely aware of the strain on her father as he tried to buoy the morale of a nation facing invasion at any moment, and she could sense the redemptive significance of America's entry into the war.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B169600000578-0-image-m-41_1536701565674.jpg" height="823" width="634" alt="Queen Elizabeth signs on behalf of her dominion of Canada during the conclusion of the Power Project Ceremonies at the New York state end of the St. Lawrence Power Dam" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Come victory and the drab, near-bankrupt years of austerity that followed, it was America that represented fun and glamour.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Like so many others, the Princesses were entranced by the explosive arrival of the first American musical after the war, Oklahoma!</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Princess Margaret reportedly went to see it more than 30 times. Princess Elizabeth and Prince Philip watched it together as a courting couple in 1947; People Will Say We're in Love has been one of 'their' songs ever since.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen's first experience of the U.S. was in 1951, when as Princess Elizabeth she interrupted a tour of Canada to meet President Harry Truman at the White House. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Her first visit as Queen came in 1957 when she met President Dwight D. Eisenhower as well as the then-Vice-President Richard Nixon.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Alongside formalities to mark the 350th anniversary of the first English colony at Jamestown, Virginia, the Queen and the Duke paid their first visit to a supermarket. </p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/11/4FE05F8C00000578-6152855-Pictured_The_Queen_of_the_World_by_Robert_Hardman-a-1_1536663598008.jpg" height="471" width="306" alt="Pictured: The Queen of the World by Robert Hardman " /><p class="mol-para-with-font">'How nice you can bring your children along,' she told shoppers as she marvelled at the sight of a frozen-food section.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Food was also on the agenda in 1959 when the Queen first entertained a U.S. president at home. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Spending two days with the monarch at Balmoral, President Eisenhower found the experience so agreeable that he asked the Queen for 'her' scone recipe (though not her own, she duly transcribed it in her own hand).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Disagreements after the Suez Crisis and then over Vietnam would strain the 'special relationship' on the political front, but not the rapport between the Windsors and the White House.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In 1976, Gerald Ford invited the Queen across the Atlantic for a tumultuous state visit to honour the bicentenary of American independence. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">She was accompanied by her new Foreign Secretary, Anthony Crosland, and his American-born wife, who later recorded the Queen's advice on how to get through arduous tours like these.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'One plants one's feet like this,' the Queen told her. 'Always keep them parallel. Make sure your weight is evenly distributed. That's all there is to it.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The advice would be invaluable, with a punishing itinerary in 100f (38c) heat. The centrepiece was a White House state banquet for more than 200 guests, including Hollywood stars Cary Grant, Telly Savalas and Merle Oberon.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There was some amusement when the after-dinner cabaret, pop duo Captain &amp; Tennille, launched into their moderately risque hit Muskrat Love. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">That turned to considerable unamusement when President Ford invited the Queen to dance. The band chose that very moment to strike up a new tune: The Lady Is A Tramp.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There was an even more awkward moment when Ford's successor arrived at Buckingham Palace a year later. Perhaps overcome with nerves on what was his first journey outside the U.S., Jimmy Carter became a little over-familiar with a senior member of the Royal Family.</p><video preload="none" id="1590602" title="Queen Elizabeth and Prince Phillip visit the Reagans in 1983" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2017/12/13/13/474A098100000578-0-image-a-2_1513171634109.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2017/12/13/294555959546593198/1024x576_MP4_294555959546593198.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><p class="mol-para-with-font">As William Shawcross notes in her official biography, the Queen Mother hated being told that she reminded people of their own mothers. Having informed her that she did, indeed, remind him of his own mother — 'Miz Lillian' — President Carter kissed the Queen Mother on the lips. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As she later remarked, no one had done that since the death of George VI. 'I took a sharp step backwards,' she recalled, 'not far enough.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Carter's successor, however, would enjoy one of the more enduring friendships between the Queen and any foreign politician. It certainly helped that Ronald Reagan was an accomplished horseman. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">When he came to Windsor Castle for a semi-private stay in 1982, the two heads of state spent a good hour riding all over Windsor Great Park followed by teams of bodyguards — on both four legs and four wheels.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">On a return trip to the U.S. in 1983, the Queen fulfilled a lifetime's ambition of touring the West Coast. In Hollywood, Reagan laid on a star-packed lunch for 500. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The entertainment included Frank Sinatra, Bob Hope and Perry Como, but the arrangements left some of the local talent rather peeved.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Ronald Reagan was asked who should be at the top table,' recalls Sir Brian Fall, then private secretary to the British Foreign Secretary, Francis Pym. 'Should it be actor friends or political friends? He couldn't sort it out so he said: 'Why don't we pack it out with Brits in Hollywood?' '</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The result was a top table full of British-born stars such as Julie Andrews and Dudley Moore. For some status-obsessed Hollywood egos, it was all too much. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Palace press office, which had played no part in the planning, was left fending off accusations that the Queen was only interested in sitting with fellow Brits.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B16A000000578-0-image-m-42_1536701617075.jpg" height="803" width="634" alt="Her Majesty the Queen and the Duke of Edinburgh this afternoon arrived in Washington D.C. where they were greeted by President Eisenhower" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I was on the table next door with Julie Andrews's husband,' Sir Brian recalls. 'He was so ticked off at not being on the right table that he walked off and left a gap.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">A few days later the Queen was due to arrive in San Francisco on Britannia, but foul weather persuaded her to fly instead. The Reagans put Air Force Two at her disposal and staff recall a very excited Queen pressing her face against a plane window to enjoy an aerial view of the Golden Gate Bridge.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">With no Royal Yacht to stay on, the combined power of the White House, the Palace and the personal contacts of the former state governor found the Queen and the Duke last-minute accommodation in the Presidential Suite at the St Francis Hotel, where Nancy Reagan even arranged for works of art from local museums to be rounded up and hung on the walls.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'The next question was: where to go for dinner?' remembers Sir Brian. Again the White House came to the rescue and managed to empty San Francisco's most famous restaurant, Trader Vic's, for the night. For the Queen, who had not eaten in a restaurant for 15 years, it was a novel experience, right down to being given a fortune cookie at the end (she read the message and then put it in her handbag).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 'special relationship' was still in robust shape following the first Gulf War as the Queen and Prince Philip arrived to stay with President George H. W. Bush in 1991.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">However, the state visit got off to an inauspicious start following President Bush's formal welcome on the White House lawn. After his speech, he was supposed to press a pedal which raised the platform from which the Queen was then going to speak.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font"> He forgot to do it and the Queen, being rather shorter, remained invisible to much of the crowd.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The moment was encapsulated in the words of NBC's Jim Miklaszewski: 'She's gone! All I got is a talking hat!' To this day, Palace officials and diplomats still refer to the state visit as 'the talking hat tour'.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">D uring her stay in Washington, the Queen had her first encounter with the President's son, George W. Bush, then in charge of the Texas Rangers baseball team. He had been forewarned by his mother not to talk to the Queen, as he could be 'mercurial'.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen was rather intrigued, particularly since he was wearing cowboy boots etched with the words 'God Save The Queen'. At one point she asked him if he was the black sheep of the family.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I guess so,' replied Bush Junior.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'All families have them,' observed the Queen.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Who's yours?' Bush Junior replied, at which point the First Lady, Barbara Bush, intervened with a cry of: 'Don't answer that!'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Relations between London and Washington cooled to a more business-like level during the Clinton years, partly because of heated disagreements over the Western response to war in Bosnia.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There was no state visit in either direction in that sort of climate, but the Queen fulfilled her now-familiar role as keeper of the 'special relationship'.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Clintons might not have had the full royal treatment at Windsor or Buckingham Palace but, in 1994, they were the Queen's guests for the commemoration of the 50th anniversary of D-Day.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Only the Clintons were invited to stay aboard Britannia in Portsmouth ahead of the voyage to France the next day, accompanied by the leaders of all the allied nations and ocean liners packed with veterans.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B16AC00000578-0-image-a-40_1536701343521.jpg" height="423" width="634" alt="Queen Elizabeth II stands with US President Donald Trump and his wife, Melania, in the Grand Corridor during their visit to Windsor Castle in Berkshire" /><video preload="none" id="1727028" title="Queen Elizabeth welcomes Trump and wife to Windsor Castle" poster="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/07/14/04/4E39945E00000578-0-image-a-23_1531539007756.jpg"><source src="https://video.dailymail.co.uk/video/mol/2018/07/14/5361227972338075854/1024x576_MP4_5361227972338075854.mp4" type="video/mp4"></source></video><p class="mol-para-with-font"> They were given cabins nine and 11, the best suite apart from the Queen's. A presidential bodyguard took up position at the door and refused to let anyone inside, including the steward bringing the Clintons' morning coffee.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The President was up early for his exercise routine. No one could fail to spot him.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to Sir Robert Woodard, Britannia's captain, he put on 'these DayGlo neoprene things' for a short run around the dockyard.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He did his post-running press-ups and hip jerks for quite literally five minutes with the whole yacht standing to attention,' laughs Woodard. 'Then he went down and was politely late for breakfast.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Only a handful of senior members of the Royal Household were at the breakfast table, along with the Duke of Edinburgh. One recalls the extraordinary moment when Clinton began to describe the World War II ceremonies he had attended at battlefields in Italy the previous day:</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He was talking about visiting the U.S. graves at Anzio and suddenly he burst into tears — which was unexpected.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It would be George W. Bush who became the first American president to pay a full state visit to the United Kingdom when he arrived with his wife, Laura, in 2003. The second would be President Obama in 2011, but planning a U.S. state visit would turn out to be somewhat more problematic by the time the 45th President began his administration.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Just weeks after Donald Trump's inauguration in 2017, Theresa May travelled to Washington to meet him. She duly issued an invitation — promptly accepted — for a state visit in the near future.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The plan stalled, however, due to the threat of protests from activists and politicians such as Liberal Democrat leader Sir Vince Cable, who said that such a state visit would 'embarrass' the Queen and the country.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">In the event, the President made an 'official' visit in July 2018 and was invited, with the First Lady, for tea with the Queen at Windsor (mindful of American tastes, there was plenty of coffee, too).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">T here was not the faintest possibility that the Queen would be 'embarrassed' in this way. According to one of her staff, she would be intrigued to encounter a head of state who, like her, had a Scottish mother and who, like her, happens to own a large area of Scottish countryside (Balmoral in her case and a pair of golf courses in Trump's).</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The tea party — in the Oak Room in the Queen's private quarters — overran by 20 minutes.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Whether Donald Trump will get round to a full state visit remains to be seen but, regardless, the White House-Palace connection seems certain to endure.</p><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news" data-version="2" id="mol-f6437610-b608-11e8-a649-df1cec79f1c7">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Even the threat of assassination didn't stop her...</h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen had the unlikeliest of fans in the Cuban Communist dictator Fidel Castro.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">According to a story told by Sir Sonny Ramphal, former Commonwealth Secretary-General, one Left-wing Caribbean leader was so keen to get into Castro's good graces that he confided in him that he was thinking of turning his country into a republic.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He thought it would go down well with Fidel. But Fidel said: 'Why? Does the Queen interfere?'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Prime Minister: 'No.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Castro: 'Then why would you do that? You want to be a big tourist island and she's good for showing off your stability. Why are you doing that?' '</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Despite this acknowledgement of the monarch's usefulness, reports emerged of a plot by Castro to assassinate the Queen at the 1979 Commonwealth summit in Zambia, then a one-party state under President Kenneth Kaunda.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The crunch debate at the summit was to be over white minority rule in neighbouring Rhodesia, an issue causing much division among Commonwealth leaders.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen's would-be assassins, it was alleged, hoped to pin the blame on Rhodesia's white leaders and generate enough international outrage to bring down their regime.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 'plot' would later turn out to be nonsense. But, alerted to this and other threats, Downing Street expressed serious reservations about despatching the Queen to a maelstrom of African violence.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There was, however, one compelling argument in favour of this ostensibly suicidal royal tour: the Queen was very much looking forward to it. As Head of the Commonwealth, she was determined to join the rest of the 'club' in Lusaka, with the Duke of Edinburgh at her side, and 19-year-old Prince Andrew, too.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">They were already doing their packing and the British High Commission was bombarded with questions, including what Prince Andrew would need for his safari.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Back came the reply: 'Normal bush wear and stout shoes. Mosquito nets will be provided.'</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There were weeks of tension between the Palace and senior Government officials until finally, on July 17, Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher told the Commons that her mind was made up: she was not going to tell the Queen not to go to Zambia.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It was just as well, because two days later the monarch was on her way, arriving in time to deal with an explosive speech prepared by Kaunda. Some of its more incendiary passages were likely to cause terrible divisions within the Commonwealth.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Queen intervened personally with Kaunda and the controversial text miraculously disappeared. This set the scene for a harmonious summit at which history was made with Mrs Thatcher's announcement that she would be working with all the parties involved to deliver 'genuine black majority rule' in Rhodesia as quickly as possible.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">We are often told 'the Queen does not do politics'— and indeed she does not.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">But over seven decades on the throne, there have been moments when she has strayed close to the line. On this occasion, she was willing to cross it.</p>                            </div>                        </div><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news" data-version="2" id="mol-1989aac0-b633-11e8-abfb-d1b6995f220e">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">Rule No.1: NEVER say yes to a gift horse! </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <p class="mol-para-with-font">When organising visits for the Prince of Wales, the Foreign Office's Royal Visits Committee knows to expect a certain amount of haggling. Like the Queen, Prince Charles must follow ministerial advice. But he still enjoys some leeway in arranging the itinerary. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">There was certainly some bartering in 1996 when the Government dispatched the Prince on a tour of Central Asian outposts of the old Soviet Union.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Though some of his hosts had a deeply suspect record on human rights, there were important commercial opportunities for British companies in this newly emerging market.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Prince's staff proposed a schedule that seemed closely aligned to the old Silk Road between China and the West.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/03/500B16B400000578-6157131-image-a-1_1536719365572.jpg" height="436" width="586" alt="Stalling: Charles plays it clever as President Niyazov shows him his prize horses " /><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I suspect it was his own determination to see Samarkand,' says the Foreign Secretary of that time, Sir Malcolm Rifkind, with a knowing smile. Sure enough, the ancient Uzbek cities of Samarkand and Bukhara featured prominently on the final itinerary.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Perhaps the most challenging leg was in Turkmenistan, where the Prince spent the evening at the pink palace of the country's horse-obsessed dictator, President Saparmurat Niyazov.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">As well as banning dogs and pop music, he was in the habit of presenting visiting dignitaries with horses, a serious problem for the recipients.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The Foreign Office had been left to sort out the mess when, during a stopover in 1993, John Major was given a horse called Maksat.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Eventually, it was brought to Britain, at great expense, but proved wholly unfit for official duties.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Although Maksat finally ended up living happily on a Welsh farm, the Foreign Office had one clear instruction for the Prince's officials: no more horses.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This made for a tense evening as Niyazov led the Prince down to a vast  equestrian arena, where an energetic display of Turkmeni horsemanship was laid on for his benefit. As the two men walked through the stables, Niyazov sang the praises of one horse after another.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">It looked increasingly likely that the Prince was about to be offered one at any minute. Yet the royal guest managed to dodge every presidential blandishment.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Craftily observing how impressed he was that the President could manage so many horses, when he himself had too many to look after and frequently rubbing the 'bad back' which made riding painful these days, he managed to leave Niyazov's pink palace at the end of a 22-course banquet with nothing more awkward than a pom-pom hat and a carpet.</p>                            </div>                        </div><div class="art-ins mol-factbox news" data-version="2" id="mol-1db441a0-b633-11e8-abfb-d1b6995f220e">                            <h3 class="mol-factbox-title">How Camilla's husband saved rival Charles' life </h3>                            <div class="ins cleared mol-factbox-body">                                <img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/03/500E51EB00000578-6157131-image-a-9_1536720277170.jpg" height="364" width="284" alt="Andrew Parker Bowles in his army days" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Spring 1980, a year before his marriage to Lady Diana Spencer, and the Prince of Wales was on his way to Rhodesia for the hand-over ceremony which would herald its rebirth as independent Zimbabwe.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Arrangements for the royal visit had been made by one Lieutenant Colonel Andrew Parker Bowles and he had invited out his wife Camilla who, as the newspapers wasted no time in pointing out, was the Prince's former girlfriend.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'Charles's old flame lights up darkest Zimbabwe,' the Daily Mail's Nigel Dempster reported. However, it was Andrew Parker Bowles whom the Prince should have been most grateful to see.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">The 40-year-old Army officer had taken it upon himself to double-check every section of the royal itinerary.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">This included a trip to the Henderson Veterinary Research Station at Mazowe, where the vets were so convinced that they had found a way to tame the notoriously irascible African buffalo, a creature responsible for at least 200 deaths each year, that they were going to invite the Prince to ride one.</p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/12/03/4FE1576000000578-6157131-Mr_Parker_Bowles_earlier_this_month-a-7_1536720259899.jpg" height="239" width="284" alt="Mr Parker Bowles, earlier this month" /><p class="mol-para-with-font">Fortunately for Prince Charles, the gallant Lieutenant Colonel decided to test-ride a buffalo himself, only to be thrown off and gored through the right thigh. A few inches further up and he would have been killed. The royal riding trip at Mazowe was now off. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">Had the Prince followed the Foreign Office plan, though, he would have been in grave danger. </p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'I always remind him that if it hadn't gored me and had gored him, things might be very different these days,' laughs Brigadier Parker Bowles.</p><p class="mol-para-with-font">'He gives me a wry smile and, rightly, takes it quite lightly.'</p>                            </div>                        </div><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Adapted from Queen Of The World by Robert Hardman (Century, £25). © Robert Hardman 2018. To order a copy for £20 (offer valid until September 20, 2018; p&amp;p free), visit mailshop.co.uk/books or call 0844 571 0640.</strong></p><p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong></strong></p>]]></content:encoded><dc:description>A major new book by the Mail’s royal writer outlines the diplomatic role undertaken by the Queen during her unprecedented years of public service. Today, in the final part of our serialisation, he traces HM’s own special relationship with the U.S. Queen Elizabeth met with Gerald Ford (left) Ronald Reagan (top right), Dwight Eisenhower (bottom right) and most recently Donald Trump (inset).</dc:description><dc:publisher>MailOnline</dc:publisher><dc:creator>Robert Hardman for the Daily Mail</dc:creator><dcterms:modified>2018-09-12T13:31:10.000Z</dcterms:modified><mi:shortTitle>The REAL First Lady: Familiar presidents and blundering US officials</mi:shortTitle><mi:dateTimeWritten>2018-09-12T13:31:10.000Z</mi:dateTimeWritten><media:keywords>The Queen</media:keywords><media:content url="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/newpix/2018/09/11/22/500B37DB00000578-0-image-a-31_1536701180314.jpg"><mi:hasSyndicationRights>0</mi:hasSyndicationRights></media:content><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6156987/Karl-Stefanovic-defends-artist-racist-Serena-Williams-cartoon.html" title="‘It’s satire, if you don’t like it you don’t have to read it’: Karl Stefanovic defends artist behind racist Serena Williams cartoon – and says trying to crack down on cartoonists is a ‘slippery slope’"></atom:link><atom:link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://www.dailymailint.co.uk/news/article-6157055/Brits-six-months-passport-face-turned-away-EU-borders.html" title="Brits with less than six months on their passport could face being turned away at borders of European countries from the end of March "></atom:link></item></channel></rss>
